(music)
WHERE IS SLEEP?
"OVER THE MOUNTAINS
OF THE MOON,
DOWN THE VALLEY
OF THE SHADOW,
'NEATH THE WAVES OF
THE DEEP GULF STREAM,"
REPLIED THE HANDSOME DUKE
IN DARK,
LANGUID TONES.
(music)
IN DARK...
LANGUID TONES.
DARK, FOREBODING...
FOREBODING TONES.
HE FERVENTLY STROKED
HER ALABASTER BROW,
AND SHE FELL UNDER
HIS CLOAK OF DARKNESS.
[ Sigh ]
(music)
[ Quiet chatter ]
MORGAN, LOOK.
DO YOU THINK
SHE NEEDS HELP?
(music)
ARE YOU A...
A JOURNALIST?
NO, A TEACHER.
NO, I'M A WRITER.
ACTUALLY I WRITE BOOKS.
OH. BOOKS.
BOOKS.
I HOPE NOTHING'S
SPOILED, OR MISSING.
DOESN'T MATTER. I
KEEP IT ALL FILED AWAY
IN MY IMAGI-
NATION ANYWAY.
MORGAN.
MORGAN, WE'LL
BE LATE FOR
OUR LUNCHEON.
THANK YOU.
EXCUSE ME.
(music)
Children:
(singing) NO MORE PENCILS,
NO MORE BOOKS, (singing)
(singing) NO MORE TEACHER'S
DIRTY LOOKS (singing)
[ Mixed chatter ]
BYE, BARBARA SHAW.
DON'T FORGET
YOUR LUNCH PAIL.
Girl:
BYE, SHIRLEY.
BYE.
BYE, JACOB.
GOOD LUCK IN YOUR
JOB AT THE SMITHY.
Children:
GOODBYE, MISS SHIRLEY.
!
GOODBYE,
MISS SHIRLEY.
BYE-BYE.
GOODBYE, MISS SHIRLEY,
SEE YOU NEXT YEAR.
GOODBYE,
MISS SHIRLEY.
MINNIE MAY.
GOOD BYE,
MISS SHIRLEY.
[ Sigh ]
IS THAT HOW
YOU SMOKE IT?
DON'T YOU
KNOW ANYTHING?
YOU GOTTA LICK
IT TO MAKE THE
PAPER STICK.
[ Blowing raspberry ]
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
MY MAMA SAYS SMOKING
MAKES YOUR MOUTH BROWN
AND YOUR EARS STICK OUT.
YOUR MOTHER'S
AN OLD WINDBAG.
NO SHE IS NOT.
I'M GOING TO TELL
MISS SHIRLEY YOU
TWO HAVE BEEN SMOKING.
YOU DO AND I'LL
LOCK YOU UP AND
SIC MY DOG ON YOU.
WILL NOT. YOU
CAN'T CATCH ME.
[ Blowing raspberry ]
HELP!
LET'S SEE HOW
YOU LIKE BEING
LOCKED UP,
YOU LITTLE
TATTLETALE.
LET ME GO!
I'M GONNA TELL
ON YOU TWO.
LET ME GO. I'M
GONNA TELL ON YOU TWO.
YOU TWO ARE
BAD BOYS. I'M
GONNA TELL...
SEE HOW YOU
LIKE THAT, YOU
LITTLE TATTLETALE.
YEAH, AND WE'RE
GONNA SIC HIS
DOG ON YOU
IF YOU SAY
ANYTHING.
[ Banging on door ]
HELP!
[ Sigh ]
[ Banging on door ]
Minnie May:
[ Wailing ]
I WANT OUT!
[ Sobbing ]
WHY, MINNIE MAY!
ANTHONY PYE
AND TOMMY BELL
LOCKED ME IN
'CAUSE I WAS GOING
TO TELL ON THOSE TWO.
THEY WERE
SMOKING CIGARETTES.
AND ANTHONY'S GONNA
SIC HIS WATCHDOG ON ME.
HE'LL DO NO SUCH THING.
NOW YOU RUN ALONG.
YOUR MOTHER WILL BE
WONDERING WHERE YOU ARE.
ALL RIGHT,
MISS SHIRLEY.
[ Twittering of birds ]
OH, GOOD DAY,
MISS SHIRLEY.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
MR. PYE.
MUST BE GLAD
SCHOOL'S OUT.
I HOPE MY ANTHONY
BEHAVED HIMSELF
THIS YEAR.
ANTHONY'S GRADES
HAVE BEEN QUITE GOOD.
AND HE IS WELL-
LIKED BY EVERYONE.
I UNDERSTAND FROM
MINNIE MAY BARRY,
YOU HAVE AN EXCELLENT
WATCHDOG LOOKING OUT
FOR YOU, ANTHONY.
OH, AND
THAT'S A FACT.
NO FOXES AROUND OUR
CHICKEN COOP THIS
YEAR, MISS SHIRLEY.
[ Chuckle ]
A FINER WATCHDOG
YOU'LL NEVER SEE.
SO MINNIE MAY
WAS JUST
TELLING ME.
OH, AND THANK YOU,
ANTHONY, FOR VOLUN-
TEERING WITH TOMMY
TO WHITEWASH THE
OUTHOUSE FOR ME
NEXT MONDAY.
I HEAR YOU TWO
ARE EXCELLENT
PAINTERS.
I'LL BE SEEING YOU
THEN, MONDAY MORNING
AT 9:00 O'CLOCK.
GOOD DAY.
YOU'RE OFFO DO
SOME PAINTING THEN,
ANTHONY, ARE YOU?
(music)
I'M SORRY. I
KNOW YOU'RE CLOSED,
MRS. HARRISON,
BUT I PROMISED MARILLA
I'D PICK UP THE MAIL
IN TOWN TODAY.
THE POSTMAN, HE
LEFT A REGISTERED
CARD IN OUR BOX
YESTERDAY.
LUCKY YOU
CAUGHT US,
ANNE SHIRLEY.
DON'T KNOW IF
I'VE SEEN ANYTHING
COME THROUGH
TODAY THOUGH.
NO. NO, MA'AM,
NOTHING FOR GREEN GABLES.
BUT I HAVE A REGISTERED
CARD, MRS. SLOANE.
OH. JUST A
MINUTE NOW.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
I REMEMBER ONE OF
THEM BIG MANILA ENVELOPES
THAT YOU'VE
BEEN SENDING
OUT RECENTLY
DID COME BACK
YESTERDAY,
REGISTERED MAIL.
THAT IS RIGHT.
LET'S SEE.
RIGHT! YES,
HERE IT IS
HERE. NOW...
CAN'T SEE A THING
WITHOUT MY GLASSES.
GOT YOUR NAME
ON IT ALL RIGHT.
CURTIS PUBLISHING
COMPANY, BOSTON.
AIN'T THEY
MAGAZINE PEOPLE?
MUST BE A COMPLIMENTARY
SUBSCRIPTION OR SOME
SUCH NUISANCE.
THANKS SO MUCH
FOR LETTING ME IN.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
MRS. HARRISON,
MRS. SLOANE.
[ Jingling of door bell ]
[ Running footsteps ]
SO!
AH!
THIS IS WHY
YOU KEEP DISAP-
PEARING ON ME
EVERY TIME I PLAN
TO PICK YOU UP
AFTER SCHOOL.
GILBERT BLYTHE!
ALL THIS SECRECY.
YOU NEVER HAVE
TIME TO SPEAK TO
YOUR FRIENDS ANY MORE.
OH, YOU GIVE THAT
BACK OR I WON'T
SPEAK TO YOU AGAIN.
WELL, IF YOU'RE
GOING TO BE SO
TOUCHY.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE
THINK YOU'VE
BEEN ACTING VERY
PECULIARLY LATELY,
AND I MIGHT AS
WELL TELL YOU SO.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
SHOW UP AT THE
CARMODY SPRING FESTIVAL?
I SAVED A SPOT
FOR YOU AT OUR
TABLE.
I WAS BUSY. I
WAS TRYING TO GET
MY FINALS MARKED.
ANNE, YOU HAD YOUR
FINALS MARKED AND
POED WITH THE
BOARD BEFORE I DID.
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
NOTHING!
THIS IS A COMPLETE-
LY PERSONAL MATTER.
I SUPPOSE IT MUST
BE IF YOU CAN'T KEEP
YOUR WORD ANY MORE.
GOOD GRIEF!
YOU KNOW HOW TO
TRY ONE'S PATIENCE,
DON'T YOU?
(music)
Gil:
DON'T GET UP ON
YOUR HIGH HORSE
WITH ME, ANNE SHIRLEY.
I CYCLED ALL THE
WAY FROM CARMODY TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING
I FOUND OUT ABOUT
DIANA BARRY TODAY.
YOU ARE A
REAL PILL,
GILBERT BLYTHE.
WHAT ABOUT
DIANA BARRY?
UH-UH, NOT
UNTIL YOU SPILL
THE BEANS.
YOU WON'T SAY
ANYTHING TO
YOUR FOLKS,
OR JANE ANDREWS,
OR CHARLIE SLOANE?
ON MY HONOUR.
AND YOU PROMISE
YOU WON'T EVER
TEASE ME ABOUT THIS?
I WOULDN'T RISK
YOUR ANGER.
DEAR MISS SHIRLEY:
WE REGRET TO RETURN
THE ENCLOSED MANUSCRIPT,
"AVERIL'S ATONEMENT",
BUT ARE UNABLE
TO ACCEPT IT FOR
PUBLICATION.
SINCERELY YOURS,
WOMAN'S HOME
JOURNAL MAGAZINE?
YOU KNOW THE
STORY I WROTE
THIS SPRING?
I'M ATTEMPTING TO
HAVE IT PUBLISHED.
[ Gasp/chuckle ]
ANNE, THAT'S
TREMENDOUS!
[ Ringing of
bicycle bell ]
LISTEN TO THIS,
EVERYBODY,
AVONLEA'S PUBLIC
SCHOOL TEACHER,
SOON TO BECOME
WORLD FAMOUS
CANADIAN AUTHOR...
IT HASN'T
HAPPENED YET,
YOU FOOL.
AND DON'T YOU
DARE TELL ANYONE.
NOW WHAT'S ALL
THE FUSS ABOUT
DIANA BARRY?
WELL, FROM WHAT
I UNDERSTAND,
SHE'S GOING ON
AN EXTENDED VACATION
THIS SUMMER.
IS THAT ALL?
WHERE IS
SHE GOING?
YOU MEAN WITH
WHOM IS SHE GOING?
ALL RIGHT.
WITH WHOM THEN?
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES IT MAKE?
FRED WRIGHT OBVI-
OUSLY MAKES A LOT
OF DIFFERENCE TO HER.
HE'S PROPOSED AND
DIANA HAS ACCEPTED.
PROPOSED?
CHARLIE SLOANE
FOUND OUT FROM
FRED HIMSELF.
ROLY-POLY FRED WRIGHT?
BUT THEY HARDLY
KNOW EACH OTHER.
OF ALL THE STUPID,
SENTIMENTAL THINGS
FOR DIANA TO DO.
I DIDN'T EVEN
KNOW IT WAS
LIKE THIS.
SHE PROBABLY
ONLY ACCEPTED
BECAUSE FRED WAS
THE FIRST PERSON
TO EVER ASK HER.
DON'T BE SILLY.
FRED'S A TERRIFIC FELLOW.
WELL, HE BETTER
STEER CLEAR OF ME.
HE HAS NO BUSINESS
WALTZING IN,
STEALING MY BEST FRIEND.
YOU'RE NOT JEALOUS,
ARE YOU?
NO.
JUST DISAPPOINTED.
WHY DO PEOPLE
HAVE TO GROW UP...
AND MARRY... CHANGE.
OH, YOU'D CHANGE.
IF SOMEONE EVER ADMITTED
THAT THEY WERE HEAD
OVER HEELS FOR YOU,
YOU'D BE SWEPT OFF
YOUR FEET IN A MOMENT.
I WOULD NOT.
AND I DEFY ANYONE
WHO WOULD TRY AND
MAKE ME CHANGE.
YOU DO?
(music)
LAST ONE TO
THE BRIDGE IS A
STUFFED GOOSE.
[ Chuckling ]
CHEATERS NEVER
PROSPER, ANNE SHIRLEY.
(music)
[ Barking of dog ]
Boy:
WATCH OUT, ROVER.
Gil:
WHOO!
YOU'VE GOT IT NOW,
MISS SHIRLEY.
Anne/Gil:
[ Laughing ]
[ Clearing of throats ]
Anne:
OH, I'M SORRY,
DIANA.
SORRY, UM...
BUT GIL, HE'S...
HE FELL IN
THE BROOK AND...
WELL, THANK YOU
FOR THE LOVELY
WALK, DIANA.
Diana:
OH, PLEASE THANK
YOUR MOTHER FOR
THE CROCHETS.
MYRA GILLIS HAD
37 DOILIES WHEN
SHE GOT MARRIED,
AND I-I'M DETERMINED
TO HAVE AT LEAST
AS MANY AS SHE HAD.
I SUPPOSED IT
WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE
TO KEEP HOUSE WITH
ONLY 36 DOILIES.
BUT I ASSURE
YOU, MR. WRIGHT,
DIANA WILL BE THE
SWEETEST LITTLE
HOMEMAKER IN THE WORLD,
SO LONG AS YOU
CAN AFFORD TO LET
HER KEEP UP WITH
THE GILLISES.
WELL, I HOPE SO.
UH, GOOD DAY,
LADIES. GILBERT.
WELL, I BETTER GO
GET MY BICYCLE.
I'LL TALK TO
YOU LADIES LATER.
BYE.
[ Sigh ]
ANNE SHIRLEY...
THAT WAS...
I'VE NEVER BEEN SO HUMIL-
IATED IN ALL MY LIFE.
THAT WAS THE MEANEST...
HOW COULD YOU MAKE
FUN OF ME IN PUBLIC?
DIANA...
I WASN'T MAKING FUN.
I WAS JUST TEASING.
I'M SORRY.
YOU ALWAYS HAVE TO BE
THE CENTRE OF ATTENTION
WHENEVER GILBERT BLYTHE
IS IN ANYONE'S COMPANY.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
PLEASE FORGIVE
ME, DIANA.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO
PICK A QUARREL.
[ Sigh ]
WHY COULDN'T YOU
HAVE TOLD ME
ABOUT YOU AND
FRED YOURSELF?
[ Sob/sniffle ]
I FEEL LIKE
I'VE LOST MY
BEST FRIEND.
YOU WERE... YOU
WERE SO BUSY,
WRITING YOUR
BOOK AND MARKING
EXAM PAPERS.
IT JUST HAPPENED.
[ Sniffling ]
AND HE ASKED ME...
[ Laugh ]
I'M REALLY HAPPY.
BUT IT DOES
SEEM RIDICULOUS
TO THINK OF ME
BEING ENGAGED TO
FRED, DOESN'T IT?
OH, I DON'T
CARE WHAT HE
LOOKS LIKE.
HE... HE'S GOT
A GOOD HEART.
HE'S SO THOUGHTFUL.
WE'LL PROBABLY
MAKE A PUDGY OLD
COUPLE SOME DAY,
BUT IT DOESN'T
MATTER.
I AM GLAD FOR
YOU, DIANA.
DON'T YOU EVER
MEAN TO GET
MARRIED?
PERHAPS, IF I
MEET THE RIGHT ONE.
WHAT ABOUT GILBERT?
GILBERT'S JUST
A CHUM.
I DON'T CARE FOR
HIM IN THAT WAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT MY
IDEAL IS, DIANA.
TALL, IRRESISTIBLY
HANDSOME,
PROUD AND
MELANCHOLIC.
BUT PEOPLE'S
IDEALS CHANGE
SOMETIMES.
MINE WOULDN'T.
I WOULDN'T CARE
FOR ANY MAN WHO
DIDN'T FULFIL THEM.
WHAT IF YOU
NEVER MEET HIM?
WELL, THEN I SHALL
DIE AN OLD MAID.
OH, I SUPPOSE
YOU'RE RIGHT TO
BE DISCRIMINATING.
HALF THE MEN
ACROSS THE COUNTRY
WILL BE COURTING YOU
WHEN YOUR STORY
IS PUBLISHED.
YOU'RE GOING TO
BE FAMOUS, AND
I'LL BE SO PUD.
WHAT IS IT?
OH...
"WOMAN'S HOME JOURNAL"
SENT IT BACK.
WHAT?
WELL, THEIR EDITOR
MUST BE CRAZY.
WHAT REASON
DID HE GIVE?
NO REASON AT ALL,
JUST A PRINTED SLIP
SAYING IT WASN'T
ACCEPTABLE.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS!
THEY MUSTN'T
HAVE READ IT.
I'M GOING TO CANCEL
MY SUBSCRIPTION
IMMEDIATELY.
"AVERIL'S ATONEMENT."
IT SOUNDED SO
INSPIRING AND
ROMANTIC.
BUT YOU CAN TELL
ME TRUTHFULLY,
DIANA,
IF YOU RECALL
ANY MAJOR FAULTS
IN MY STORY.
[ Sigh ]
WELL...
T-THE PART WHERE...
WHERE AVERIL
MAKES THE CAKE...
DOESN'T... IT
DOESN'T SEEM TO
MATCH THE REST
OF THE STORY.
THAT'S ONE OF
THE MOST ROMANTIC
PARTS IN THE
WHOLE STORY.
IT'S A WELL-KNOWN
FACT THAT GREAT
LADIES OF OLD BELIEVED
THAT THE CULINARY
ARTS ALSO FED
THE SOUL.
WELL, I'LL HAVE
TO READ IT AGAIN
TO REMEMBER
WHAT MY FIRST
OPINION WAS.
IF YOU LET ME KEEP
IT, MAYBE I CAN
SUGGEST SOME CHANGES.
YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW DISCOURAGING
IT IS TO GET A
REJECTION, DIANA.
AND RIGHT WHEN
I'M IN THE MIDST
OF WRITING A NEW EPIC:
"ROSAMUND'S REVENGE."
THIS CERTAINLY
TAKES THE BLOOM
OFF THE ROSE.
[awling of cow ]
DON'T BE
DISCOURAGED.
ANNE SHIRLEY!
I'M NOT GOING
TO PUT UP WITH
THIS A DAY LONGER.
I WARNED MARILLA
NOT TO LET IT
HAPPEN AGAIN.
WELL, IT HAS.
PATIENCE HAS CEASED
TO BE A VIRTUE.
I WANT THIS RUMPUS
STOPPED RIGHT NOW.
IF YOU COULD JUST
CALM DOWN AND
TELL ME WHAT
THE TROUBLE IS.
HAH! CALM DOWN.
FIRST IT WAS OUR POTATOES.
THEN MY JUNE LILIES,
WHICH THOMAS PLANTED
ON OUR 25th WEDDING
ANNIVERSARY.
NOW THIS DARN JERSEY
COW HAS DEVOURED ALMOST
ALL MY PRIZE-
WINNING CABBAGES.
AND IF TILLIE BOULTER
WALKS AWAY WITH
THE RED RIBBON AT THE
CHARLOTTETOWN EXHIBITION,
YOU CAN LET MARILLA
KNOW I AM HOLDING HER
FINANCIALLY RESPONSIBLE.
I'M SORRY,
MRS. LYNDE, BECAUSE
DOLLY IS MY COW,
NOT MARILLA'S.
MATTHEW BOUGHT HER
FOR ME TWO YEARS
AGO AS A CALF
FROM MR. BELL.
SORRY! WELL, SORRY IS
NOT GOING TO HELP THE HAVOC
THIS ANIMAL HAS
MADE TRAMPLING
THROUGH MY CABBAGES.
AND IF YOU THINK...
I AM SORRY.
BUT THE FENCE
THAT SEPARATES
YOUR POTATO FIELD
FROM OUR PASTURE
IS AN EYESORE.
AND IF YOU KEPT
IT IN BETTER REPAIR,
DOLLY WOULDN'T
HAVE BROKEN IN.
A JAIL FENCE WOULDN'T
KEEP THAT DEVIL OUT.
AND WHAT'S MORE,
MY THOMAS HAS BEEN
FAR TOO ILL THE
PAST SIX MONTHS
TO REPAIR ANY FENCES.
AND I KNOW ONE THING,
YOU RED-HEADED SNIPPET,
YOU'D BE BETTER
EMPLOYED FIXING
THAT FENCE YOURSELF
RATHER THAN
MOONING AROUND,
WASTING YOUR TIME
WRITING FOR SOME
RUBBISHY MAGAZINE.
I WOULD RATHER
SPEND MY TIME
PROFITABLY,
THAN SQUANDER IT
IN IDLE GOSSIP,
MEDDLING IN
OTHER PEOPLE'S
AFFAIRS.
OH!
I WON'T CHERISH
ANY HARD FEELINGS
AGAINST YOU
BECAUSE OF YOUR
NARROW-MINDED
OPINIONS.
NOTHANK
GOODNESS I HAVE
AN IMAGINATION
WHICH ALLOWS ME
TO UNDERSTAND
HOW IT MUST BE TO
FIND A COW AMONGST
PRIZE-WINNING CABBAGES.
DOLLY SHALL
NEVER BREAK INTO
YOUR FIELD AGAIN.
I GIVE YOU MY
WORD OF HONOUR
ON THAT POINT.
WELL!
YOU JUST
MAKE SURE
THAT SHE DOESN'T.
[ Bawling of cow ]
WHOA. WHOA, WHOA.
WELL, MARILLA, I HOPE
THAT CANAL HORSE DESTROYS
YOUR TOMATO PATCH NEXT.
AND DON'T EXPECT
ANY SYMPATHY
FROM YOUR GIRL.
I'VE ALWAYS WARNED
YOU SHE HAD A TEMPER
TO MATCH HER HAIR.
[ Thinking ]
OH, GOOD LORD.
[ Clicking of tongue ]
SHE CAN'T POSSIBLY
GET OUT NOW
UNLESS SHE TEARS
THE FENCE DOWN.
I NEVER REALIZED
MRS. LYNDE WAS
SUCH A CRANK.
THERE'S CERTAINLY
NOTHING OF A
KINDRED SPIRIT IN HER.
(music)
YOU SET YOUR
HEART TOO MUCH ON
FRIVOLOUS THINGS,
AND THEN CRASH
DOWN INTO DESPAIR
WHEN YOU DON'T
GET THEM.
I KNOW.
I CAN'T HELP FLYING
UP ON THE WINGS
OF ANTICIPATION.
IT'S AS GLORIOUS
AS SOARING
THROUGH A SUNSET.
ALMOST PAYS FOR THE THUD.
WELL,
MAYBE IT DOES,
BUT I'D RATHER
WALK CALMLY ALONG,
AND DO WITHOUT BOTH
FLYING AND THUD.
[ Ringing of cow bells ]
Anne:
MARTIN'S FORGOTTEN
THE COWS ON
ORCHARD SLOPE.
I WAS AS POLITE
AS I COULD BE
UNDER THE CIRCUM-
STANCES, MARILLA.
AND I APOLOGIZED,
DESPITE HER
STINGING PERSONAL
REMARKS.
RACHEL SPECIALIZES
IN GETTING UNDER
PEOPLE'S SKIN, I KNOW,
BUT YOU OUGHT TO
HAVE BIT YOUR
TONGUE, ANNE,
SEEING AS WE
WERE IN THE WRONG.
NO, I OUGHT TO
HAVE SOLD DOLLY TO
GILBERT'S FATHER
A MONTH AGO
WHEN HE WANTED
TO BUY HER.
I THOUGHT IT
WAS JUST AS
WELL TO WAIT
TILL THE AUCTION,
AND LET ALL
THE STOCK GO
TOGETHER.
MARTIN, THERE ARE
TWO MORE COWS.
RACHEL WILL
GET OVER THIS.
HER NERVES HAVE
BEEN RAW LATELY,
AND DESERVEDLY SO.
THOMAS IS PRETTY BAD,
AND DR. SPENCER SAYS
THAT HE WON'T
BE WITH US
FOR VERY LONG.
I HOPE SHE
DOESN'T HAVE TO
SELL HER FARM.
IT'D BE A
TERRIBLE LOSS.
AND I KNOW HOW
WE FELT WHEN
MATTHEW DIED.
ANNE, I'VE WANTED TO
TALK TO YOU ABOUT
SOMETHING FOR A WHILE.
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN
CONTENT ENOUGH HERE,
BUT I NEVER
FEEL AT EASE,
THINKING ABOUT HOW YOU
HAVE GIVEN UP SO MUCH
OF YOUR OWN OPPORTUNITY.
MARILLA, I COULDN'T
LEAVE YOU ALONE HERE.
BESIDES, I'M...
I'D PROBABLY MAKE
A MUCH BETTER TEACHER
THAN A WRITER
ANY DAY.
ANNE...
YOU HAVE BEEN MY
COMFORT AND MY JOY
SINCE MATTHEW
PASSED AWAY.
BUT I PROMISED
MYSELF
WHEN YOU GAVE UP
THE AVERY SCHOLARSHIP
TO STAY HOME,
I'D MAKE IT UP TO
YOU ONE DAY.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
SORRY I'VE STAYED
FOR A MOMENT.
MR. BARRY HAS
REALLY TAKEN OVER
THE FARM ALMOST
COMPLETELY AND...
MY EYESIGHT
IS SO MUCH
BETTER NOW,
I CAN MANAGE
WITH MARTIN.
PERHAPS ONE OF
THE PICARD GIRLS
OVER IN RUSTICO
COULD...
BOARD WITH ME
FOR A WHILE,
SO YOU COULD
DUST OFF SOME OF
YOUR AMBITIONS
IF YOU LIKE.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK ABOUT THAT?
OH, MARILLA!
I FEEL AS THOUGH
SOMEONE'S HANDED
ME THE MOON,
AND I DON'T
EXACTLY KNOW WHAT
TO DO WITH IT.
MATTHEW AND I
SPENT 40 YEARS
LOOKING AFTER PAPA.
PERHAPS I NEVER
MENTIONED IT
BEFORE, BUT...
I CAN'T HELP
BUT CONFESS,
IT WAS WITH A
REGRETFUL HEART
AT TIMES.
YOU HAD A LITTLE BIT OF ROMANCE
IN YOUR OWN LIFE, MARILLA.
YOU WOULDN'T THINK
IT TO LOOK AT
ME, WOULD YOU?
BUT YOU CAN NEVER TELL ABOUT
PEOPLE BY THEIR OUTSIDES.
DO YOU SUPPOSE THAT MR. BLYTHE
REMEMBERS THAT HE WAS YOUR BEAU?
STUFF AND
NONSENSE.
[ Giggling ]
NO, NO. THAT'S
ENOUGH NOW.
NO MORE
FOOLISHNESS.
OH, IT SEEMS
SO FUNNY AND
HORRIBLE
TO THINK OF DIANA
MARRYING FRED,
DOESN'T IT?
WHAT IS SO
HORRIBLE ABOUT IT?
WELL, HE CERTAINLY ISN'T THE
WILD, DASHING YOUNG MAN
DIANA USED TO
WANT TO MARRY.
FRED IS...
EXTREMELY GOOD.
THAT IS EXACTLY
WHAT HE SHOULD BE.
WOULD YOU WANT TO
MARRY A WICKED MAN?
WELL, I WOULDN'T MARRY
ANYONE WHO WAS REALLY WICKED.
BUT I THINK I'D LIKE IT
IF HE COULD BE WICKED...
AND WOULDN'T.
(music)
YOU'LL HAVE
MORE SENSE
SOMEDAY, I HOPE.
I BELIEVE
ANNE SHIRLEY JUST
COPIED THAT STORY.
I AM SURE I
REMEMBER READING
IT IN A NEWSPAPER
YEARS AGO.
WELL, I'M SORRY
TO HEAR SHE'S
TAKEN TO WRITING
NOVELS AT ALL.
NOBODY BORN AND
BRED IN AVONLEA
WOULD DO IT.
BEEN WRITING
ANY MORE STORIES
LATELY, MISS SHIRLEY?
NO, MRS. HARRISON.
WELL, NO
OFFENSE MEANT.
MABEL SLOANE HERE SAYS SHE FOUND
ANOTHER ONE OF THEM BIG MANILA ENVELOPES
COME THROUGH HERE A
COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO, THAT'S ALL.
HMM, IT WAS
ADDRESSED TO THE
ROLLING RELIABLE BAKING
POWDER COMPANY IN MONTREAL.
I SUSPICIONED THAT SOMEBODY
WAS TRYING FOR THAT PRIZE
THAT THEY'RE OFFERING
FOR THE BEST STORY
INTRODUCING THEIR
NEW BAKING POWDER.
THE ADDRESS
WASN'T IN YOUR
HANDWRITING THOUGH.
I SHOULD HOPE NOT.
I'D NEVER DREAM OF COMPETING
FOR ANYTHING SO DISGRACEFUL.
IT WOULD ALMOST BE AS BAD AS
JAKE GRIFFITH'S CHATAGHUA SHOW.
BUT THEN THAT'S WHAT COMES OF
MARILLA CUTHBERT ADOPTING AN ORPHAN
FROM GOODNESS KNOWS
WHERE, OR WHAT KIND OF PARENTS.
OH!
WHY, ANNE,
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU HAVE SUCH A WAY OF
PUTTING AVONLEA ON THE MAP.
WELL... THANK YOU.
BUT WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
CONGRATULATIONS FOR WHAT?
[ Sarcastic laugh ]
YOU WERE ALWAYS SUCH A TERRIBLE
FAKE AT MODESTY, ANNE,
EVEN DURING
PUBLIC SCHOOL.
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING
FAKE ABOUT THE BUSINESS
LAWSON'S GENERAL
STORE INTENDS TO
DO FROM ALL THIS.
AND I THINK THAT
BLUE YOU'RE WEARING
IS SO DRAMATIC FOR
A YOUNG AUTHORESS.
YOU ALMOST LOOK
PRETTY IN IT.
[ Sarcastic chuckle ]
DON'T SAY THINGS
YOU DON'T MEAN, JOSIE.
THAT ANNE SHIRLEY
IS SO SMUG.
THAT GIRL ALWAYS
DID GIVE HERSELF AIRS.
Boys:
CONGRATULATIONS.
CONGRATULATIONS,
ANNE.
IT'S A WONDERFUL
STORY, ANNE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
WONDERFUL STORY,
ANNE.
YOU DESERVE
THE BEST.
Women:
CONGRATULATIONS.
CONGRATULATIONS,
MISS SHIRLEY.
CONGRATULATIONS ON
YOUR STORY, MISS SHIRLEY.
I REALLY LIKE THE
BIT ABOUT THE CAKE.
(music)
GREAT JEHOSOPHAT!
[ Excited murmurs ]
ANNE SHIRLEY,
WE'VE BEEN TRYING
TO TRACK YOU DOWN
EVERYWHERE.
OH, LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN, MAY I
PRESENT TO YOU
AVONLEA'S FAMOUS
AUTHORESS.
FATHER,
COME OUT HERE.
OH, MY GOODNESS,
MISS SHIRLEY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU WON THE
CONTEST, YOU GOOSE.
AND I KNEW YOU'D
GO AND DO IT ALL
BEHIND OUR BACKS.
Mr. Lawson:
QUIET, EVERYBODY,
QUIET PLEASE.
[ Clearing of throat ]
[ Ringing of cash register bell ]
IT IS MY GREAT PLEASURE
AS OFFICIAL PURVEYOR
TO AVONLEA
OF THE ROLLINGS RELIABLE
BAKING POWDER COMPANY
TO READ THIS,
THE FOLLOWING TRIBUTE.
UH, MISS ANNE SHIRLEY,
GREEN GABLES, PEI.
DEAR MADAM,
WE HAVE MUCH PLEASURE
IN INFORMING YOU
THAT YOUR CHARMING STORY,
"AVERIL'S ATONEMENT",
[ Applause ]
HAS WON THE
$100 GRAND PRIZE
IN OUR RECENT COMPETI-
TION FOR THE BEST STORY
INTRODUCING THE NAME OF
OUR REVERED PRODUCT.
[ Applause ]
[ Chuckling ]
UH, THE PRIZE WILL BE
PRESENTED BY MR. CHARLES LAWSON
OF LAWSON'S GENERAL,
AVONLEA.
WE HAVE ARRANGED
PUBLICATION OF THE STORY
IN SEVERAL PROMINENT
NEWSPAPERS ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
AND WILL SUPPLY
IT IN PAMPHLET FORM
FOR DISTRIBUTION
AMONG OUR PATRONS.
THANKING YOU FOR
THE INTEREST YOU HAVE SHOWN
IN SUPPORTING
OUR ENTERPRISES,
WE REMAIN YOURS
VERY TRULY
THE ROLLINGS RELIABLE...
BAKING POWDER
COMPANY.
YOU'LL SIGN MINE,
WON'T YOU? HERE
OH, AND I'M SURE
MISS SHIRLEY WILL BE HAPPY
TO SIGN EVERYBODY'S BROCHURES.
AND DON'T FORGET YOUR PURCHASE
OF THIS REMARKABLE PRODUCT.
NEXT.
ANNE!
OH, I'M WILD
WITH DELIGHT. AH!
I WAS SURE IT WOULD WIN WHEN I
SENT IT INTO THE COMPETITION.
DIANA BARRY!
YES I DID.
I THOUGHT OF YOUR
STORY IN A MINUTE
WHEN I SAW THE
AD IN THE PAPER.
Man:
MISS SHIRLEY, WILL YOU
SIGN THIS FOR MY DAUGHTER?
[ Mixed hubbub ]
THANK YOU.
WELL I WAS GOING
TO TELL YOU TO SEND IT IN YOURSELF,
BUT I FIGURED YOU HAD SO LITTLE
FAITH LEFT IN IT, YOU WOULDN'T.
SO I SENT MY COPY.
THEN IF IT HADN'T WON,
YOU'D NEVER HAVE KNOWN,
BECAUSE THE STORIES THAT
FAILED WEREN'T BEING SENT BACK.
WHY, ANNE, YOU DON'T
SEEM A BIT PLEASED.
OF COURSE I COULDN'T BE
ANYTHING BUT PLEASED.
IT WAS THE
GESTUREOF A
TRUE FRIEND
TO TRY TO BOOST
MY SPIRITS.
BUT THERE ISN'T
A WORD ABOUT...
BAKING POWDER.
OH, I PUT THAT
IN. IT WAS EASY
AS A WINK.
YOU KNOW THE
SCENE WHERE AVERIL
MAKES THE CAKE?
WELL, I JUST
STATED THAT SHE USED
ROLLINGS RELIABLE,
AND THAT'S WHY
IT TURNED OUT
SO WELL.
SEE? AND THE
HERE, IN THE
LAST PARAGRAPH
WHERE PERCIVAL
CLASPS AVERIL IN
HIS ARMS AND SAYS.
"SWEETHEART,
THE BEAUTIFUL
COMING YEARS
WILL BRING US THE
FULFILMENT OF OUR
HOUSE OF DREAMS."
I ADDED, "IN WHICH
WE WILL NEVER USE
ANY BAKING POWDER
EXCEPT
ROLLINGS RELIABLE."
OH-H!
COME ON. I HAVE THE BUGGY.
I'LL TAKE YOU HOME.
(music)
YOU'VE WON $100.
AND PRISSY GRANT TOLD ME THAT
"CANADIAN WOMEN"
ONLY PAID
$5 A STORY.
I CAN'T TAKE IT.
IT'S RIGHTFULLY
YOURS, DIANA.
YOU SENT THE
STORY IN AND MADE
THE ALTERATIONS.
I CERTAINLY
WOULDN'T
HAVE SENT IT.
SO YOU HAVE
TO TAKE IT.
I'D LIKE TO
SEE MYSELF!
IT WASN'T ANY
TROUBLE, ANNE.
THE HONOUR OF BEING THE BEST
FRIEND OF THE PRIZE WINNER
IS ENOUGH FOR ME
I'M SO GLAD
FOR YOUR SAKE.
I THINK YOU'RE
THE SWEETEST AND
TRUEST FRIEND
IN THE WORLD,
DIANA.
I WILL BUY YOUR
WEDDING GIFT WITH THIS.
DON'T YOU DARE
SPEND IT ALL ON ME.
I GOT A LETTER TODAY
FROM OUR DEAR OLD
TEACHER, MISS STACEY.
SHE IS HEAD
OF THE KING'S COUNTY
BOARD OF EDUCATION
IN NEW BRUNSWICK.
WHAT A PROMOTION.
WELL, APPARENTLY,
THERE'S A POSITION
SHE'S RECOMMENDED ME FOR
AT A LADIES' COLLEGE
IN KINGSPORT.
HOW FLATTERING!
YOU WOULDN'T ACTUALLY
LEAVE, WOULD YOU?
NO, BUT I OUGHT
TO REPLY ANYWAY.
SHE'S GONE TO
ALL THIS TROUBLE,
AND I WOULD...
[ Bawling of cow ]
STOP, DIANA!
ANNE!
YOU'LL RUIN YOUR DRESS
IN THAT
MUDDY FIELD.
RUIN IT!
OH, SHE'LL NEVER GET
THAT COW OUT BY HERSELF.
(music)
COME BACK!
STOP!
ANNE SHIRLEY, YOU'RE
BEING RIDICULOUS.
GET OUT OF THIS
FIELD THIS MINUTE.
I DON'T CARE
ABOUT MY DRESS.
I MUST GET THE
COW OUT BEFORE
RACHEL LYNDE SEES HER.
GO ON,
DIANA, RUN.
CORNER HER.
THAT'S IT,
DIANA.
NOW DON'T
FRIGHTEN HER.
THIS IS WHAT
WE'VE GOT TO DO.
[ Bawling of cow ]
MAYBE IF WE CAN
GET A HOLD OF HER,
WE CAN FORCE HER
OVER THE FENCE
INTO OUR FIELD.
OKAY, YOU
FILL THE GAP,
AND I'M GOING
TO MAKE A RUN FOR IT,
STRAIGHT
TOWARDS HER.
WITH ANY LUCK,
SHE'LL JUMP THE FENCE.
YOU DON'T MEAN
YOU'RE GOING TO ACTUALLY
WALK THROUGH THAT
MULCH, DO YOU?
IT'S THE LESSER
OF THE TWO EVILS, DIANA.
WHAT IF SHE WAS GOING TO GET INTO
RACHEL'S CABBAGE PATCH AGAIN?
(music)
ALL RIGHT, I HAVE
THE GAP BLOCKED.
COME HERE, DOLLY.
GOOD GIRL.
SHOO. COME ON.
WRETCHED COW.
OH, DON'T EVEN
THINK ABOUT RACHEL'S CABBAGES.
[ Gasp ]
[ Shriek ]
COME HERE,
YOU STUPID...
Both:
[ Yelping ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Sigh ]
SORRY.
Gil:
WELL,
THE ELEGANT
AND ILLUSTRIOUS
MISS SHIRLEY.
UH, RELAXED WHILE
SEEKING OUT IDEAS
FOR HER NEXT ROLLING
RELIABLE'S...
WRITING ASSIGNMENT, I PRESUME.
WELL, DO YOU SUPPOSE I'M HERE
TO CHAT WITH THE BULLFROGS?
BE A GENTLEMAN.
YOU'D HAVE BEEN BETTER OFF
SELLING HER LAST MONTH
WHEN DAD OFFERED
TO BUY HER.
WELL, I'LL SELL DOLLY TO HIM
RIGHT NOW IF HE WANTS HER.
Man:
[ Laughing ]
YOU MAY HAVE
OUR DARN JERSEY
ANY TIME YOU WANT
HER, MR. BLYTHE.
THIS VERY MINUTE
FOR THAT MATTER.
[ Laughing heartily ]
DONE!
I'LL GIVE YOU THE
$20 I OFFERED BEFORE.
GIL CAN DRIVE HER
OVER TO CARMODY RIGHT NOW.
SHE'LL GO TO TOWN WITH THE REST
OF THE SHIPMENT THIS EVENING.
I PROMISED MR. REED
OF BRIGHTON A JERSEY.
[ Chuckling ]
WHAT WILL MARILLA SAY?
SHE WON'T CARE.
DOLLY WAS MY
COW ANYWAY.
IT'S NOT LIKELY SHE'LL BRING
MORE THAN $20 AT THE AUCTION.
BUT WHEN RACHEL
SEES THIS FIELD,
SHE'LL KNOW
DOLLY WAS LOOSE.
ANNE, I'LL BE OVER THIS
AFTERNOON WITH YOUR $20.
WELL, IT'S TAUGHT ME A LESSON,
NOT TO STAKE MY WORD OF
HONOUR ON COWS.
Mr. Blythe:
[ Chuckling ]
(music)
HOW DO YOU
THINK A MOTHER WOULD FEEL
IF SHE FOUND HER CHILD
TATTOOED ALL OVER
WITH A BAKING POWDER
ADVERTISEMENT?
I LOVED MY STORY,
AND I WROTE IT
OUT OF THE BEST
THAT WAS IN ME.
AH, YOU'RE JUST TIRED.
BESIDES, WHY
SHOULD YOU CARE?
100 BUCKS IS MORE
THAN YOU MAKE IN TWO
MONTHS TEACHING ANYWAY.
JOSIE PYE AND TILLIE BOULTER
CAN'T WAIT TO POUNCE ON IT.
AH, THEY'RE
SPITEFUL
OLD CATS.
YOU'RE JUST THE
FIRST PERSON IN
POKEY OLD AVONLEA
TO TRY ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
ALL PIONEERS ARE CONSIDERED TO BE
AFFLICTED WITH MOONSTRUCK MADNESS.
MAD TO THINK I COULD
WRITE ANYTHING BETTER
THAN A BAKING
POWDER ADVERTISEMENT.
THIS HAS
DAMPENED ANY
SPARK OF AMBITION.
I SHALL NEVER
WRITE ANOTHER
STORY AGAIN.
WELL, I
WOULDN'T GIVE
UP ALTOGETHER.
MAYBE IF YOU JUST LET YOUR
CHARACTERS SPEAK EVERYDAY ENGLISH
INSTEAD OF ALL THAT HIGH-
FALUTING MUMBO-JUMBO.
YOU THINK MY STORY'S
FULL OF FAULTS
TOO, DON'T YOU?
"WILT THOU GIVE
UP THY GARTER,
OH, FAIREST OF THE FAIR?"
ANNE, NOBODY
SPEAKS THAT WAY.
AND LOOK AT THAT
SAD PERCIVAL
WHO SITS AROUND
MOONING THE ENTIRE TIME.
HE NEVER LETS THE GIRL
GET A WORD IN EDGEWISE.
IN REAL LIFE, SHE'D
HAVE PITCHED HIM.
HIS POETRY WOULD
WIN ANY GIRL'S HEART.
WELL, IF YOU
WANT MY OPINION,
MISS SHIRLEY,
I'D WRITE ABOUT
PLACES I KNEW
SOMETHING OF
AND PEOPLE THAT
SPOKE EVERYDAY
ENGLISH
INSTEAD OF THESE
SILLY SCHOOLGIRL
ROMANCES.
I DON'T SHARE
YOUR OPINION.
I AM NOT YOUR
HORSE, MR. BLYTHE.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO GIVE YOU A BIT
OF FRIENDLY ADVICE.
IS THAT SO?
TAKE THE $100,
AND WRITE A REAL
STORY ABOUT THE
PEOPLE YOU CARE ABOUT,
RIGHT HERE IN AVONLEA.
WELL YOU CERTAINLY
WOULDN'T BE ONE OF THEM.
"PITCHING"
AND "MOONING"?
[ Sniffle ]
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE ABOUT
AS INTELLECTUAL
AS CHARLIE,
AND MOODY AND
FRED AND ALL THE
REST OF THE BOYS
WHO COULD ONLY THINK OF
FINDING SOME SILLY GIRL TO MARRY
AND KEEP HOUSE
FOR THEM.
WELL, YOU CAN CRY
AND FEEL SORRY FOR
YOURSELF ALL YOU WANT,
BUT IT WON'T HELP YOU
WRITE A BETTEROVEL.
[ Sigh ]
WILL YOU STILL COME
TO FRED'S CLAMBAKE
WITH ME NEXT TUESDAY?
[ Sniffle ]
LISTEN, ANNE, I'M SORRY.
WILL YOU LET ME
WALK YOU BACK?
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO BE HELPFUL.
YOU... YOU KNOW YOU GET
MY BACK UP SOMETIMES.
LISTEN, I'M SORRY.
WHAT ELSE CAN I DO?
[ Grunt of effort ]
LET ME GET A
WORD IN EDGEWISE
ONCE IN A WHILE,
BEFORE I
PITCH YOU!
(music)
WHOA!
GOOD DAY, MARILLA.
WELL... JOHN BLYTHE.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
AROUND THESE PARTS MUCH LATELY.
WELL, I HAVEN'T
MUCH TIME FOR SOCIAL
CALLS NOWADAYS.
OLD PLACE STILL LOOKS
AS PRETTY THOUGH.
THE OLD BUILDINGS
ARE GETTING WORN DOWN.
BUT PEOPLE IN
AVONLEA STILL SAY
THAT IT'S THE
LOVELIEST OLD SPOT
ON THE NORTH SHORE.
OH, IT IS THAT.
SOME THINGS NEVER
CHANGE EVEN IN 30 YEARS.
I'M LOOKING FOR MY BOY.
YES.
ANNE AND HE ARE
WALKING BY THE POND.
MAYBE...
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SIT A WHILE,
TILL THEY COME BACK?
THANKS.
BUT WE'RE TAKING A SHIPMENT INTO
CHARLOTTETOWN BEFORE DARK.
I'D BEST GO AND FIND HIM.
[ Whinnying of horse ]
ANNE? WHAT
ABOUT YOUR $20?
FOR THE COW.
THE APPLE DOESN'T FALL
FAR FROM THE TREE, DOES IT?
GOOD DAY,
MARILLA.
(music)
[ Sobbing ]
[ Knocking on door ]
THERE, THERE.
[ Sniffling ]
YOU TAKE THINGS
TOO MUCH TO HEART,
ANNE SHIRLEY.
OH, MARILLA,
IT'S BEEN SUCH
A JONAH DAY,
WITH ROLLINGS
RELIABLE,
AND DOLLY,
AND GILBERT.
NOW, NOW,
JONAH DAYS COME
TO EVERYBODY.
GOD KNOWS BEST.
YOU USED TO SAY...
"TOMORROW IS
ALWAYS FRESH WITH
NO MISTAKES."
DO YOU REMEMBER?
[ Chuckling ]
OH, WHAT A
GIRL YOU WERE
FOR MAKING
MISTAKES IN
THEM DAYS.
HMMM?
[ Gulping ]
I USED TO THINK
YOU WERE POSSESSED.
DO YOU MIND
THE TIME YOU
DYED YOUR HAIR?
OH LORD.
OH, WHAT A
WORRY MY RED
HAIR USED TO BE.
I'M AFRAID I'VE
NEVER BEEN ABLE
TO ENDURE PERSONAL
CRITICISM VERY WELL.
GILBERT GAVE HIS
HONEST OPINION
OF MY STORY
THIS AFTERNOON.
MY... MY TEMPER...
IT ALWAYS GETS
THE BETTER OF ME.
I WHIPPED HIM AS
HARD AS I COULD.
I'M GLAD
TO HEAR IT.
THE BLYTHES HAVE
ALWAYS BEEN FAR
TOO OPINIONATED
FOR THEIR
OWN GOOD.
NO, MARILLA.
HE WAS RIGHT.
AND I'VE MADE
A TERRIBLE IDIOT
OF MYSELF.
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW
SPITEFUL I WAS.
I CAN IMAGINE.
OUR FRIENDSHIP...
IT WON'T EVER
BE THE SAME NOW.
WHY CAN'T HE JUST
BE SENSIBLE AND...
INSTEAD OF ACTING
LIKE A SENTIMENTAL
SCHOOLBOY.
BECAUSE HE
LOVES YOU.
HE LOVES ME?
I CAN'T
KNOW WHY.
BECAUSE YOU
MAKE JOSIE PYE
AND RUBY GILLIS
AND ALL OF THOSE WISHY-WASHY YOUNG
LADIES WHO'VE WALTZED BY HIM
LOOK LIKE
SPINELESS NOTHINGS.
BUT GIL AND I...
HE'S HARDLY
MY IDEA OF A
ROMANTIC SUITOR.
YOU HAVE TRICKED SOMETHING OUT OF
THAT IMAGINATION OF YOURS
THAT YOU
CALL ROMANCE.
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN HOW HE GAVE UP
AVONLEA SCHOOL FOR YOU,
SO THAT YOU
COULD STAY
HERE WITH ME?
HE PICKED YOU
UP EVERY DAY IN
HIS CARRIAGE,
SO THAT YOU
COULD STUDY YOUR
COURSES TOGETHER.
DON'T TOSS IT
AWAY, ANNE,
FOR SOME
RIDICULOUS IDEAL
THAT DOESN'T EXIST.
HMMM?
NOW YOU COME DOWNSTAIRS AND
SEE IF A GOOD CUP OF TEA
AND SOME OF THOSE PLUM PUFFS THAT I
MADE TODAY DON'T HEARTEN YOU.
PLUM PUFFS WON'T
MINISTER TO A
MIND DISEASED.
AND A WORLD THAT
HAS CRUMBLED
INTO PIECES.
WELL, I'M GLAD
TO SEE THAT YOUR
DENTED SPIRITS
HAVEN'T INJURED
YOUR TONGUE.
(music)
SUPPOSE IT'S JUST AS WELL
YOU SOLD THE DARN COW...
THOUGH YOU DO DO
THINGS IN A DREADFUL
HEADLONG FASHION.
I ONLY PRAY THAT
RACHEL DOESN'T
BURST A BLOOD VESSEL
WHEN SHE SEES
HER POTATO
FIELDS TODAY.
I'VE DECIDED TO
WRITE MISS STACEY,
AND ASK HER FOR MORE PARTICULARS
ON THIS LADIES' COLLEGE.
I THINK THAT'S A
WISE IDEA, ANNE.
GO OUT AND FIND
ME A COUPLE OF
EGGS, WILL YOU?
I DON'T KNOW HOW
IN HEAVEN'S NAME
DOLLY GOT OUT
OF THAT PEN.
SHE MUST HAVE
JUST BROKEN SOME
OF THE BOARDS.
[ Squawking of geese ]
[ Bawling of cow ]
OH NO!
MARILLA,
DOLLY'S HERE!
ANNE, WHAT IN
HEAVEN'S NAME IS
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WHAT WILL I DO?
OH, THIS IS TERRIBLE
AND IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
I MUST LEARN TO
REFLECT A LITTLE
BEFORE I GO CHARGING
AHEAD RECKLESSLY.
ANNE SHIRLEY, YOU ARE THE
MOST EXASPERATING GIRL.
WHAT IS IT THAT
YOU'VE DONE?
I'VE SOLD
RACHEL LYNDE'S
JERSEY COW,
THE ONE THEY
BOUGHT IN CARMODY
LAST SPRING,
TO MR. BLYTHE,
AND DOLLY IS HERE
THIS VERY MINUTE
IN THE MILKING PEN.
ANNE, ARE
YOU DREAMING?
I ONLY WISH
I WERE.
THERE'S NO
DREAM ABOUT IT,
THOUGH IT'S VERY MUCH
LIKE A NIGHTMARE.
THAT IS DOLLY.
RACHEL LYNDE'S
COW IS IN
CHARLOTTETOWN
BY NOW.
MARILLA, I THOUGHT
I WAS FINISHED
GETTING INTO SCRAPES,
AND HERE I AM IN THE
VERY WORST ONE I EVER
WAS IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
WHAT CAN I DO?
DO? THERE IS
NOTHING TO DO
BUT TO GO AND TELL
RACHEL THE TRUTH.
YOU ARE JUST GOING
TO HAVE TO LEARN
TO SETTLE DOWN
AND PAY HEED
TO THINGS.
Anne:
I'VE HUMILIATED
MYSELF
INTO THE
VERY DUST.
MAYBE SHE'D ACCEPT A PLATE
OF PLUM PUFFS AS A PEACE OFFERING.
(music)
Anne:
OH, NO.
IF SHE'S THAT
CROSS, WHAT
WILL SHE BE
WHEN I SAY
WHAT I'VE DONE?
Marilla:
IF SHE GIVES
YOU THE CHANCE TO
SAY ANYTHING AT ALL.
AFTERNOON,
THOMAS.
MARILLA.
AFTERNOON,
RACHEL.
MARILLA.
ANNE. I'M GLAD
YOU'VE COME.
I CERTAINLY HAD
NO INTENTION OF
VISITING YOU PEOPLE
AFTER BEING FLOWN
AT AS I WAS ON
MY LAST VISIT.
WELL, IT WOULD
APPEAR THAT
SOME KIND OF...
KAFUFFLE HAS
COME OUT OF THIS.
ANNE WOULD
LIKE TO...
PLEASE,
MARILLA,
I'M NOT FINISHED YET.
ON REFLECTION,
I REALIZED THAT I
WAS PARTLY TO BLAME.
I HAD NO RIGHT TO BE SO
ILL-TEMPERED WITH YOU,
AND I'M NOT ONE
OF THEM THAT CAN
NEVER BE BROUGHT
TO OWN UP TO
THEIR MISTAKES.
I'D LIKE TO
APOLOGIZE TO YOU,
ANNE SHIRLEY,
AND I WONDER IF
YOU'D SIGN MY COPY
OF YOUR "AVERIL'S
ATONEMENT"?
THE MONEY THEY
PAY FOR SUCH
LIES IS PERFECTLY
AMAZING, BUT...
I READ IT TO MY THOMAS
AND WE WERE BOTH MOVED.
I'M MUCH OBLIGED TO YOU,
AS IT'S THE ONLY
ENTERTAINMENT HE'S HAD
FOR THE PAST SIX MONTHS.
I LAUGHED SO HARD,
I'M NOT SURE IT WASN'T
GOOD FOR MY HEART.
I'M SO PLEASED.
COME AND LAY OFF
YOUR THINGS.
YOU'LL STAY TO
TEA, WON'T YOU?
THANK YOU,
RACHEL.
Rachel:
IT'S NOTHING
SHORT OF A WONDER
HOW YOU'VE
IMPROVED, ANNE, IN
LOOKS AND TALENT.
I'M NOT OVERLY PARTIAL TO THE
PALE, WIDE-EYES STYLE MYSELF.
I PREFER MORE
SNAP AND COLOUR.
BUT YOU DO MAKE THEM
OTHER AVOLEA GIRLS
WITH SHOWY GOOD LOOKS
SEEM KIND OF OVERDONE.
LIKE MY JUNE LILIES
ALONGSIDE THEM
BIG, RED PEONIES.
THAT'S WHAT.
HERE'S YOUR
TEA, THOMAS.
I DON'T WANT ANY TEA.
NOW, THOMAS,
YOU JUST FINISH
YOUR NAP HERE,
AND GET SOME
FRESH AIR.
I REALLY... I WANTED
TO CONFESS SOMETHING
TO YOU, MRS. LYNDE.
IT'S ABOUT
THE JERSEY COW.
I SAW MY TRAMPLED
POTATO FIELD
THIS MORNING.
NEVER MIND, ANNE. IT
MAKES NO DIFFERENCE NOW.
IF ONLY IT WERE
THAT, MRS. LYNDE.
BUT IT'S 10 TIMES WORSE.
WELL, YOU'RE NEVER
SAFE FROM SURPRISE
TILL YOU'RE DEAD.
DON'T TELL ME SHE'S
DONE IN THE LAST
OF MY CABBAGES TOO.
IT'S NOT THE
CABBAGES, MRS. LYNDE,
AND I'LL TELL
YOU EVERYTHING.
BUT PLEASE
DON'T INTERRUPT.
IT'S MAKING
ME NERVOUS.
Thomas:
RACHEL!
THOMAS, YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE SNOOZING.
YOU SEE, DIANA
AND I CHASED A
CERTAIN JERSEY COW
OUT OF YOUR POTATO
FIELD YESTERDAY.
WELL, YOU CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT
A DIFFICULT TIME WE HAD.
I WAS SO DREADFULLY
TIRED AND WET
AND CROSS
AFTER IT ALL,
WELL, I SOLD THE
COW ON THE SPOT
TO THE BLYTHES FOR $20.
TSK, TSK, I HOPE
YOU'RE NOT VEXED
WITH HER, MARILLA.
SHE SHOULD HAVE
CONSULTED YOU FIRST.
SO LONG AS MY
CABBAGES ARE SAFE,
WE'LL JUST PRETEND
IT DIDN'T HAPPEN.
Anne:
YOU SEE,
THIS MORNING,
I FOUND MY DOLLY
STILL SHUT UP IN
OUR MILKING PEN.
IT WAS YOUR COW...
THAT ANNE SOLD
TO JOHN BLYTHE,
RACHEL.
AND IT WAS SHIPPED
OUT RIGHT AWAY
ON THE AFTERNOON
TRAIN BY MR. BLYTHE.
Marilla:
YOU'LL FIND THAT
OUR JERSEY IS AS
GOOD AS YOURS,
OR PERHAPS YOU'D
PREFER THE $20.
MARILLA CUTHBERT,
WE PAID MORE THAN
$50 FOR OUR COW.
AND I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF ACCEPTING THAT VARMINT
OF YOURS IN EXCHANGE.
YOU HAVE ADMITTED
YOU ARE PARTIALLY TO
BLAME FOR ALL OF THIS.
ANNE SHIRLEY, YOU ARE TOO
HEEDLESS AND IMPULSIVE.
YOU JUST GO ON AND DO WHATEVER
COMES INTO YOUR HEAD, THAT'S WHAT.
WELL, IN THIS WORLD YOU
PAY FOR YOUR MISTAKES,
AND YOU CAN CERTAINLY
AFFORD TO PAY NOW.
WELL, YOU HAVE CERTAINLY
MADE A FINE EXHIBITION
OF YOURSELF, RACHEL,
FALLING ALL
OVER THIS GIRL
BECAUSE SHE'S
A SUCCESS.
IT'S PLAIN
TO SEE NOW
WHAT YOUR TRUE
COLOURS ARE.
Thomas:
RACHEL!
I'M COMING, THOMAS.
OH, THAT MAN! IF
HE'D JUST BRAVE UP
AND EXERT HIS WILL
POWER A LITTLE,
HE'D GET BETTER
IN NO TIME.
IT'S A WONDER TO
ME THAT HE DARED
TO GET SICK AT ALL
WITHOUT ASKING
HER PERMISSION.
COME ALONG,
ANNE.
WE'LL PAY
HER HER $50.
Rachel:
THOMAS!
[ Moaning ]
OH, DEAR GOD,
PLEASE DON'T
TAKE HIM.
WHAT IS IT,
THOMAS?
WHERE'S HIS
MEDICINE, RACHEL?
IT'S IN THE
CUPBOARD.
IS THIS IT?
YES.
RACHEL?
YES, THOMAS,
WHAT IS IT?
I...
I CAN'T
HEAR YOU.
WHAT IS IT?
OH, THOMAS!
[ Sobbing ]
OH, RACHEL...
I'M AFRAID
THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO.
[ Sobbing ]
Rachel:
THERE WON'T
BE MUCH LEFT
AFTER ALL OUR
DEBTS ARE SETTLED.
I EXPECT I'LL GO
WEST TO MY ROBERT,
IF HE'LL HAVE ME.
[ Sniffle ]
THE FARM IS
MORTGAGED AND...
NOW IT WILL
HAVE TO BE SOLD.
NOW, RACHEL.
PULL YOURSELF TOGETHER.
WELL, I'M NO
JELLYFISH. BUT...
A WOMAN MY AGE DOESN'T
MAKE FRIENDS AND INTERESTS
EASILY, THAT'S ALL.
IT BREAKS MY HEART TO
THINK OF LEAVING AVONLEA.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING
TIGHT, RACHEL?
A LITTLE BETTER I
THINK, THANK YOU, ANNE.
HERE'S MY GIFT, PAID
FOR OUT OF THE PROCEEDS
OF THE JERSEY COW.
IT'S NOT MUCH
OF A PARTY
GIFT, BUT...
YOU TELL THEM THAT
I PLAN TO GIVE
THEM MY ZIGZAG QUILT
AS A WEDDING
PRESENT.
WHY, ANNE, YOU HAVEN'T
WORN THAT OUTFIT IN AGES.
YOU LOOK
LOVELY.
THANK YOU, MARILLA.
GILBERT BLYTHE WILL
BE MIGHTY PROUD.
WHY ISN'T HE HERE YET?
PUT ON YOUR SWEATER.
IT'S GOING TO BE
COOL THIS EVENING.
I'M... I'M GOING
ALONE, RACHEL.
I HOPE YOU DON'T
MIND MY TAKING THE
CARRIAGE, MARILLA.
NO. NO.
YOU DID PUT
MY NAME ON THE
CARD, I HOPE.
OF COURSE,
MARILLA.
GOODBYE NOW.
GOODBYE, RACHEL.
HAVE A
LOVELY TIME.
BE CAREFUL THAT YOU DON'T
GET YOUR SKIRT CAUGHT
IN THE WHEEL OF
THE HAY-WAIN, ANNE.
[ Closing of door ]
WELL, MARILLA,
YOU KNOW I
PRIDE MYSELF ON
SPEAKING MY MIND.
I SMELL TROUBLE, AND
I DON'T MIND SAYING SO.
PROVIDENCE MATCHED
THEM TWO UP
SINCE THEY
WERE CHILDREN,
THAT'S WHAT.
AND THEY ARE
CHILDREN STILL.
SHE'S 18, AND
I WAS MARRIED
BY THAT TIME.
BUT ANNE'S GROWN TOO
MUCH LIKE YOU, MARILLA.
IT'S THE OVER-PARTICULAR
ONES, GET LEFT BEHIND
AND IT IS THE
OVER-OPINIONATED
THAT END UP UNHAPPY
AND MEANER THAN
SECOND SKIMMINGS.
Both:
[ Giggling ]
OH! THIS IS
GLORIOUS!
DID YOU REMEMBER
THE TIME...
[ Giggling ]
WE SLEPT ALL
NIGHT IN THE
HAY LOFT?
AND I WAS SO
FRIGHTENED WE WERE
GOING TO BE ATTACKED
BY THAT BARN OWL,
I...
COME ON, DIANA,
WE'VE GOT
TO ORGANIZE
THE GIFTS.
DUTY CALLS.
[ Fiddle music ]
ANNE, WHERE
ARE YOU OFF TO?
WE WON'T LEAVE
ANY CLAMS FOR YOU
IF YOU DON'T
HURRY BACK.
JUST ENJOYING
THE FRESH AIR.
OH, YOU HAVEN'T
MET MY FIANCE.
HARRY INGLIS
FROM WINNIPEG,
ANNE SHIRLEY.
PLEASED TO MEET
YOU, MA'AM.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
WELL, YOU'RE A VERY
LUCKY MAN, MR. INGLIS.
WHERE WILL
YOU LIVE?
IN MONTREAL.
HARRY'S IN THE
MINING BUSINESS.
OH, JANE, STOP
SHOWING OFF
YOUR RING.
I CAN SEE IT
GLIMMERING
THROUGH THE TREES.
IT'S BEEN REAL
NICE SEEING YOU
AGAIN, ANNE.
LET'S GO, HARRY.
YOU BOYS RUN
ALONG WITH JANE
AND HARRY.
I WANT TO TALK TO ANNE.
ISN'T JANE'S
MILLIONAIRE ANCIENT?
HE COULD BE
HER FATHER.
WELL, HE CERTAINLY MUST
HAVE A LOT OF MONEY.
I'LL SAY. HE'S
JUST SHOWERED HER
WITH JEWELLERY.
AND THEY'RE GOING TO
EUROPE ON A WEDDING TOUR.
JANE'S SUCH A NICE GIRL.
SHE'S NEVER EVEN TRIED
TO ATTRACT ATTENTION.
WELL, SHE'S
CERTAINLY NOT IN THE
MILLIONAIRE'S CLASS.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, ANNE?
ARE YOU HERE
WITH GILBERT?
I...
AREN'T THOSE
TWO RIDICULOUS?
THEY'RE DETERMINED
TO SIT EACH
OTHER OUT.
I REALLY DON'T CARE
A SNIT ABOUT EITHER
OF THEM, YOU KNOW.
WELL, LET'S
GET TOGETHER
SOON, ANNE.
I WANT TO HEAR
ALL OF YOUR NEWS.
[ Fiddle music ends ]
[ Distant applause ]
[ Twittering of birds ]
[ Fiddle music starts ]
[ To imaginary partner ]
ME?
I'D BE HONOURED TO
ACCEPT THIS DANCE.
[ Orchestra music ]
[ Imaginary
conversation ]
WHY THANK YOU.
YOU CAN CALL ME CORDELIA.
CORDELIA, YOU
HAVE AN EXQUISITE
ROSELEAF COMPLEXION.
DO ALLOW ME.
I HAVE AN ACCOUNT
TO SETTLE WITH
THIS YOUNG LADY.
YOUR $20.
CARE TO?
[ Orchestra music ]
[ Sigh ]
I'M SORRY, GIL.
I MUST HAVE
TWO LEFT FEET.
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING ABOUT?
I'M AFRAID TO
SPEAK OR MOVE
FOR FEAR THAT ALL
THIS WONDERFUL BEAUTY
WILL JUST VANISH,
LIKE A BROKEN SILENCE.
DOESN'T IT REMIND
YOU OF OUR OLD
SCHOOL-DAY PICNICS?
HMMM.
I DON'T WANT ANY
OF IT TO CHANGE.
I WISH I COULD
JUST HOLD ONTO
THOSE DAYS FOREVER.
I HAVE A FEELING
THINGS WILL NEVER
BE THE SAME AGAIN.
WILL THEY?
I WON'T CHANGE.
THAT'S THE LEAST
I CAN PROMISE YOU.
ANNE, THERE'S
SOMETHING I
WANT TO ASK YOU.
GIL, PLEASE DON'T.
WHAT IS IT?
YOU'VE BEEN AVOIDING
ME ALL SPRING,
EVER SINCE WE GRADUATED.
I NEVER WANTED TO MAKE
YOU CARE FOR ME SO.
I KEPT AWAY SO
YOU WOULDN'T.
WELL, I WON'T
BE COMING BACK TO
WHITE SANDS IN THE FALL.
DALHOUSIE MEDICAL SCHOOL
HAS ACCEPTED ME.
GIL, I'M SO PROUD OF YOU.
I'M SORRY ABOUT
LAST WEEK.
I ONLY WANTED TO SHOW
YOU HOW MUCH I CARE.
WELL, MAYBE YOU DON'T
THINK I'M GOOD ENOUGH
FOR YOU NOW,
BUT I WILL BE SOMEDAY.
NO, GIL, YOU'RE A GREAT
DEAL TOO GOOD FOR ME.
BUT YOU WANT SOMEONE
WHO'LL ADORE YOU;
SOMEONE WHO'LL
BE HAPPY JUST TO
HANG ON YOUR ARM
AND BUILD A
HOME FOR YOU
I WOULDN'T.
ANNE, THAT'S NOT WHAT
I'M LOOKING FOR AT ALL.
WE'D END UP LIKE TWO
OLD CROWS, FIGHTING
ALL THE TIME.
I KNOW I'D
BE UNHAPPY,
AND I'D WISH WE'D
NEVER DONE IT.
EVERYBODY
EXPECTS IT.
YOU MUST
FEEL THAT.
WELL THEN, IT
WOULD BE FOR
ALL THE WRONG
REASONS, GIL.
YOU JUST THINK
THAT YOU LOVE ME.
ANNE...
I'VE LOVED YOU AS LONG
AS I CAN REMEMBER.
I NEED YOU.
I CAN'T GO AWAY KNOWING
THAT IF I'D JUST...
I PROMISE THAT
I'LL ALWAYS BE HERE
IF YOU NEED ME.
GOOD FRIENDS ARE
ALWAYS TOGETHER
IN SPIRIT.
LET'S NOT CHANGE, GIL.
LET'S JUST GO ON
BEING GOOD FRIENDS.
[ Heavy sigh ]
FRIENDS, HUH?
I THOUGHT WE
WERE KINDRED
SPIRITS.
PLEASE SAY YES.
I CAN'T.
GIL, I'M SO
DESPERATELY SORRY.
[ Sigh ]
[ Chirping of crickets ]
[ Honking of car horn ]
WHOA!
[ Neighing of horse ]
LADY, GET OUT OF THE WAY.
WHOA!
WHAT THE HECK ARE
YOU DOING, LADY?
HAVE YOU ANY IDEA
HOW DIFFICULT IT IS
TO REPLACE ONE
OF THESE LANTERNS?
YOU HAD NO
BUSINESS TAKING
THE RIGHT-OF-WAY.
YOU HAD NO BUSINESS
TO BE OUT HERE ALONE
IN THE DARK
WITHOUT A LANTERN.
ARE ALL MOTORISTS
AS BOLD AS YOU?
I ENJOY BEING OUT
ALONE AT NIGHT.
ANY GENTLEMAN
WOULD HAVE HAD THE
DECENCY TO STOP.
I WAS HOPING
WE'D MEET AGAIN.
I'VE BEEN WONDERING
FOR SEVERAL WEEKS
EXACTLY WHO YOU WERE.
I'M SORRY I
WASN'T ABLE TO
INTRODUCE MYSELF
THAT DAY ON
THE BEACH.
CAPTAIN...
I HAVE NO DESIRE
TO BE INTRODUCED,
THANK YOU.
I'LL BET NO
ONE'S EVER TOLD
HOW BECOMING RED HAIR
CAN BE IN THE MOONLIGHT.
ACTUALLY LOTS
OF PEOPLE HAVE.
WHY DON'T YOU
TIE THE HORSE UP?
I'LL TAKE WHEREVER
YOU WANT TO GO.
YOU CAN COME BACK
FOR THE BUGGY
IN THE MORNING.
I'LL DO NO
SUCH THING.
SUIT YOURSELF.
JUST TRYING TO
BE A GENTLEMAN.
[ Whinnying of horse ]
DON'T GIVE YOURSELF AIRS.
YOU ARE IN A CLASS
ENTIRELY BY YOURSELF.
(singing) OH PROMISE ME THAT
SOMEDAY YOU AND I... (singing)
[ Giggling ]
(singing) WILL TAKE OUR LOVE
TOGETHER TO SOME SKIES (singing)
(singing) WHEN WE...
Both:
[ Giggling ]
(singing) ...ALONE AND
LOVE RENEW... (singing)
IF THE MINISTER'S WIFE
ATTEMPTS TO DO THIS
PIECE, I SHALL FAINT.
I CAN'T ALLOW IT.
(singing) ...FLOWERS BLUE...
[ Giggling ]
CAN'T YOU
JUST SEE
THE BUTTONS POPPING
OFF HER CORSET.
OH STOP, ANNE.
OH, I'M GOING TO BE SICK.
NOW, NOW, THIS IS YOU,
NERVOUSLY SWEEPING
UP THE AISLE ON
YOUR FATHER'S ARM,
YOUR BLACK CURLS
FROSTED OVER
WITH THE FILM OF YOUR
DELICATE CHIFFON VEIL.
THE PERFECT
BRIDE.
YOU LOOK INTO
FRED'S RED FACE
AND WHISPER,
"DO."
OH, NO.
DON'T BE MEAN.
JUST PROMISE
ME ONE THING.
IF HE FAINTS,
MAKE SURE YOU
CATCH HIM.
[ Scratching of record ]
DIANA?
DIANA BARRY,
WHAT IN HEAVEN'S
NAME IS GOING ON?
NOW YOU'VE
DONE IT.
DIANA, ANSWER ME.
NOTHING, MOTHER.
WE'RE JUST
REHEARSING THE
WEDDING MARCH.
WELL FOR PITY'S
SAKE, DON'T MARCH
THROUGH THE CEILING.
OH, I'M SO
NERVOUS, ANNE.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW I'M GOING
TO GET THROUGH
THIS TOMORROW.
YOU'LL BE
ALL RIGHT.
EVERYONE SURVIVES
THE CEREMONY.
IT'S AFTERWARDS...
OH, YOU'RE
SO SMUG.
JUST WAIT TILL
YOUR TURN COMES,
MISS ANNE.
NO, I HAVE DEFI-
NITELY DECIDED
ON A CAREER
OVER MARRIAGE.
I THINK I'D LIKE
TO BE A NUN.
WOULDN'T IT
BE WONDERFUL
TO BE THE BRIDE
OF HEAVEN?
OH, BUT THEN,
I'M NOT CATHOLIC.
AND I'D HARDLY
QUALIFY FOR THAT
SORT OF CAREER.
WELL, WHAT
ABOUT A NURSE?
THAT'S A ROMANTIC
PROFESSION,
SMOOTHING
FEVERED BROWS,
FALLING MADLY IN
LOVE WITH YOU,
AND CARRYING
YOU OFF TO THE
MEDITERRANEAN.
I CAN'T GIVE IT
UP FOR THE PROSAIC
REALITY OF GILBERT.
HE PROPOSED,
YOU KNOW...
AND I REFUSED.
YOU WHAT?
YES.
ANNE, ARE YOU
OUT OF YOUR MIND?
DON'T SCOLD ME, DIANA.
CAN'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
OH, ANNE, I
CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I THOUGHT ALL THIS
GOING ON ABOUT YOU
IDEALS WAS A COVER-UP
BECAUSE HE HADN'T
ASKED YOU YET.
YOU ACTUALLY SAID NO?
AFTER TWO YEARS
OF FLIRTING,
THIS IS
SCANDALOUS.
YOU TAKE THAT
BACK, DIANA BARRY.
I'VE NEVER
FLIRTED WITH HIM.
GIL AND I HAVE ONLY
EVER BEEN GOOD FRIENDS.
I EVEN STEERED CLEAR OF
GILBERT BECAUSE OF YOU.
HOW COULD YOU, ANNE?
I KNOW... I
DON'T LOVE HIM.
I'M SURE HE
DESPISES ME NOW.
AND YOU DESISE ME
AND I DESPISE
MYSELF.
I'M SO HUMILIATED
OVER THIS WHOLE
STUPID THING.
YOU POOR
DARLING.
I'VE NO RIGHT
TO SCOLD.
THINGS ARE
SO MIXED UP IN
REAL LIFE, ANNE.
EY'RE NEVER AS
CLEAR AS THEY ARE
IN ROMANTIC NOVELS.
[ Wedding music ]
(singing) OH PROMISE ME THAT
SOMEDAY YOU AND I (singing)
(singing) WILL TAKE OUR LOVE
TOGETHER TO SOME SKIES... (singing)
[ Mixed chatter ]
YOUR PARENTS
ARE COMING.
OH! OH, ANNE,
I SHALL DIE.
I'M SO NERVOUS,
I KNOW I'M GOING
TO FAINT, AUNT JO.
IF YOU DO, I'LL DRAG YOU DOWN
TO THE RAINWATER HOG SHED
AND DROP YOU IN.
HERE. LET
ME SEE YOU.
DON'T YOU FRET.
OH, YOU
LOOK LOVELY.
Mr. Barry:
WELL, EVERYTHING'S ALL READY.
I'VE GIVEN
THE MINISTER
THE SIGNAL.
OH, MY DARLING,
I'M LOSING
YOU FOREVER.
OH! OH!
NOW, NOW, DON'T GET ALL
SENTIMENTAL, ELIZABETH.
YOU STILL
HAVE MINNIE MAY.
TEARS AREN'T
LUCKY AT WEDDINGS.
(singing) ...OH PROMISE ME
(singing) HEARING GOD'S MESSAGE
WHILE THE ORGAN ROLLS (singing)
(singing) ITS MIGHTY MUSIC
TO OUR VERY SOULS (singing)
(singing) A LOVE THAT'S PERFECT
AND A LIFE WITH PEACE (singing)
(singing) OH PROMISE ME
(singing) OH PROMISE...
WHAT A FINE-
LOOKING PAIR.
YOU WON'T WIN THAT
BLYTHE BOY BACK
BY PUNISHING HIM.
I WONDER
WHY EVERYONE
SEEMS TO THINK
I OUGHT TO BE WITH
GILBERT BLYTHE.
DIANA...
[ Cheering/applause ]
[ Mixed greetings ]
EXCUSE ME.
MOODY SPURGEON.
Anne:
GOODNESS, YOU
LOOK OLDER
IN YOUR NEW
CELLULOID COLLAR.
THANKS, ANNE.
YOU LOOK DASHING
Y-YOURSELF.
Y-YOU LOOKED
AS GOOD AS
THE BRIDE.
WELL, HOW SWEET
OF YOU, MOODY,
TO ASK JOSIE
TO THE WEDDING.
YOU KNOW, I WAS
AFRAID YOU MIGHTN'T
HAVE BEEN INVITED.
ISN'T SHE
PRECIOUS, MOODY?
YOU WORE THAT
SWEET OLD DRESS
TO FANNY EMERSON'S
WEDDING LAST
YEAR THOUGH,
DIDN'T
YOU, ANNE?
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY,
"TWICE A BRIDESMAID,
NEVER A BRIDE."
THAT'S "THREE TIMES
A BRIDESMAID,"
NOT TWICE, JOSIE.
BUT THEN YOU'RE
SO FORTUNATE.
THE ONLY THING YOU'VE
EVER HAD TO WEAR TWICE
IS A SOUR EXPRESSION.
NOW, DON'T YOU FORGET
TO SAVE ME A WALTZ.
I WON'T, ANNE.
ALL RIGHT.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO BE POLITE.
YOUR TURN,
GILBERT...
AH, EXCUSE ME
A MOMENT, WON'T
YOU, CHRISTINE?
MOODY, JOSIE.
GILBERT.
WHAT'S WRONG?
I DON'T KNOW.
ANNE, WAIT.
PLEASE, GIL.
WHERE ARE
YOU GOING?
I'M LEAVING.
MARILLA TOOK
RACHEL BACK
EARLY.
SHE WAS
ILL, AND...
I DON'T FEEL
VERY WELL EITHER.
I'LL DRIVE
YOU BACK.
WHAT ABOUT
YOUR FRIEND?
I CAN EXPLAIN.
SHE WON'T MIND.
SHE LOOKS
LIKE A LOVELY
AND ACCOMPLISHED
YOUNG LADY, GIL.
IT'S NOT CHRISTINE
I CARE ABOUT.
THERE'S SOMEONE
ELSE, ISN'T THERE?
NO, GIL, HONESTLY
THERE ISN'T.
I DON'T CARE
FOR ANYONE
IN THAT WAY,
AND I LIKE
YOU MORE
THAN ANYBODY.
ANNE, I'LL WAIT.
EVEN IF I
THOUGHT YOU CARED
JUST A LITTLE.
I DO CARE, GIL.
I ALWAYS HAVE.
BUT I CAN NEVER, NEVER LOVE YOU
IN THE WAY THAT YOU WANT ME TO.
I'M HAPPY AS I AM.
I WON'T EVER MARRY.
YOU'LL MARRY ALL RIGHT.
SOME FOOL WHO'LL SIT
AND READ TENNYSON BY
FIRE LIGHT, NO DOUBT...
AND BUILD YOU
YOUR CASTLES
IN THE SKY.
I KNOW YOU.
PLEASE, GIL, I DON'T
MEAN TO HURT YOU,
BUT YOU'LL SEE THAT
I'M RIGHT BY AND BY,
WHEN YOU FALL
FOR SOMEONE ELSE.
YOU HAVEN'T
HURT ME REALLY.
IT'S JUST
THAT I'VE...
FOOLED MYSELF INTO
THINKING THAT YOU
LOVED ME, THAT'S ALL.
GIL, PLEASE.
I HOPE HE BREAKS
YOUR HEART...
WHOEVER HE IS.
YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
THEN MAYBE YOU'LL
COME TO YOUR SENSES.
ANNE!
OH, YOU LOOK
POSITIVELY
RADIANT.
YOU LOOK LIKE
YOU'VE SEEN
A GHOST.
GILBERT SPOKE
TO ME AGAIN.
DIANA, I FEEL
LIKE I'VE CUT OFF
HIS RIGHT ARM.
WOULD YOU PLEASE
GO AND TALK TO HIM?
I KNOW HE'LL
LISTEN TO YOU.
HURRY UP, DIANA.
I DON'T... I DON'T KNOW
WHEN OR... OR HOW, BUT...
I'LL TRY.
GOODBYE, ANNE.
FAREWELL, MY BELOVED.
(music)
[ Cheering ]
Christine:
YOU'RE WRONG,
TILLIE.
I THOUGHT
ANNE SHIRLEY
LOOKED LOVELY
BESIDE DIANA.
CHRISTINE STEWART,
YOU'RE TOO KIND.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU DIDN'T NOTICE
ANNE STARING
AT GILBRT,
JUST TO MAKE
HIM JEALOUS.
I KNOW THAT GIL IS
VERY FOND OF ANNE,
BUT HE CERTAINLY
ISN'T JEALOUS.
HUH!
SHE'S JUST TRYING
DESPERATELY TO WIN
HIM BACK FROM YOU.
Christine:
I DON'T THINK
IT'S THAT AT ALL.
BESIDES,
GIL AND I ARE
ONLY FRIENDS.
WELL, I THINK
ANNE SHIRLEY
HAS FAR TOO BIG
AN OPINION
OF HERSELF.
(music)
WHY, ANNE,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GOING TO STAY AT THE
BARRYS' FOR THE BONFIRE.
WHY DID YOU COME
HOME SO EARLY?
DIANA... SHE
WAS THE BRIDE
OF MY DREAMS.
BUT SHE AND FRED
HAVE LEFT NOW AND...
I FEEL TIRED
AND... ANXIOUS.
I DON'T KNOW.
PERHAPS I SHOULD
ACCEPT MISS STACEY'S
OFFER IN KINGSPORT.
I'D LIKE TO
SEE AND HEAR
NEW PLACES.
I COULD GET A WHOLE
BUNCH OF IDEAS I COULD
WRITE STORIES FROM.
RACHEL WAS FEELING
PRETTY DISCOURAGED
TODAY AT THE WEDDING,
HAVING TO MOVE
WEST AND LIVE WITH
HER BOY AND ALL.
AND THE THOUGHT CAME
TO ME THAT PERHAPS
I SHOULD ASK HER
TO BOARD WITH
ME INSTEAD OF
THE PICARD GIRL.
I HAVEN'T SAID
ANYTHING TO HER.
I WANTED
YOUR OPINION.
WELL, IT WOULD BE
YOUR DECISION, MARILLA.
BUT ARE YOU SURE?
WELL, SHE HAS HER
FAULTS, I KNOW.
BUT SHE HAS
BEEN MY NEAREST
NEIGHBOUR
FOR 45 YEARS, AND...
I'D RATHER PUT UP WITH
HER THAN LOSE HER.
PLEASE DON'T DO
THIS BECAUSE YOU FEEL
BADLY ON MY ACCOUNT.
OH, STUFF AND NONSENSE.
I CAN BE CIVIL
WITH RACHEL,
AS LONG AS SHE STAYS
OUT OF MY KITCHEN.
WE'LL BE QUITE CAPABLE
OF LOOKING AFTER THE FARM
WITH MR. BARRY'S HELP.
MARILLA...
DO YOU NEVER WISH
YOU'D ADOPTED A BOY
LIKE YOU
INTENDED TO?
I MEAN, HE COULD
HAVE RUN THIS FARM,
AND SAVED YOU
ALL THIS TROUBLE.
ANNE SHIRLEY,
I WOULDN'T TRADE
YOU FOR A DOZEN BOYS.
NOW YOU JUST
MIND THAT.
WAS IT A BOY THAT GOT
THE BACHELOR OF ARTS,
AND WON THE ROLLINGS
RELIABLE STORY CONTEST,
NOW WAS IT?
I'LL MISS YOU.
I'LL MISS MY GIRL.
PROMISE ME
YOU WON'T STAY
AWAY FOREVER.
(music)
I NEVER THOUGHT OF LIVING AS FAR
OFF THE ROAD AS GREEN GABLES,
BUT I... I'D RATHER LIVE AT
THE BOTTOM OF A WELL
THAN LEAVE
AVONLEA.
WELL, I KNOW HOW
GRATEFUL ANNE IS
TO YOU FOR STAYING.
WELL, SHE WAS
ALWAYS ONE TO
LEAP INTO THINGS
WHEN SHE'D
MADE HER MIND
UP TO IT.
IT'S A BLESSING
SHE'S OFF TO A LADIES'
ACADEMY, THAT'S WHAT.
I DON'T APPROVE OF
THEM CO-EDUCATIONAL
INSTITUTIONS,
AND I NEVER HAVE.
ALL THE GIRLS
FLIRTING WITH
ALL THE BOYS.
THEY DO STUDY A
LITTLE, RACHEL.
HUMPH. PRECIOUS
LITTLE.
HOWEVER HER PUPILS
WILL BE WELL
ENOUGH BEHAVED,
IF THIS SCHOOL'S
AS WELL-TO-DO
AS SHE CLAIMS.
I CAN'T IMAGINE I'VE
FORGOTTEN A THING.
Anne:
YOU'VE ALL BEEN
SO HELPFUL.
MIND HOW YOU
WERE RAISED NOW,
AND GO TO CHURCH
REGULARLY, ANNE,
AND BE CAREFUL
WHAT FRIENDS
YOU MAKE.
Marilla:
BE SURE TO PUT
ON YOUR WARM
UNDER-CLOTHES
WHEN THE WEATHER
GETS CHILLY.
Rachel:
YES, AND BE CAREFUL
OF YOUR HEALTH
WHATEVER YOU DO.
AND YOU LET US
HEAR FROM YOU WHEN
YOU'VE SETTLED.
Rachel:
GOODBYE, ANNE.
GOODBYE.
MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING'S
WELL TAGGED
WHEN YOU PUT
IT ON THE TRAIN.
DON'T WORRY,
WE'LL TAKE GOOD
CARE OF HER AT
THE STATION.
HURRY UP NOW.
YOU'LL BE LATE.
GOOD LUCK.
GOODBYE,
MARILLA.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'D DO
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'VE BOTH BEEN
SO WONDERFUL.
BUT I WON'T BE
GONE FOR LONG,
AND I PROMISE
I'LL WRITE AS
OFTEN AS I CAN.
GOODBYE.
(music)
WELL, MARILLA,
I NEVER WOULD
HAVE BELIEVED
AN ORPHAN COULD
TURN OUT SO FINE.
NO ONE COULD DENY
SHE'S REAL TALL
AND STYLISH NOW.
NOBODY AT ALL.
Marilla:
I CAN'T HELP
REMEMBERING HER
AS A LITTLE GIRL.
AWFUL HARD I
WAS BEWILDERED,
TRYING TO
MANAGE HER.
MATTHEW UNDERSTOOD
HER BETTER.
WELL, IT'S TO
YOUR CREDIT YOU'VE
CHANGED HER AS
MUCH AS YOU DID.
OH, SHE HASN'T
CHANGED THAT MUCH.
NOT REALLY.
IT'S US THAT'S
CHANGED, RACHEL.
(music)
HOW I'VE LONGED
FOR THIS MOMENT,
DIANA,
AND NOW THAT
IT'S STARING
ME IN THE FACE,
I CAN'T BEAR
THE THOUGHT
OF LEAVING.
WE SAW GIL BLYTHE OFF TO
MEDICAL SCHOOL LAST WEEK.
DID HE... SAY
ANYTHING, DIANA?
I THINK HE
UNDERSTANDS,
ANNE.
(music)
[ Chugging of train ]
ANNE?
ANNE SHIRLEY!
OH, THERE
YOU ARE.
OH, MISS STACEY.
IT FEELS
LIKE DECADES.
OH, UP ALL
NIGHT ON THAT
DREADFUL TRAIN,
YOU MUST BE
EXHAUSTED.
OH, I FEEL BROKEN-DOWN
AND GREEN AND PROVINCIAL,
AND ONLY TEN
YEARS OLD.
FOR PITY'S SAKE PLEASE
TAKE ME SOMEPLACE
WHERE I CAN HEAR
MYSELF THINK.
I'VE GOT A CAB
WAITING JUST OUTSIDE.
WHERE ARE YOUR
LUGGA TICKETS?
THE DRIVER CAN TAKE
CARE OF YOUR TRUNK.
IF YOU WEREN'T
HERE, MISS STACEY,
I THINK I SHOULD
JUST SIT DOWN AND
BURST INTO TEARS.
WELL, I CAN'T TELL YOU
JUST HOW HAPPY
I AM TO HAVE
YOU HERE, ANNE.
AFTER ALL, WHY BE
A MEMBER OF THE
BOARD OF GOVERNORS
OF AN INSTITUTION,
IF YOU CAN'T PULL
A FEW STRINGS?
OH, MISS STACEY,
YOU DIDN'T!
YES, I DID.
(music)
Anne:
I INTEND TO KEEP
UP WITH MY WRITING.
THIS QUAINT OLD
TOWN WILL BE A
WONDERFUL INSPIRATION.
WELL, I THINK
YOUR YOUTH
AND VITALITY
WILL MAKE AN ENORMOUS
CONTRIBUTION TO
OUR LADIES' COLLEGE.
AFTER ALL, YOU
WERE MY PRIZE
PUPIL IN AVONLEA.
Anne:
I'M SO NERVOUS
I WON'T MEET WITH
THEIR EXPECTATIONS.
Miss Stacey:
OH, NONSENSE.
THEY MAY BE PRIVILEGED
YOUNG LADIES FROM
WEALTHY FAMILIES,
BUT THEY'RE SPOILED AND
PAMPERED, MANY OF THEM.
(music)
GREAT JEHOSOPHAT!
WHAT RICHNESS!
THIS IS FAR
MORE GRACIOUS
THAN I EVER
DREAMED
COULD EXIST.
[ Rapping on door ]
GOOD MORNING,
MA'AM.
GOOD MORNING.
COULD YOU PLEASE
TELL MISS PRINGLE
THAT MISS STACEY
AND MISS ANNE SHIRLEY
ARE HERE TO SEE HER.
I THINK
YOU'LL BE QUITE
COMFORTABLE HERE.
MRS. TOM PRINGLE
IS ON THE ALUMNI.
SHE'S BEEN
BOARDING TEACHERS
FROM KINGSPORT
LADIES' COLLEGE
FOR 30 YEARS NOW.
MISS STACEY,
HOW DELIGHTFUL
TO SEE YOU.
AND YOU,
MRS. PRINGLE.
MAY I INTRODUCE
YOU TO MISS
ANNE SHIRLEY
OF AVONLEA,
PRINCE EDWARD
ISLAND?
HOW DO YOU DO?
SHE'S OUR NEW
ENGLISH TEACHER
AT KINGSPORT
LADIES' COLLEGE,
WHO YOU'LL
BE BOARDING
THIS YEAR.
SHOULD I HAVE
THE CABBY BRING
HER TRUNK?
OBVIOUSLY YOU DID
NOT RECEIVE MY LETTER.
I'M AFRAID I'VE
DECIDED NOT TO TAKE
HER, MISS STACEY.
I'M REALLY
RATHER TIRED OF
BEING BOTHERED
BOARDING STAFF.
MY GIRLS ARE FINISHED,
AS YOU KNOW,
AND I REALLY SPEND
SO LITTLE TIME
WITH THE ALUMNI.
BUT MRS. PRINGLE...
I DO APOLOGIZE FOR
THE INCONVENIENCE.
GOOD DAY, MISS STACEY.
NOT AT ALL.
GOOD DAY.
HOW TYPICALLY
PRINGLE.
AS SMOOTH AS CREAM, EVEN WHEN
THEY'RE WORKING AGAINST YOU.
WELL, WE SHALL
SEE ABOUT
THAT. HMM?
WHAT IS IT,
MISS STACEY?
KINGSPORT IS
FULL OF PRINGLES
AND HALF-PRINGLES.
THEY'RE THE
OLD MONEY THAT
RULES THIS TOWN,
AND MRS. TOM PRING
BOSSES THE WHOLE TRIBE.
I WAS AFRAID
THEY'D BE
DOWN ON YOU.
WHY SHOULD THEY
BE? I'M A TOTAL
STRANGER.
ONE OF THEIR
COUSINS, MISS AMY
PRINGLE BOOTHE,
APPLIED FOR
YOUR POSITION,
AND WAS ABYSMALLY
LESS QUALIFIED,
I MIGHT ADD.
HOWEVER, WHEN THE
BOARD ANNOUNCED
THAT THEY HAD
ACCEPTED YOUR
APPLICATION,
WELL THE WHOLE
KIT AND KABOODLE
OF THEM
JUST THREW BACK
THEIR HEADS
AND HOWLED.
UH, KINGSPORT
LADIES' COLLEGE,
PLEASE, DRIVER.
WELL, THEY'RE
NOT GOING TO GET
AWAY WITH IT.
THEY CAN'T BOYCOTT
THE BOARD'S DECISION.
IT'S UNDEMOCRATIC.
Anne:
I'M NOT SURE I QUITE
ALWAYS TRUST DEMOCRACY.
THEY'VE ALWAYS
RULED THE ROOST
HERE, THE WHOLE
CLAN OF THEM.
POLITICALLY
AND SOCIALLY.
WELL, THEY MAY OWN
THE LUMBER MILL,
THE RAILWAY,
THE GAS WORKS AND
THE WOOLEN MILL,
BUT I WILL NOT ALLOW THE
PRINGLES TO DICTATE OUR
SYSTEM OF EDUCATION.
YOU CAN'T
IMAGINE HOW
NERVOUS I AM NOW.
[ Chuckling ]
(music)
MISS KATHANE
BROOKE IS THE
PRINCIPAL HERE.
A BIT OF A
MARTINET IN MATTERS
OF DISCIPLINE,
FROM TIME
TO TIME,
BUT I'M SURE
THAT WE CAN RESOLVE
WHATEVER LITTLE
DIFFERENCES
OF OPINION
THAT MIGHT
ARISE.
(music)
[ Rapping on door ]
COME IN.
GOOD MORNING,
MISS BROOKE.
MISS STACEY.
PLEASE FORGIVE
THE INTRUSION,
BUT I WAS JUST
SO EAGER TO
INTRODUCE YOU
TO OUR NEW
ENGLISH PROFESSOR,
MISS ANNE SHIRLEY.
ONE OF THE BRIGHTEST
STARS OF MY ENTIRE
TEACHING CAREER.
SHE HAS RECENTLY
PUBLISHED A SHORT WORK
OF FICTION AS WELL.
WELCOME TO KINGSPORT,
MISS SHIRLEY.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
THANK YOU. I'M
VERY PLEASED
TO BE HERE.
MISS STACEY HAS
RECOMMENDED YOU
SO HIGHLY TO US.
I HADN'T EXPECTED
ONE SO ACCOMPLISHED
TO BE SO YOUNG...
A FAULT WHICH TIME
WILL CURE ALL TOO SOON.
MISS BROOKE, THERE SEEMS
TO BE SOME SORT OF MIX-UP
REGARDING MISS SHIRLEY'S
ACCOMMODATIONS,
BUT I WAS SURE THAT
YOU WOULDN'T OBJECT
HAVING HER STAY
HERE AT THE SCHOOL
WITH YOUR
OUT-OF-TOWN
BOARDING
STUDENTS.
I'M SURE YOU'LL FIND
HER TO BE THE PERFECT
DEN-MOTHER FOR THEM.
WE HAVE NO NEED OF
MATERNAL AFFECTATIONS
IN THIS INSTITUTE,
MISS STACEY.
WE GOVERN BY RULES
AND REGULATIONS.
WHICH DO REQUIRE A
LEAVEN IN THE LUMP
FROM TIME TO
TIME, MS BROOKE.
SHALL WE HAVE THE
GROUNDSMAN BRING IN
MISS SHIRLEY'S THINGS?
I'LL HAVE THE MAID
PREPARE HER ROOM.
THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
SHE IS AN ABSOLUTE
SERGEANT-MAJOR,
MISS STACEY.
HOW SHALL I EVER
TOLERATE HER SARCASM?
NONETHELESS SHE IS
A DEDICATED TEACHER,
IF SOMEWHAT OF AN EXCES-
SIVE DISCIPLINARIAN.
YOU JUST KEEP
YOUR CHIN UP,
AND YOU GIVE IT
YOUR VERY BEST,
IF ONLY TO
SPITE THEM ALL.
YOU KNOW HOW HIGHLY
I REGARD YOUR
ABILITIES, ANNE.
I SHALL DO
VERY BEST TO RISE
TO THE OCCASION.
GOOD GIRL.
NOW YOU WANT
TO GET YOURSELF
ORGANIZED
BEFORE THE
START OF CLASSES
TOMORROW.
OH, HO-HO!
OH.
THANK YOU FOR
EVERYTHING,
MISS STACEY.
WE CAN DO THE
REST OF OUR
CATCHING UP LATER.
(music)
IN FUTURE,
MISS SHIRLEY,
YOU WILL
KINDLY REMEMBER
THAT YOU ARE
NOT AT LIBERTY TO
MAKE ANY CHANGES,
NO MATTER HOW MINOR,
TO THE CONVENTIONS
OF THIS INSTITUTION.
I'M SORRY, I...
I WAS JUST
SO MOVED BY YOUR
INSPIRING QUOTATION,
I WANTED TO
EMBELLISH IT.
DON'T PATRONIZE ME.
WHAT IS TO BE THE
PILL IN AL THIS
JAM, MISS SHIRLEY?
WHY NOTHING. I...
I JUST THOUGHT IT
WAS A TREMENDOUSLY
UPLIFTING IDEA,
THAT'S ALL.
I'M GLAD YOU SPELL
YOUR NAME WITH A "K".
KATHARINE WITH A "K" IS
SO MUCH MORE ALLURING
THAN CATHERINE
WITH A "C".
A "C" ALWAYS
LOOKS SO SMUG.
WE HAVE 50
YOUNG LADIES
IN OUR CHARGE,
FROM THE MOST PRIVILEGED
FAMILIES IN THE MARITIMES.
MY METHODS ADMONISH ANYTHING
BEYOND THE STANDARDS
OF THE UTMOST DECORUM.
THIS IS NOT A PUBLIC
SCHOOL OF THE KIND
THAT YOU ARE USED
TO, MISS SHIRLEY.
OUR STUDENTS
DO NOT REQUIRE
EMBELLISHMENT.
SIMPLE STRAIGHT-
FORWARD ADHERENCE TO
RULES AND REGULATIONS
WHICH I HAVE CLEARLY
DELINEATED FOR YOU,
MISS SHIRLEY.
OUR STUDENTS
ARE DRILLED IN
THEIR STUDIES
AT THE BEGINNING
OF EACH CLASS.
BEDTIME AND MEALTIME
WILL BE STRICTLY OBSERVED
BY OUR 15 BOARDERS.
YOU,
MISS SHIRLEY,
WILL SEE TO IT
THAT THE BOARDERS ESPECIALLY
ADHERE TO THE
UTMOST ORDERLINESS.
I AM PLACING
THEM UNDER
YOUR CONTINUAL
DIRECTION.
I AM
REFERRED TO
BY THE ENTIRE
FACULTY AS BROOKE.
YOU MAY DO THE SAME.
YES, MISS BROOKE.
I UNDERSTAND YOU HAVE
EXTRAORDINARY TALENTS.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO OBSERVING THEM.
I AM GLAD I MEET
WITH YOUR APPROVAL
IN SOME APPROXIMATION.
WE SHALL SEE.
YOU ARE HERE AS A
RESULT OF THE BOARD'S
DECISION, NOT MINE.
[ Jangling of
electric bell ]
FOR A COUNTRY-
SCHOOL MA'RM,
YOU'LL FIND
THAT WE ARE
EQUIPPED WITH
THE MOST MODERN
EFFICIENCIES,
DUE TO THE TREMENDOUS
FINANCIAL SUPPORT
OF CERTAIN PROMINENT FAMILIES.
Girls:
[ Singing ]
IN FACT, WE ARE
THE FIRST SCHOOL
IN THE PROVINCE
TO HAVE A TELEPHONE.
(singing) ALL THINGS BRIGHT
AND BEAUTIFUL (singing)
(singing) ALL CREATURES
GREAT AND SMALL (singing)
(singing) ALL THINGS WISE
AND WONDERFUL (singing)
(singing) THE LORD GOD
MADE THEM ALL (singing)
WELCOME TO A NEW YEAR.
I TRUST YOU GIRLS
ARE READY TO DRIVE
INTO THE FIRST SESSION
WITH DETERMINATION.
YOU ALL KNOW MISS MCKAY,
MATHEMATICS AND SCIENCE,
MISS KERR, HISTORY
AND GEOGRAPHY,
AND MISS SHIRLEY WILL
BE YOUR NEW TEACHER,
RESPONSIBLE FOR
ENGLISH AND LITERATURE,
AS WELL AS ALL
STUDENT BOARDERS.
MISS SHIRLEY
WILL BE LIVING IN
THE SCHOOL WITH US,
AND WILL HAVE DIRECT
SUPERVISORY AUTHORITY.
LET US GET TO WORK THEN,
WITH NO NONSENSE.
PLEASE ORGANIZE
YOURSELVES INTO FORMS.
[ Blasting of whistle ]
FORM ONE, DO YOU CALL
THAT A STRAIGHT LINE?
EMMELINE HARRIS...
STEP FORWARD.
IF YOU INTEND TO
MAKE A HABIT OF THIS,
I WILL HAVE NO
CHOICE BUT TO DETAIN
YOU AFTER CLASS.
STEP BACK.
LEARN TO RESPOND TO SIGNALS ON
THE ELECTRIC BELL AS WELL.
I'D MUCH PREFER TO INVENT
TITLES FOR EACH GROUP,
LIKE A
SORORITY.
WHAT ABOUT...
TUDOR, KENT AND WINDSOR?
I AM NOT INTERESTED
IN FAIRY TALES.
YOU MUST LEARN TO USE
THE MODERN CONVENIENCES
OF OUR SYSTEM.
AT RECESS, I
WILL EMPLOY THE
ELECTRIC BELL.
[ Blasting of whistles ]
YOUR ROOM IS
DOWN THE HALL,
FIRST DOOR.
[ Blasting of whistle ]
PERHAPS YOU THINK
YOU ARE ABOVE RULES,
MISS SHIRLEY?
Girls:
[ Giggling ]
Anne:
[ Clearing of throat ]
WELL... OFF
YOU GO, GIRLS.
[ Giggling/chattering ]
Anne:
PLEASE, GIRLS.
QUIET PLEASE.
GOOD MORNING.
[ Clearing of throat ]
I WOULD LIKE TO BEGIN
BY SHARING WITH YOU
WHAT A GREAT PRIVILEGE
IT WOULD BE FOR ME
TO SHARE WITH YOU... UH!
Girls:
[ Laughing nastily ]
OH, BLAST!
[ Groan of pain ]
...TO SHARE WITH
YOU MY GREAT LOVE OF
ENGLISH LITERATURE
DURING THE
FORTHCOMING YEAR.
LET'S HOPE I'M A LITTLE
LIGHTER ON SHAKESPEARE
THAN I AM ON MY FEET.
[ Clearing of throat ]
[ Snapping of chalk ]
NEVER MIND.
I HAD A SPEECH PREPARED,
BUT IT DOESN'T SEEM VERY
IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW.
MY NAME IS ANNE SHIRLEY,
AND I KNOW WE SHALL
ALL BECOME GOOD
FRIENDS IN NO TIME.
Girls: [ Chanting ]
7 TIMES 2 IS 14.
7 TIMES 3 IS 21.
7 TIMES 4 IS 28.
7 TIMES 5 IS...
I COME FROM A LITTLE
TOWN CALLED AVONLEA ON
PRINCE EDWARD ISLAND,
WHERE I HAVE BEEN
TEACHING FOR THE
PAST TWO YEARS.
SO THIS IS MY FIRST
TIME IN A PRIVATE
SCHOOL POSITION.
AND I HOPE THAT YOU WILL
ALL BE ABLE TO GIVE ME
LOTS OF ASSISTANCE.
NOW... WHEN I CALL
OUT YOUR NAME,
ANSWER "HERE".
PRINGLE, MYRA C.
PRINGLE, REBECCA A.
AREN'T THESE YOUR NAMES?
NO, MISS, PERHAPS
THE CLASS LISTS
HAVE BEEN MIXED UP.
Girls:
[ Giggling ]
OH, ALL RIGHT,
GIVE ME YOUR NAMES
THEN, ONE AT A TIME,
STARTING HERE, THE YOUNG
LADY IN THE FRONT ROW.
LAST NAME FIRST, AND AGE.
OPPENER,
FANNY I. OPPENER.
THERE ARE TWO
"Ps" IN OPPENER.
14.
GIRDLE, MYRTLE N. GIRDLE.
HEIND. THAT'S H-E-I-N-D.
ALICE B. HEIND. 14.
BALL. WILMA I. BALL.
33.
ACTUALLY I'M FROM
THE ROLLINGS RELIABLE
BAKING COMPANY,
AND WE WERE WONDERING
WHEN YOU'D BE AVAILABLE
TO REWRITE OUR LABELS.
THAT'S ENOUGH!
I HADN'T ANTICIPATED A CLASS
WHOSE PARENTS WERE
SUCH NITWITS AT
NAMING THEIR CHILDREN.
HARRIS.
EMMELINE HARRIS. 13.
AND DON'T BELIEVE ANY
OF THEM, MISS SHIRLEY.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THEY'RE JUST PULLING
YOUR LEG BECAUSE
THEY'RE PRINGLES,
AND THEY THINK THEY
CAN GET AWAY WITH IT.
OLD TELESCOPE-EYES HERE
WOULDN'T KNOW A PRINGLE
IF SHE WERE FACE-
TO-FACE WITH ONE.
Girls:
[ Laughing nastily ]
SINCE MISSES
FANNY EYEOPPENER,
MYRTLE ENGIRDLE,
ALICE BEHEIND AND
WILMA EYEBALL FIND THEM-
SELVES SO TERRIBLY WITTY,
THEY WILL WRITE
OUT AN ACCURATE
CLASS LIST 100 TIMES,
TODAY AFTER CLASSES,
FOR MY BENEFIT.
NOW, OPEN YOUR
READERS, PLEASE.
[ Screaming ]
Girls:
[ Quavering ]
PLEASE...
M-M-MISS SHIRLEY...
[ Screaming continues ]
Girl:
OH, MISS SHIRLEY,
HELP HER.
[ Murmurs of concern ]
Anne:
EMMELINE HARRIS,
TAKE THIS GIRL TO
THE LADIES' ROOM.
SOAK THE HANDKERCHEIF
IN COLD WATER
AND SEE IF YOU CAN
STOP THE BLEEDING.
Girls:
[ Chatter/laughter ]
[ Blasting of whistle ]
ALL RIGHT. ALL OF
YOU SIT DOWN NOW!
AND REMAIN SEATED.
WHO PUT THE SNAKE
IN MY DESK?
WHAT IS YOUR REAL NAME?
JEN PRINGLE,
MISS SHIRY.
WAS IT YOU, JEN PRINGLE?
YES, IT WAS.
YOU WILL BE DETAINED
AFTER CLASSES TODAY...
AND EVERY DAY FOR
THE ENTIRE WEEK.
[ Murmurs of reaction ]
NOW, PLEASE, OPEN
YOUR THIRD FORM
READERS, CLASS.
I CAN'T, MISS SHIRLEY.
MY MOTHER EXPECTS ME
FOR THE NEXT THREE DAYS
AT THE LADIES' AID
SOCIETY RUMMAGE SALE.
WELL, I'M SORRY BUT YOUR
MOTHER WILL HAVE TO MAKE
OTHER ARRANGEMENTS.
BUT SHE'S PROMISED
MY HELP ON THE ORGAN-
IZATION COMMITTEE.
I DON'T CARE.
YOU'LL STAY IF I SAY SO.
I SIMPLY CANNOT STAY.
I'M SORRY.
WELL THEN, IT'S
UP TO YOU, ISN'T
IT, JEN PRINGLE?
EITHER YOU STAY AFTER
SCHOOL FOR THE WEEK...
OR I'LL HAVE TO
MINISTER THE STRAP.
Myra:
YOU JUST CAN'T DO
THAT, MISS SHIRLEY.
[ Mixed whispers ]
I'LL TAKE THE STRAP.
REALLY?
[ Clearing of throat ]
COME HERE THEN,
MISS PRINGLE.
PUT OUT YOUR HAND.
[ Impact of
strap on hand ]
(music)
OPEN YOUR READERS, CLASS,
AND PLEASE LOOK AT
THE FIRST CHAPTER FOR
THE REST OF THE PERIOD.
(music)
[ Jangling of
electric bell ]
Girls:
[ Chattering ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, ESSIE?
I'M AFRAID I'M NOT VERY
GOOD AROUND REPTILES.
NEITHER AM I.
YOU'LL GET
USED TO ESSIE,
MISS SHIRLEY.
SHE FAINTS AT
LEAST ONCE A WEEK.
THE DOCTORS
SAY HER BLOOD
IS WEAK.
THANK YOU, EMMELINE.
DON'T CONCERN
YOURSELF ABOUT THE
PRINGLE GIRLS EITHER.
THE ONLY PEOPLE THEY
LIKE ARE THEMSELVES.
I CAN SAY THAT
WITHOUT MALICE,
BECAUSE MY MOTHER
WAS A PRINGLE.
BESIDES, I LIKE YOU,
AND I THINK YOU
HANDLED THE CLASS
VERY INTELLIGENTLY.
(music)
[ Twittering of birds ]
[ Mixed chattering ]
YOU TRAITOR,
HARRIS.
I GUESS THERE
ARE ONLY TWO
KINDS OF PEOPLE
IN KINGSPORT;
THOSE WHO
ARE PRINGLES
AND THOSE
WHO AREN'T.
SHUT UP, JEN.
I DON'T CARE A
SNIT WHAT YOU SAY.
I'M HALF-PRINGLE.
HUH, YOUR MOTHER
DIDN'T LIVE LONG ENOUGH
TO MAKE YOU ANYTHING.
AND MY PAPA
SAYS YOUR PAPA
IS THE GREATEST
PHILANDERER IN
THIS COUNTRY,
SO THAT
PRACTICALLY
MAKES YOU
AN ORPHAN.
Emmeline/Essie:
[ Yelps of distress ]
DON'T YOU DARE
EVER SAY ANOTHER
WORD ABOUT MY
FATHER AGAIN.
YOU STUPID, GOOD-FOR-
NOTHING GOOSE-EGG.
[ Mixed shouting ]
HE'S A BRUTE,
AND MY PAPA
SAYS SO.
LET'S SEE HOW
BIG YOUR MOUTH IS
NOW, JEN PRINGLE.
[ Squealing ]
[ Mixed shouting ]
OH, MY GLASSES!
STOP IT!
[ Blasting of whistle ]
THAT IS ENOUGH!
ON YOUR... GET UP THERE.
STAND UP.
HAVE YOU GIRLS
NO PROPRIETY?
THIS IS NOT
TURKISH BAZAAR.
THEY TRIED TO RUN ME
DOWN ON THAT BICYCLE.
YOU LITTLE LIAR!
SHE THREW HER CROQUET
MALLET IN THE WHEEL
AND TRIPPED US.
DIDN'T SHE,
ESSIE?
I DID NOT, YOU BEAST!
SHE ATTACKED ME.
STOP IT!
I HAVE A GOOD MIND
TO EXPEL YOU BOTH
FOR SUCH HOOLIGANISM.
BICYCLES ARE FORBIDDEN
ON SCHOOL PROPERTY.
THIS CONTRAPTION
IS CONFISCATED
AS OF THIS MOMENT.
BUT, MISS BROOKE, THE
BICYCLE ISN'T MINE.
IT'S MY BROTHER'S.
HE OUGHT NOT TO
HAVE BEEN SO FOOLISH
AS TO HAVE ENTRUSTED
IT TO YOU.
IT HARDLY SEEMS FAIR TO
BE PUNISHING HER BROTHER.
YES, MISS BROOKE,
I THINK...
DO YOU NOT UNDER-
STAND ENGLISH?
Miss Brooke:
NOW I WANT YOU TWO
GIRLS TO APOLOGIZE
TO EACH OTHER,
AND BEHAVE LIKE
PROPER YOUNG LADIES.
I AM QUITE
PREPARED TO
FORGIVE YOUR
LACK OF MANNERS.
AND I YOUR
RUDE COMMENTS.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
WELL, DON'T STAND THERE
LIKE PIGEONS, GIRLS.
GO ALONG.
IF YOU ALLOW AN
OUTBURST LIKE THAT
TO OCCUR AGAIN,
MISS SHIRLEY,
YOU SHALL HAVE
THE BOARD TO
RECKON WITH.
LOCK THIS IN THE
SHED, MCTAVISH.
GO ALONG,
GIRLS,
DON'T GAWK.
(music)
LOOKING FOR THESE?
JEN!
I'M SORRY ABOUT
YOUR SPECTACLES.
WE'LL GET THEM REPLACED.
IT'S NOT THAT.
IT'S WHAT SHE SAID
ABOUT MY PAPA.
JUST YOU FORGET ABOUT
WHATEVER THEY SAID.
THERE'S NOT AN OUNCE
OF TRUTH IN IT.
WE WON'T LET
IT SPOIL THE
AFTERNOON.
WE DIDN'T
GET YOU INTO
TROUBLE,
DID WE,
MISS SHIRLEY?
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT ME.
BROOKE'S JUST
AN OLD BATTLE-
AXE ANYWAY.
DON'T TELL
ANYBODY I
SAID THAT.
I ALMOST FAINTED
WHEN I SAW HER COME
ACROSS THE LAWN.
WELL, SHE'LL COOL OFF
IN A FEW DAYS AND...
THEN I'LL GET
YOUR BROTHER'S
BICYCLE BACK.
COME ALONG, AND
DON'T YOU GIVE
IT ANOTHER WORRY.
Essie:
YOU SHOULD
HAVE SEEN HER
WITH HER MOUTH
FULL OF MUD,
MISS SHIRLEY.
THAT'S THE BEST
JEN PRINGLE'S
LOOKED IN A
LONG TIME.
[ Knocking on door ]
ALL RIGHT, I'M
TURNING MY LIGHT
OUT NOW, MISS BROOKE.
[ Knking on door ]
Emmeline:
MISS SHIRLEY?
EMMELINE!
OH, MISS SHIRLEY,
YOU'VE GOT TO HELP US.
ESSIE'S BROTHER
NEEDS THE BICYCLE
IN THE MORNING
FOR HIS
DELIVERY
JOB, OR HE'LL
BE FIRED,
AND HE'S READY
TO MURDER ESSIE.
WE CAN'T GET THE
SHED DOORS OPEN.
OH, SHE'S
AWFUL SCARED,
AND I'M AFRAID
SHE'LL FAINT.
HEAVEN PRESERVE US FROM
MISS BROOKE IF SHE DOES.
MR. MCTAVISH,
THE GROUNDSMAN,
KEEPS HIS TOOLS
IN HERE.
MAYBE WE COULD SAW THE
CHAIN OR PICK THE LOCK.
STOP WHIMPERING, ESSIE.
EMMELINE, DO YOU THINK
YOU COULD SQUEEZE THROUGH
THAT SKYLIGHT UP ABOVE?
UH-HUH, IF I
HAD A LADDER.
COME ALONG. I'VE
GOT A BETTER IDEA.
(music)
ALL RIGHT, YOU
GO DOWN FIRST,
AND I'LL SHIMMY
DOWN AFTER YOU.
I'M FRIGHTENED.
I'M GOING
TO FAINT.
OH, JUST HANG
ON ANOTHER
MOMENT, ESSIE,
AND YOU CAN.
IF ANYONE
CATCHES US, YOU
DON'T PPOSE
THEY'LL THINK
WE'RE TRYING
TO STEAL ANY-
THING, DO YOU,
MISS SHIRLEY?
OUR MOTIVES
ARE HARDLY
IDLE CURIOSITY.
Emmeline:
ALL RIGHT.
UNTIE THE END,
ESSIE, AND
THROW IT DOWN.
[ Whimpering ]
Essie:
I DON'T THINK
YOU SHOULD
DO THIS.
OH, I HOPE
THE SKYLIGHT'S
NOT LOCKED,
MISS SHIRLEY.
WE'RE IN LUCK.
MR. MCTAVISH HAS AN ARMY
OF TOOLS DOWN HERE.
GOOD, NOW IF
WE CAN JUST...
[ Yelping ]
OH, MISS SHIRLEY!
[ Shrieking ]
BED SHEETS!
WELL NOW, ANNE SHIRLEY,
WHERE'S THE FIRE?
[ Groan of despair ]
[ Jangling of
electric bell ]
Anne:
GOOD MORNING.
[ Clearing of throat ]
[ Mixed whispers ]
GOOD MORNING, CLASS.
Girls:
[ Snickering ]
REALLY, GIRLS,
IF YOU CAN'T COME
UP WITH A BETTER
LIKENESS THAN THAT,
I SUGGEST YOU
GIVE UP ALTOGETHER.
OPEN YOUR OXFORD BOOK
OF VERSE, PAGE 223.
TENNYSON'S
"THE LADY OF SHALOTT".
EMMELINE, WOULD YOU
PLEASE READ THE FIRST
FOUR VERSES FOR US?
THEN WE'LL
DISCUSS THEM.
Myra:
MY, MY,
WHOSE APPLE ARE
WE POLISHING NOW?
LET'S HITCH OUR WAGON
TO A STAR, GIRLS.
Girls:
[ Giggling ]
WILLOWS WHITEN,
ASPENS QUIVER.
LITTLE BREEZES
DUSK AND SHIVER.
THROUGH THE WAVE
THAT RUNS FOREVER,
FLOWING DOWN TO CAMELOT.
[ Opening of door ]
WHY ARE YOU LATE?
MY MOTHER INSISTED
ON KEEPING MY
MAID THIS MORNING.
I HAD NO ONE TO
DARN MY STOCKINGS.
KINGSPORT LADIES'
COLLEGE DOES NOT
TOLERATE TARDINESS,
NOR DO I.
TAKOUT YOUR
DICTIONARY,
AND COPY OUT THE
ENTIRE "A" SECTION.
YOU WILL HAVE TO CATCH
UP ON THIS CLASS LATER.
THERE SHE KEPT
HER VIGIL ONLY,
WAITING IN HER
CHAMBER LONELY,
AND LOOKED DOWN
TO CAMELOT.
REAPERS REAPING
FIELDS OF BARLEY...
ARE YOU TRYING
TO TELL ME
THAT EMMELINE
IS SOLELY
RESPONSIBLE FOR
THIS MISCONDUCT?
I AM NOT TRYING TO
TELL YOU ANYTHING
OTHER THAN THAT
YOUR DAUGHTER
HAS AN OVERT DISREGARD
FOR REGULATIONS.
STEALING IS
STEALING.
I DON'T SEE
HOW YOU CAN
PRETEND IT TO
BE OTHERWISE.
THIS INCIDENT IS THE
TIP OF THE ICEBERG.
I BELIEVE SHE REQUIRES
REMEDIAL DISCIPLINE.
I WANT THAT TEACHER
RAKED OVER THE COALS
AS WELL THEN.
I'D LIKE NOTHING
BETTER, CAPTAIN HARRIS,
BUT THAT WILL BE FOR
THE BOARD TO DECIDE.
LET ME BE PERFECTLY
CLEAR, MISS BROOKE.
I WILL NOT
ALLOW EMMELINE...
TO BE EXPELLED
FROM ANY SCHOOL.
I AM WITH-
DRAWING BOTH
MY DAUGHTER
AND MY FINANCIAL
SUPPORT FROM THIS SECOND-
RATE INSTITUTION...
IMMEDIATELY.
YOU CAN RECKON
WITH THE OARD
OF GOVERNORS.
THERE SHE WEAVES
BY NIGHT AND DAY,
A MAGIC WEB
OF COLOURS GAY.
SHE HAS HEARD
A WHISPER SAY,
"CURSES ON HER
IF SHE STAY
TO LOOK DOWN ON CAMELOT."
Myra/Jen:
[ Giggling ]
I HAVE WARNED YOU TWO
ABOUT FOOD IN CLASS.
BRING THAT PARCEL
HERE, MYRA.
BRING THAT PARCEL HERE.
THROW IT IN THE STOVE.
ARE YOU SURE YOU REALLY
WANT ME TO DO THIS?
MYRA, OBEY ME AT ONCE.
Girl:
WHY IS SHE
RUNNING?
[ Screaming ]
RUN, GIRLS!
GIRLS, RUN!
[ Screaming ]
RUN, GIRLS!
Essie:
NO!
RUN!
MY SKIRT
IS CAUGHT.
[ Moan of fainting ]
Girls:
[ Screaming ]
[ Coughing ]
Captain Harris:
EMMELINE!
PAPA! PAPA!
PAPA, YOU CAME.
MARCH STRAIGHT OUT TO THE
CAR, YOUNG LADY, AND...
AND TAKE OFF
THOSE RIDICULOUS-
LOOKING SPECTACLES.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE WEARING
THEM, OTHER THAN FOR READING.
[ Jangling of
electric bell ]
Miss Brooke:
SHUT THAT BLASTED
ALARM BELL OFF.
THIS IS
MY TEACHER,
MISS SHIRLEY.
Captain Harris:
MISS SHIRLEY,
IS IT?
WE'VE MET BEFORE,
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN.
YES, SIR,
I REMEMBER.
[ Soft moan ]
COME ON, ESSIE.
WHAT IN THE DEVIL
HAVE YOU DONE NOW?
Captain Harris:
MISS SHIRLEY'S GOT
THE ENTIRE ACADEMY
AWAITING YOUR REMEDIAL
DISCIPLINE, MISS BROOKE.
I'M QUITE POSITIVE YOU'LL
ENJOY THE CHALLENGE.
EMMELINE,
COME ALONG.
YOU'RE LEAVING THIS
FOURTH-RATE INSTITUTION
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
[ Sigh of
exasperation ]
Miss McKay:
GIRLS, GIRLS, GET AWAY
FROM THAT AUTO CAR.
(music)
WHAT SORT OF
THINGS ARE BEING SAID!
WELL, HATTIE PRINGLE; YOU
ARE ACCUSED OF 'MARKING DOWN'
HER PAPERS JUST
BECAUSE SHE IS A PRINGLE.
HERE YOU ARE SAID
TO LAUGH AT THE STUDENTS
WHEN THEY MAKE MISTAKES.
WHAT?
WELL ALRIGHT I DID LAUGH
WHEN MYRA PRINGLE DEFINED
AN ALLIGATOR AS "A
LARGE KIND OF INSECT".
I COULDN'T HELP MYSELF.
OH DEAR.
MR. JAMES PRINGLE, THE FATHER
OF JEN PRINGLE CLAIMS THAT THERE
IS NO DISCIPLINE WHATSOEVER
AT THE SCHOOL SINCE YOUR ARRIVAL
AND HE IS CIRCULATING A
REPORT THAT YOU ARE A "FOUNDLING"
WELL, IT GOES ON AND ON.
ALMOST EVERY PRINGLE PARENT
HAS WRITTEN THE BOARD DEMANDING,
NOT REQUESTING,
DEMANDING YOUR RESIGNATION.
OH THOSE CANTANKEROUS,
PREJUDICED OLD CREATURES!
HOW CAN ANYONE POSSIBLY
SUCCEED AGAINST SUCH TACTICS!
I'M SO SORRY ANNE.
I DO FEEL RESPONSIBLE...
WELL, ON BEHALF OF THE 15
STUDENTS WHO AREN'T PRINGLES
I AM DETERMINED TO PERSEVERE.
CAPTAIN HARRIS HAS WITHDRAWN
HIS RATHER SUBSTANTIAL FINANCIAL
SUPPORT TOWARDS THE COLLEGE
MORTGAGE AND SEVERAL OF THE
OTHER PRINGLE FAMILIES ARE
THREATENING TO DO THE SAME...
I SEE.
SO YOU WANT ME
TO RESIGN AS WELL.
NEVER.
THE BOARD WANTS YOU TO RESIGN.
I WANT YOU TO STAY HERE AND MAKE
THESE PRINGLES EAT THEIR WORDS.
IF MONEY IS DEEMED TO BE THE
POWER BEHIND THIS INSTITUTION,
WELL THEN YOU MY DEAR ANNE, ARE
GOING TO COMPENSATE FOR EVERY
SINGLE PENNY THAT'S BEEN LOST.
BUT HOW?
SHALL I GIVE UP MY SALARY?
OH NO MY DEAR.
OH NO, NO, NO...
I AM GOING TO INSIST THAT THE
BOARD GIVE YOU A PROBATIONARY
TERM AT LEAST UNTIL CHRISTMAS.
IN THE MEANTIME MIGHT YOU
CONSIDER MOUNTING A LAVISH
BENEFIT CONCERT?
HIGHLIGHTING A PLAY PERHAPS
DIRECTED BY A MISS ANNE SHIRLEY...
IT WILL HAVE TO BE SOMETHING
WITH A NUMBER OF SUPERB ROLES
IN IT THOUGH.
AND STRONG DRAMATIC CONTENT.
THE AUDIENCE WILL HAVE TO
BE COMPLETELY OVERWHELMED.
I THINK EVERY PRINGLE PARENT
WOULD GLADLY PAY TO SEE THEIR
DAUGHTER'S NAMES IN THE
PROGRAM, DON'T YOU THINK!
LET'S SEE UH, 100 TICKETS
AT $25 A TICKET WHY THAT MAKES
EXACTLY $2500....
THAT'S AN OUTRAGEOUS PRICE!
DO YOU HONESTLY THINK
ANYONE WOULD PAY FOR THAT?
YES, AND ALL THE MONEY
WILL GO DIRECTLY TO THE SCHOOL.
YOU ARE PERFECTLY
INGENIOUS MISS STACEY.
WE'LL SHOW THE
PRINGLES THE MEANING
OF THE WORD "CAPITALISM".
JUST A MINUTE ANNE,
I THINK THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE
A LOOK AT THESE OLD DIARIES.
MRS. STANTON, OUR LIBRARIAN,
AND I ARE PREPARING A HISTORY
OF KINGSPORT AND WE
LITERALLY STUMBLED ACROSS
THOSE IN THE ARCHIVES.
THEY WERE WRITTEN BY
CAPTAIN ABRAHAM PRINGLE
THE FOUNDER OF KINGSPORT.
MY DEAR ANNE, IF YOU
WANT TO WIN THE GAME
YOU HAVE TO
UNDERSTAND THE PLAYERS.
I SEE.
"AND SO, FOR THE LAST TIME THE
OLD TEACHER PASSED BY THE CRUEL
PORTRAIT OF HERSELF ETCHED IN
THE WALL BY HER FORMER STUDENTS.
GERTRUDE GLIMPSED THE OLD
WOMAN'S HAUGHTY LONELINESS
AS SHE RETREATED
SILENTLY INTO THE GARDEN.
SHORTLY THEREAFTER THEY
LEARNED THAT THE HAND OF DEATH
HAD TOUCHED HER.
AND GERTRUDE WAS HAUNTED BY
THE REALIZATION THAT SHE COULD
NEVER THANK THE WOMAN WHO
HAD SILENTLY GIVEN HER SO MUCH.
IT WAS MORE THAN
SHE COULD BEAR".
AT THIS POINT IN THE TERM I
WOULD LIKE TO DEDICATE THIS
SHORT STORY TO EACH OF YOU
YOUNG LADIES WHO HAVE MADE
THE FIRST FEW WEEKS
HERE FOR ME SO MEANINGFUL.
CLASS DISMISSED.
WHAT ARE THESE GIRLS CRYING FOR?
I'VE BEEN READING THEM A
SHORT STORY, MISS BROOKE.
GOOD GRIEF - CRYING
OVER AN ENGLISH LESSON!
MISS BROOKE IS HERE TO
DISCUSS MY SUGGESTION OF A PLAY
AND BENEFIT CONCERT.
I THINK IT'S SCANDALOUS,
BUT MY OPINION MATTERS LITTLE
SINCE THE SCHOOL
NEEDS THE FUNDS.
EXACTLY.
I WAS HOPING YOU WOULD ASSIST
ME IN THE COACHING, MISS BROOKE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU WOULD.
SINCE I HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH DRAWING UP
THIS RIDICULOUS SCHEME!
THE MOST IMPORTANT QUESTION IS,
THEN, WHO SHALL PLAY THE LEADING
ROLE OF MARY QUEEN OF SCOTS?
I THINK - WE DON'T WANT
ANY GREEN HORN IN THE ROLE.
I'M NOT GOING TO BE
ASSOCIATED WITH ANYTHING
THAT ISN'T SUCCESSFUL.
JEN PRINGLE IS THE ONLY
ONE I CAN THINK OF WHO COULD
PLAY THE PART.
NO ONE ELSE HAS THE
NECESSARY PERSONALITY.
I CAN'T DENY THAT JEN HAS
A NATURAL FLAIR FOR ACTING.
THEN IT'S ALL SETTLED.
WHY, I THINK MISS BROOKE
WILL MAKE AN EXCELLENT COACH.
AND MISS MACKAY AND MISS
KERR CAN DO THE DECORATIONS
AND I'LL SEE TO THE HIRING
OF THE HALL AND THE BAND.
PERHAPS I CAN EVEN ENTICE A
FAMOUS SOPRANO FROM FREDERICTON
TO SING BETWEEN
ACTS AT NO CHARGE!
I TRUST SHE'LL
SING FOR THE CREDITORS
IF THE WHOLE THING FLOPS!
BUT, DON'T SAY
I DIDN'T WARN YOU!
MAKE YOUR BRUSH STROKE MOVE LIKE
FURIOUS FIRE.
LET THE FLAME SHOOT OUT FURIOUSLY!
MAKE GREAT BIG STITCHES
SO THEY WON'T SHOW.
I IMPLORE YOU!
DON'T JUST STAND
THERE LIKE LIMP RAGS...
HELP ME, HELP ME.
FEEL IT, FEEL IT!
LET GO THE QUEEN.
MYRA, YOU'RE USING
YOU UPSTAGE HAND.
YOU'RE HIDING YOUR FACE.
HELP ME MY MISTRESS, HAVE MERCY.
MERCY NAY I AM INNOCENT.
SAVE ME SWEET LADY.
WILL YE SLAY SAVE ME TOO?
DRAG HIM AWAY,
PLUCK HIS HANDS OFF HER.
THIS SCENE LOOKS RIDICULOUS.
I AM NOT GONNA LOWER
MYSELF ANY FURTHER.
HATTIE YOU'RE AS
STIFF AS A POKER!
I CAN'T HELP IT.
I DON'T WANT TO BRUISE MYSELF.
IF I CAN GO DOWN EASILY, I WILL.
YOU'VE ALL SEEN
ESSIE CARRYING ON.
NOW DO IT THIS WAY.
I AM INNOCENT,
SAVE ME SWEET LADY.
OH!
...NOW THE QUEEN SHE
ORDERS THE GUARDS TO HALT.
BUT THE GUARDS DRAG RIZZIO AWAY. DRAG ME.
NOW HATTIE, YOU TRY IT.
I AM INNOCENT, SAVE ME
SWEET LADY UH HUH, UH HUH.
I REFUSE TO PLAY OPPOSITE HER.
SHE IS THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN BE REMOTELY CONVINCING
AS AN ITALIAN MUSICIAN.
DO WHAT YOU CAN MISS BROOKE.
WELL, DON'T BLAME ME
IF THE AUDIENCE LEAVES.
ONCE MORE HATTIE,
AND PLEASE RELAX!
EMMELINE!
WHAT IS IT, WHAT IS IT?
WE'VE MISSED HAVING
YOU IN OUR PLAY.
OH, I'M SO SORRY ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED WITH YOUR FATHER.
ONCE EVERYTHING'S CALMED DOWN
I'M HOPING I CAN GET A CHANCE
TO SPEAK WITH HIM
AND TRY TO EXPLAIN.
HE ISN'T HERE.
HE'S GONE BACK TO BOSTON.
OH, MISS SHIRLEY, I'VE
ALWAYS WANTED TO DO A PLAY...
I'VE NEVER HAD MUCH OF
A CHANCE TO DO ANYTHING.
PAPA WILL NEVER LET ME
COME BACK TO THIS SCHOOL.
I AM TO SPEND THE REST OF THE
YEAR WITH GRANDMAMA, ALONE.
OH EMMELINE...
PERHAPS I CAN GET
ANOTHER COPY OF THE PLAY.
I'LL COACH YOU AT
HOME, IF YOU LIKE.
I'M SURE YOUR FATHER
WILL LET YOU COME BACK
TO COLLEGE NEXT TERM.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I DON'T THINK
GRANDMAMA WILL EITHER.
I HAD TO SNEAK OUT WHILE SHE
AND AUNT PAULINE WERE NAPPING.
IS SOMEONE HELPING YOU
ALONG WITH YOUR STUDIES?
YOU DON'T WANT TO FALL BEHIND.
WELL, THEN I SHALL HAVE TO
HAVE A CHAT WITH YOUR GRANDMAMA.
WILL YOU?
YOU SHOULD HURRY ALONG HOME.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GET HER CROSS.
AND I PROMISE
I WILL COME BY TOMORROW
AND I WILL SPEAK WITH HER.
OH, IT'S NUMBER 10 MAPPLE TERRACE
YOU WON'T FORGET...
OF COURSE NOT.
OFF YOU GO.
YES?
I SHOULD LIKE TO
SPEAK WITH MRS. HARRIS.
MY NAME IS - YOU CAN'T.
SHE IS ILL AND
WON'T BE DISTURBED.
GOOD DAY.
MAY I SPEAK WITH
EMMELINE HARRIS, THEN?
SHE ISN'T ALLOWED
TO HAVE VISITORS.
IS CAPTAIN HARRIS COMING
BACK TO - LIVES IN BOSTON MISS.
SELDOM VISITS HERE.
COULD YOU TELL EMMELINE THAT
ANNE SHIRLEY CAME TO SEE HER?
THANK YOU.
MY DEAR MRS. HARRIS: I THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT BE INTERESTED IN THESE
DIARIES BELONGING TO CAPTAIN
ABRAHAM PRINGLE, WHICH I FOUND
IN THE CITY ARCHIVES.
THERE ARE SOME WONDERFUL
TRIBUTES IN HERE BY CAPTAIN
PRINGLE TO YOUR LATE
HUSBAND, CAPTAIN HARRIS.
I HOPE YOU ENJOY READING
THEM AS MUCH AS I DID.
SINCERELY, ANNE SHIRLEY,
KINGSPORT LADIES COLLEGE.
I HAVE A DELIVERY
FOR MISS SHIRLEY.
WELL YOU'RE IN LUCK.
I AM MISS SHIRLEY.
THANK YOU.
SO THEN IT'S TOMORROW
AT NOON IS IT MRS. HARRIS...
MISS SHIRLEY MADAM.
MAMA.
MAMA...
GOOD GRIEF GIRL
YOU'RE AGGRAVATING!
MISS SHIRLEY.
WHAT?
MISS SHIRLEY!
SAINTS ALIVE, WHY DIDN'T
YOU SAY SO IN THE FIRST PLACE?
SO, THIS IS THE
INFAMOUS MISS SHIRLEY.
COME TO TAKE HER
POUND OF FLESH HAS SHE...
HOW DO YOU DO MRS. HARRIS?
FAR FROM WELL.
HOW MUCH DO YOU WANT
FOR THESE DIARIES?
I HADN'T ANY
INTENTION OF SELLING THEM.
IS THERE ANY USE IN
ASKING YOU TO SIT DOWN?
YES...
THANK YOU.
WHO ELSE HAS SEEN THESE THINGS?
NO ONE AS FAR AS I KNOW.
THEN I'M READY TO NEGOTIATE.
I WILL GIVE YOU WHAT YOU WANT
IF YOU GIVE ME YOUR WORD NOT
TO REVEAL THIS MONSTROSITY
TO THE REST OF THE PRINGLES.
I WAS ONLY HOPING I MIGHT
CONVINCE YOU TO LET ME TUTOR
YOUR GRANDDAUGHTER
EMMELINE AS I UNDERSTAND
THAT SHE WILL NOT
BE RETURNING TO SCHOOL.
OH CLEVER AREN'T WE?
SUGARCOATED BLACKMAIL!
YOU WANT A REGULAR SALARY
TO KEEP YOU QUIET, IS THAT IT?
BEG YOUR PARDON?
INNOCENT AS DOVES,
CUNNING AS SERPENTS.
YOU KNEW WHEN YOU
FOUND THAT SCANDALOUS ENTRY
ABOUT MY HUSBAND IT WASN'T TRUE.
IT COULDN'T BE TRUE!
THE REST OF THE
PRINGLES WILL BE DEE-LIGHTED
TO BELIEVE IT WON'T THEY?
AND MAKE US THE
LAUGHING STOCK OF KINGSPORT!
WHICH SCANDALOUS ENTRY?
OH, SO THERE'S MORE
THAN ONE, IS THERE?
PAULINE.
JOSIAH HARRIS' SHIP WAS
BURNED AND THEIR BOATS TAKEN.
HARRIS AND THE CREW
NEARLY STARVED.
IN THE END THEY ATE...THEY ATE JONAS
SELKIRK WHO HAD SHOT HIMSELF
THEY LIVED ON HIM UNTIL RESCUED.
HARRIS TOLD ME HIMSELF.
SEEMED TO THINK
IT WAS A GOOD JOKE.
ON OCCASION PAPA WOULD
GET SO ANGRY...
PAULINE!
BE QUIET!
THAT IS A LIE.
MY HUSBAND NEVER ATE
ANYONE DEAD OR ALIVE.
LET ALONE JONAS SELKIRK.
ABRAHAM PRINGLE
WROTE THAT NONSENSE
TO GET A RISE OUT
OF HIS SILLY WIFE.
AMY PRINGLE WAS
NOTORIOUSLY GULLIBLE.
OH, PLEASE MISS SHIRLEY,
DON'T SHOW THESE TO ANYONE.
OUR PRINGLE RELATIONS
MIGHT PUBLICIZE IT.
WE'LL DO ANYTHING!
OW.
NOW MISS SHIRLEY.
HOW MUCH DO YOU WANT TO
'TUTOR' MY GRANDDAUGHTER?
OH YOU'VE MISUNDERSTOOD
ME COMPLETELY.
I'M NOT THREATENING YOU!
I JUST THOUGHT YOU'D ENJOY
ALL THE OTHER SPLENDID THINGS
SAID ABOUT YOUR HUSBAND.
I NEVER DREAMED OF TELLING
ANYONE HE WAS A CANNIBAL.
WELL NATURALLY WE TEND TO BE A
LITTLE SUSPICIOUS OF STRANGERS
IN KINGSPORT, PERHAPS
WE HAVE MISJUDGED YOU.
I SUPPOSE THE CHILD SHOULD
CONTINUE WITH HER STUDIES.
PAULINE HAS NO TIME.
SHE'S BUSY LOOKING AFTER ME.
YOU WON'T MENTION
THIS MISUNDERSTANDING
TO ANYONE WILL YOU?
I'LL TRY TO REMEMBER NOT TO...
AND WHEN DO YOU WANT TO START?
IMMEDIATELY.
HMM.
IF TWO ANGLES IN A TRIANGLE ARE
EQUAL TO EACH OTHER
THE SIDES OPPOSITE THESE TWO
ANGLES ARE EQUAL TO EACH OTHER.
EMMELINE, WHY HASN'T ANYONE
REPLACED YOUR SPECTACLES?
WELL, PAPA SAYS I DON'T
REALLY NEED TO WEAR THEM
AS MUCH AS I DO.
AND GRANDMAMA WON'T BECAUSE
SHE'S AN OLD SKIN-FLINT!
WHO GAVE YOU THOSE, THEN?
MOTHER'S SUPERIOR AT THE CONVENT
IN BOSTON TWO YEARS AGO.
ANYWAY, I'M ONLY SUPPOSED
TO USE THEM FOR READING.
YOU SIMPLY CANNOT
USE THEM ANYMORE.
YOU MUST HAVE ANOTHER PAIR!
I FOUND ANOTHER COPY
- MARY QUEEN OF SCOTS!
OH, HER VERY NAME JUST
THRILLS ME TO MY FINGERTIPS!
I DON'T BELIEVE SHE REALLY
MURDERED DARNLEY, DO YOU?
SHH!
HEAVEN HELP YOU TWO
IF YOU WAKE HER UP!
I THINK IT'S EVER SO
DRAMATIC, DON'T YOU?
IT'S A VERY CHALLENGING ROLE.
WE USED TO HAVE DRAMATICS
AND MUSIC AT THE CONVENT.
MOTHER SUPERIOR SAID I
WAS QUITE GOOD AT BOTH.
SHE TAUGHT ME TO PLAY
THE PIANO TOO, YOU KNOW.
UNFORTUNATELY, GRANDMAMA
WON'T LET ME TOUCH IT.
C-COULD WE READ IT TOGETHER?
I THINK SO.
I'LL PLAY ALL OF THE OTHER
PARTS AND YOU READ MARY.
LET'S START HERE.
"FORGIVE ALL EVIL
TOWARD ME OF ALL MEN,
DEED OR DEVICE TO HURT ME. "
YEA, I WOULD NOT BEAR ONE
HEART UNRECONCILED WITH MINE
WHEN MINE IS COLD.
I WILL NOT TAKE DEATH'S HAND
WITH ANY SOIL OF HATE OR WRATH
OR WRONG ABOUT ME BUT BEING
FRIENDS WITH THIS PAST WORLD
PASS FROM IT IN THE
GENERAL PEACE OF LOVE.
THAT WAS WONDERFUL!
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING
ME HERE, MISS SHIRLEY.
THIS WILL BE OUR
SECRET PLACE,
CANNOT REVEAL TO ANYONE.
GRANDMAMA NEVER
LETS ME OUT ALONE.
SHE THINKS I'M LIABLE TO
BE "KIDNAPPED BY GYPSIES".
I DON'T KNOW WHY SHE'D
CARE IF I WAS KIDNAPPED.
ALL SHE WORRIES ABOUT IS HER
ACHING BACK AND HER SORE FEET.
NOW, NOW.
OLD PEOPLE CLING TO THE WAY
THEY WERE BROUGHT UP THEMSELVES.
SECRETLY SHE HATES ME.
SHE ALWAYS CALLS ME "THE CHILD"
AS THOUGH I MAY BE
"THE DOG" OR "THE CAT".
IF I MAKE A SPARK OF
NOISE SHE NEARLY PASSES OUT.
SHE'S AN OLD TYRANT AND SOMEDAY
I'M GOING TO RUN AWAY FOREVER
AND BECOME A REAL ACTRESS.
WHY HAVE YOU NEVER
LIVED WITH YOUR FATHER?
HE'S VERY OCCUPIED WITH
HIS BUSINESS AFFAIRS.
I WAS AT TWO OTHER BOARDING
SCHOOLS BEFORE I CAME TO THIS ONE,
BUT HE BROUGHT ME HERE...SO
I'D BE CLOSE TO GRANDMAMA.
AND SO HE WOULDN'T
HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT ME.
I'M SURE HE MEANS
TO DO WHAT'S BEST.
WHAT JEN PRINGLE SAID ABOUT PAPA
HURT YOU KNOW...
BECAUSE IT'S TRUE.
"DEAR PAPA. I WANT
SO MUCH TO RETURN TO KLC.
NO - I WOULD LIKE TO
ASK YOU TO ALLOW ME TO GO BACK
TO KLC NEXT TERM.
I WAS AT THE TOP OF
CLASS BEFORE I LEFT.
I'D HOPED YOU'D BE
PROUD OF MY GRADES.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND
IT WAS ALL A MISTAKE.
I TRIED TO REACH YOU IN
BALTIMORE, BUT I SUPPOSE
YOU NEVER RECEIVED THE LETTER. "
MISS SHIRLEY IS HERE FOR
YOUR TUTORIAL, MISS.
THANK YOU.
MISS SHIRLEY!
GRANDMAMA WILL EAT YOU ALIVE.
IF WE ARE TO HAVE
OUR STUDIES IN THIS ROOM,
I SIMPLY CANNOT TOLERATE
THE GLOOMINESS ANY LONGER.
I HAVE A WONDERFUL
SURPRISE FOR YOU.
MISS STACEY HAS LENT ME A
ROYAL CONSERVATORY PROGRAMME,
AND YOU CAN BEGIN TODAY!
I CAN'T.
GRANDMAMA HAS
FORBIDDEN ME TO TOUCH...
FIDDLESTICKS!
IT'S HIGH TIME SOMEONE
REMINDED YOUR GRANDMAMA
WHAT A PIANO SOUNDS LIKE...
AND IT SHOULDN'T BE ME.
YOU CAN START WITH
THESE ELEMENTARY EXERCISES
AS A REFRESHER COURSE.
YOU WILL BE ON YOUR
OWN THOUGH,
BUT IT'S A STEP IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
I'LL GET YOUR TEXTBOOKS.
PLAY!
PAULINE, COME HERE GIRL!
WE WILL ANSWER AND WE WILL
TELL THEM WE CANNOT ACCEPT.
MAMA WANTS HER
STATIONARY ABIGAIL.
WHO ON EARTH IS MAKING
THAT CONFOUNDED RACKET?
THAT PIANO ISN'T
MEANT TO BE PLAYED!
GET AWAY FROM THERE, CHILD!
WHO GAVE YOU PERMISSION
TO PLAY THAT PIANO?
I'M SORRY MRS. HARRIS, BUT
EMMELINE MUST BE ALLOWED
TO DEVOTE SOME TIME
TO MUSICAL STUDIES.
I DON'T BELIEVE IN YOUNG GIRLS
PLAYING THE PIANO IN PUBLIC.
IT TENDS TO MAKE
THEM BOLD AND FORWARD.
WHY, I THINK PERHAPS
YOU ARE WISE MRS. HARRIS.
HOWEVER, I'M TOLD THAT MOST
OF THE YOUNG PRINGLE GIRLS IN
KINGSPORT HAVE PRIVATE LESSONS.
OH?
YOU JUST WOULDN'T WANT TO
BE ACCUSED OF NEGLIGENCE IN
EMMELINE'S PROPER UPBRINGING?
NO.
WHO GAVE YOU PERMISSION
TO OPEN THOSE WINDOWS?
I JUST WANTED YOUR STAFF TO
SEE HOW DUSTY THIS ROOM IS.
IT NEEDS A THOROUGH GOING OVER.
WELL, HAVE IT YOUR WAY.
YOU YOUNG PEOPLE
ARE ALL SO GIDDY!
PAULINE WANTS TO GO
AWAY AND LEAVE ME.
IT'S ONLY FOR THE DAY MAMA.
ONLY FOR A DAY SAYS SHE!
IT DOESN'T SEEM TO OCCUR TO
ANYONE THAT I'D LIKE A DAY OUT
OF THIS CONFOUNDED WHEELCHAIR.
YOU MAY NOT HAVE THE
USE OF YOUR LEGS GRANDMAMA,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING THE
MATTER WITH YOUR TONGUE.
DON'T YOU DARE TO
BE IMPERTINENT, CHILD.
I KNOW A GIRL WHO DIED IN HER
SLEEP AFTER BEING IMPERTINENT.
PAULINE, WHAT IS IT?
UH, MY COUSIN LOUISA IS
CELEBRATING HER WEDDING
ANNIVERSARY IN FREDERICTON NEXT
WEEK, AND I WAS HER BRIDESMAID
FIFTEEN YEARS AGO, AND I'D
DO ANYTHING TO BE THERE.
WELL, IF I DIE ALONE,
WHILE YOU'RE AWAY, PAULINE,
I LEAVE IT TO YOUR CONSCIENCE.
I KNOW WHAT A BURDEN I CAN BE.
MAMA PLEASE DON'T
EXCITE YOURSELF.
I'M NOT GOING TO GO
IF YOU'RE NOT WILLING.
I WILL EXCITE MYSELF.
CAN'T I HAVE A LITTLE EXCITEMENT
TO BRIGHTEN MY DULL LIFE...
OH, OH MY BACK, MY BACK IT
HURTS...
CLOSE THAT CONFOUNDED
WINDOW, GIRL!
I FEEL THE DRAFT, PAULINE
GET MY AFGHAN
AND A CUSHION FOR MY FEET.
WELL, YOU KNOW HOW PEOPLE WILL
TALK MRS. HARRIS IF PAULINE
DOESN'T GO TO THE ANNIVERSARY?
WHAT?
OH, I'M SURE IN YOUR LONG
LIFETIME YOU'VE LEARNED
WHAT IDLE TONGUES CAN SAY.
WELL THERE'S NO NEED TO THROW
MY AGE UP IN MY FACE, GIRL.
OH, THIS TOWN IS
FULL OF TATTERING TOADIES
AND DON'T I KNOW IT!
I'M NOT STOPPING HER.
I LEFT IT TO HER OWN CONSCIENCE.
NO ONE WILL EVER
BELIEVE THAT EXCUSE.
MISS SHIRLEY AND I CAN EVEN
STAY WITH YOU, GRANDMAMA.
WHY, PAULINE COULD PROBABLY
BE THERE AND BACK IN A DAY!
THERE'S SOMETHING BEHIND
ALL THIS ISN'T THERE?
WHY ARE YOU ALL
SO SET ON HER GOING?
BECAUSE SHE'S A GOOD KIND
DAUGHTER WHO NEEDS A DAY OFF
NOW AND THEN.
NEVER MIND YOUR WHEEDLING WAYS.
HAVE A PEPPERMINT.
OH...OH MY HEAD.
OH I'VE GOT SUCH A PAIN
IN MY HEAD AND I'M SO TIRED
I CAN'T ARGUE ANYMORE.
I SUPPOSE THAT MEANS I
AM GOING TO HAVE A STROKE.
OH.
ALRIGHT YOU CAN GO.
BUT IF YOU CATCH FLU AND
GET SICK DON'T BLAME ME.
OH THANK YOU MAMA, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE SO GOOD TO ME!
I WANTED TO GO TO
COUSIN LOUISA'S SO MUCH.
MAMA...I ONLY HAVE THIS
OLD BLACK TAFFETA TO WEAR.
DO YOU THINK...
BLACK TAFFETA
IS QUITE GOOD ENOUGH
FOR LOUISA HILTON'S WEDDING.
SHE'D GO DRESSED IN SCARLET
THAT ONE IF I LET HER...
AND ONLY WAITING TILL
I'M DEAD TO DO IT.
AS LONG AS I'M ALIVE YOU
WILL BE DECENT PAULINE HARRIS.
ALRIGHT MAMA.
I'M JUST GOING TO BE
GLAD INSIDE AND
NOT EVEN THINK ABOUT
WHAT I'M WEARING.
AND I'M SURE
YOU'LL GET ALONG
WITH MISS SHIRLEY
SPLENDIDLY MAMA!
I WILL NOT TAKE DEATH'S HAND
WITH ANY SOIL OF HATE OR WRATH
OR WRONG ABOUT ME, BUT BEING
FRIENDS WITH THIS PAST WORLD,
PASS FROM IT IN THE
GENERAL PIECE OF LOVE...
WELL YOU'VE ALL
DONE REMARKABLY WELL
AND DESERVE
MULTITUDES OF PRAISE.
NOW MAKE SURE YOU
HAVE YOUR LINES DOWN PAT
FOR NEXT FRIDAY'S REHEARSAL.
UH AND BEFORE YOU GO I
HAVE ONE ANNOUNCEMENT TO MAKE.
MRS. CAPTAIN JOSIAH HARRIS
AND HER GRANDDAUGHTER EMMELINE,
WOULD BE PLEASED
TO INVITE YOU LADIES
TO A FALL PICNIC
TOMORROW MORNING.
NOW IF YOU CARE TO
ATTEND WE WILL BE MEETING
AT MAPLEHURST AT 10:00AM.
OH, PLEASE BRING A SMALL GIFT FOR
MRS. HARRIS OUT OF POLITENESS
FOR HER GENEROSITY
IN HOSTING THIS EVENT.
YOU CAN GO HOME NOW GIRLS.
IT'S COMING.
IT'S COMING...
THEY LOOK WONDERFUL.
QUITE A REACTION FROM
THOSE OLD DIARIES, ANNE.
GOES TO SHOW YOU HOW MY OLD
STUDENTS ALWAYS PULL THROUGH.
DON'T SPEAK TOO LOUDLY YET!
I JUST RECEIVED A LETTER
FROM GILBERT BLYTHE.
SEEMS HE'S FINALLY
IN MEDICAL SCHOOL.
I KNOW.
WELL, HOW'S HE DOING?
WELL, YOU KNOW GILBERT'S SO
MODEST, BUT A - READING BETWEEN
THE LINES I'D SAY HE'S
AT THE TOP OF HIS CLASS.
HE WANTED TO KNOW HOW
YOU'RE DOING AS WELL.
WELL, YOU MAY TELL HIM
I'M KEEPING OUT OF MISCHIEF.
COME IN.
IT'S ONLY ME, PAULINE.
OH, MISS SHIRLEY, HOW DO I LOOK?
DREADFUL.
YOU SIMPLY CANNOT
GO IN THAT OLD THING.
I AM GONNA LEND
YOU MY BEST DRESS.
OH MY DEAR, NO, NO, NO...
I'M ON TENTERHOOKS AS IT IS.
MAMA MIGHT CHANGE HER MIND.
OH, DON'T BE SILLY.
GET UP.
TAKE THIS BLACK TAFFETA OFF...
YOU CAN PUT THIS ON UNDERNEATH
AND CAN CHANGE AT THE PARTY.
BUT TO DECEIVE MAMA I...
YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO BRING BAD
LUCK TO A WEDDING ANNIVERSARY
IN THIS BLACK THING WOULD YOU?
NO.
HMM.
OH! OH!
OH, NOW JUST A WHIFF!
MAMA WON'T APPROVE OF THIS.
OH, APPLE BLOSSOM!
OH HOW THIS REMINDS ME OF
ADELAIDE PRINGLE WHEN SHE...
WHO?
MORGAN'S WIFE.
THE MOTHER OF THE CHILD.
SHE WAS MY FIRST
COUSIN ON MAMA'S SIDE.
I SEE.
PAULINE WHY DOES YOUR
BROTHER NEVER VISIT?
OH, MORGAN, HE'S
BECOME JUST LIKE PAPA.
ALWAYS ORDERING PEOPLE ABOUT.
NO TIME FOR ANYONE ELSE.
MORGAN USED TO BE SO ROBUST
AND HANDSOME AND ADELAIDE USED
TO LOVE MUSIC AND PARTIES.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WELL, IT'S NOT
CHRISTIAN TO SPEAK OF THE DEAD.
WELL, HOW DID SHE DIE THEN?
SHE...RAN OFF SHORTLY
AFTER THE CHILD WAS BORN.
AND DIED OF CONSUMPTION.
THE PRINGLES ALL BLAMED
MORGAN, INCLUDING MAMA.
BUT IT WASN'T MORGAN'S FAULT.
NOW MAMA WON'T HAVE
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT REMINDS HER
OF WHAT HAPPENED TO ADELAIDE.
THAT'S WRONG PAULINE.
WHAT MAKES THE PEOPLE
IN THIS TOWN HOLD SUCH GRUDGES
AGAINST ONE ANOTHER?
OH THE PRINGLES
HAVE ALWAYS BICKERED
A GREAT DEAL AMONGST THEMSELVES.
WE'RE VERY POLITE TO EACH
OTHER IN PUBLIC, THOUGH.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN SUCH
RIDICULOUS BEHAVIOUR.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY BYZANTINE!
WELL, IN ANY CASE
PAULINE HARRIS,
YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE
THE 'DAY OFF' OF YOUR LIFE.
GOOD MORNING, MRS. HARRIS.
WALKING AS IF WE
OWNED THE WORLD ARE WE?
SO I DO.
COME ALONG PAULINE!
I...I'M READY TO GO MAMA.
TOO MUCH COLOUR GIRL.
YOU LOOK PAINTED.
OH NO.
IT'S JUST I'M FLUSHED.
WELL YOU DON'T SMELL
RESPECTABLE DRENCHED IN SCENT.
IT'S JUST THE
TINIEST...LITTLE...BIT OF IT.
I SAID DRENCHED
AND I MEANT DRENCHED.
TURN AROUND.
IS THAT A RIP UNDER THAT SLEEVE?
UH....
NO.
OH, REMEMBER YOUR MANNERS
AND DON'T FORGET TO CROSS YOUR
ANKLES DECENTLY
WHEN YOU SIT DOWN.
AND DON'T SIT IN A DRAFT EITHER.
AND DON'T SLIDE
DOWN THE BANISTERS.
MAMA!
WELL YOU DID AT
NANCY PRINGLE'S WEDDING.
MAMA, THAT WAS 25 YEARS AGO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK I AM?
GO ON GIRL.
DON'T STAND THERE JABBERING.
DO YOU WANT TO MISS YOUR TRAIN?
NO, MAMA.
AND IF I'M NOT HERE WHEN
YOU COME BACK, REMEMBER,
LAY ME OUT IN MY WEDDING DRESS.
AND MIND MY HAIR IS CRIMPED!
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU'LL
MANAGE HER MISS SHIRLEY.
SHE'S SUCH A BABY.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D EVER GET
A CHANCE TO VISIT MAPLEHURST.
ETTIE, ETTIE PRINGLE
GET AWAY FROM THERE,
THAT'S MRS. HARRIS' CARRIAGE.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS.
I HAVEN'T BEEN OUTSIDE...
IF I CATCH COLD GIRL, I
SHALL HOLD YOU RESPONSIBLE.
NONSENSE!
I WANT YOU TO ENJOY THE SUNSHINE
AND ALL THE
BEAUTIFUL AUTUMN COLOURS.
WE'LL HAVE A LOVELY CARRIAGE
RIDE AND YOU CAN CRITICIZE
EVERYONE WE PASS BY!
CRITICIZE?
THAT'S A VERY STRANGE
IDEA MISS SHIRLEY.
THAT'S NOT CHRISTIAN.
IT'S SIMPLY NOT CHRISTIAN.
WHAT IS THE MEANING OF THIS!
MISS SHIRLEY, I WON'T STAND FOR
ANYMORE OF YOUR MONKEYSHINES!
YOU HAVE SUCH HANDSOME
CARRIAGES AND NEVER USE THEM.
YOU PUT THEM BACK DO YOU HEAR!
THEY'VE NOT BEEN
OUT FOR SEVEN YEARS!
ALL THE MORE REASON TO
BRING THEM OUT AND USE THEM.
STOP BEING SO SELFISH.
GOOD MORNING GIRLS.
YOU LOOK LOVELY!
YOU WHEEL ME BACK IN!
DO YOU HEAR?
THIS IS ANARCHY!
WHO ARE THESE RABBLE-ROUSERS?
OH DEAR SAINTS
ABOVE I SHALL SWOON.
I CAN'T STAND ALL
THIS FRESH AIR.
IT'S SUCH A PRETTY DAY,
I THOUGHT YOU COULD HOST
A PICNIC FOR THE SCHOOL.
I DON'T EAT MY LUNCH
OUTSIDE WITH ANYONE GIRL.
I'M NOT A RAGGLE-TAGGLE GYPSY.
TAKE ME IN! TAKE ME IN!
HUSH NOW, MRS. HARRIS; SOME OF
THESE YOUNG GIRLS ARE PRINGLES.
PRINGLES?
YES.
AND YOU DON'T WANT THEM
RUNNING HOME AND TELLING TALES.
YOU'LL PAY FOR THIS.
IF I CATCH A CHILL...
YOU SAID YOU WANTED
A DAY OFF FROM YOUR
WHEELCHAIR ANYWAY GRANDMAMA.
BE QUIET!
GOOD MORNING MRS. HARRIS.
YOU LOOK AWFULLY CHIPPER.
THANK YOU ALEC MCGUINNESS.
THANK YOU.
WELL, WHAT DOES IT
MATTER IF I DIE ANYWAY?
I'VE BEEN LIVING ON BORROWED
TIME FOR TOO LONG AS IT IS.
SUCH FRIENDLY PEOPLE!
CHARMING NEIGHBOURS.
YOU KNOW I DON'T APPROVE OF
YOUR CRITICIZING PEOPLE MY DEAR.
NOW...MAY I ASK IS THAT
ALL YOUR OWN HAIR.
YES.
EVERY BIT.
WELL PITY IT'S RED.
BUT I BELIEVE RED IS
BECOMING QUITE POPULAR AGAIN.
THANK YOU.
AND ANOTHER ONE?
OH! HOW DELIGHTFUL!
NOW, THANK YOU MY DEAR.
THIS IS MY GIFT
TO YOU, EMMELINE.
OH, MISS SHIRLEY!
HOWEVER DID YOU PAY FOR THIS?
I HAD SOME LUCKY
SAVINGS PUT ASIDE.
OH!
THANK YOU A MILLION TIMES OVER!
SOME DAY I'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU!
NOW WASN'T THAT SWEET OF ALL
THESE GIRLS TO GIVE ME GIFTS?
YES, IT WAS.
YES, I RATHER LIKE YOUR
LAUGH MISS SHIRLEY.
THAT NERVOUS GIGGLE OF
PAULINE'S IT GETS ON MY NERVES.
WELL, I HOPE SHE HAS A
WONDERFUL TIME AT THE PARTY.
SHE'S PROBABLY OVER
EATEN AND MADE HERSELF ILL.
LIKE HER FATHER, THAT GIRL.
COURSE, HE NEVER KNEW
WHEN HE'D HAD ENOUGH.
DID I EVER SHOW YOU
JOSIAH'S PICTURE, MISS SHIRLEY?
MY HE WAS VERY HANDSOME.
FULL OF HEROIC SPIRIT, I'D SAY.
YES, HE WAS THE HANDSOMEST
MAN IN KINGSPORT.
AND HE ADORED ME.
WE CONSULTED EACH OTHER
ABOUT ABSOLUTELY EVERYTHING.
MIND YOU, WE DIDN'T
ALWAYS AGREE - NO.
HE HAD HIS FITS OF TEMPER.
OH YES, AND SO DID I.
YOU KNOW WHAT HE DID WHEN I
BOUGHT A DAY-CAP HE DIDN'T LIKE?
I CAN'T IMAGINE...
HE ATE IT!
GAVE HIM A TERRIBLE
STOMACH PAIN!
YES, SERVED HIM RIGHT.
HE WAS SO IRKED THAT I HAD
NEGLECTED TO CONSULT HIM!
HOW COULD HE GO AWAY AND LEAVE
ME ALONE AND CRIPPLED LIKE THIS?
DYING WAS THE ONLY THING HE EVER
DARED DO WITHOUT CONSULTING ME.
WELL, IT WON'T BE LONG
BEFORE WE'RE TOGETHER AGAIN.
THERE'S NO ONE...NO
MAN...LIKE HIM...NOWHERE...NO
THIS IS A DEGENERATE
AGE, MISS SHIRLEY.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR SON?
MORGAN.
WELL HE MANAGED
HIS MONEY SUCCESSFULLY
IF THAT'S ANY MERIT.
HIS FATHER SPOILED HIM.
NO, HE SHOULD NEVER
HAVE MARRIED HIS COUSIN.
IT WAS A BLESSING THAT POOR
ADELAIDE PRINGLE DIED DEAR SOUL;
MORGAN GOT WHAT HE
DESERVED I SUPPOSE.
THAT'S A VERY INHUMAN ATTITUDE
FOR A MOTHER, MRS. HARRIS.
YES, WELL WE'RE NOT
EXACTLY FAMOUS FOR COMPASSION
MISS SHIRLEY, ESPECIALLY
AMONG OURSELVES YOU KNOW?
ANYWAY THEY'RE ALL
WAITING FOR ME TO DIE
SO THEY CAN GET
THEIR HANDS ON THE MONEY.
PERHAPS YOU
OUGHT TO REALIZE
THAT EMMELINE ONLY
WANTS TO BE CARED FOR.
WELL.
IF YOU HAVE ANY
COMPASSION LEFT IN YOUR SOUL,
YOU MIGHT SPEND IT ON HER.
CHILDREN SHOULD BE
SEEN AND NOT HEARD.
YOU SEEM TO BE VERY BROAD-MINDED
IN YOUR OPINIONS MISS SHIRLEY.
THAT'S THE NICEST
COMPLIMENT ANYONE'S
EVER PAID ME MRS. HARRIS.
PARDON ME YOUNG MAN, I WAS
WONDERING IF YOU WOULD ALLOW MY
GIRLS AND ME THE PLEASURE OF A
HAYRIDE TO TOWN IN YOUR WAGON.
IT WOULD BE SO EXCITING,
BUT I PROMISE YOU
THEY WON'T BE ANY TROUBLE
MAMA, MAMA!
YOU'LL SIMPLY HAVE TO GO.
GOOD-BYE.
MAMA, MAMA.
MAMA!
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
MAMA ARE YOU ALRIGHT?
YOU'RE WEARING A HAT.
MAMA I CAN'T REMEMBER THE
LAST TIME SAW YOU OUT.
PAULINE WILL YOU CALM YOURSELF.
YOU SOUND HYSTERICAL.
YOU'VE SEEN ME WEAR A
HAT OFTEN ENOUGH GIRL.
MISS SHIRLEY
SUGGESTED AN AL FRESCO LUNCH
IT WAS MOST ENJOYABLE.
I'VE BEEN SO
ANXIOUS ABOUT YOU MAMA.
I WAS WORRIED
SICK THE ENTIRE PARTY.
WILL YOU STOP FLUTTERING GIRL!
YOU FIDGET ME.
PAULINE, DID YOU HAVE A GOOD
TIME AT YOUR WEDDING PARTY?
OH MY YES.
OH, LOUISE SENT
YOU HER BOUQUET MAMA.
THE FLOWERS WERE WONDERFUL.
THE PARLOUR WAS A BOWER...
LIKE A FUNERAL I SUPPOSE...
AND THE MINISTER MARRIED COUSIN
LOUISE AND MAURICE OVER AGAIN.
SACRILEGIOUS...
MOLLY AND EMILY
SEND THEIR LOVE AND...
OH AND EMILY HAS
THE MOST DELICIOUS BABY.
YOU SPEAK AS THOUGH
IT WAS SOMETHING TO EAT.
BABIES ARE COMMON ENOUGH.
BABIES ARE NEVER COMMON.
EACH ONE IS A MIRACLE.
WELL I HAD TWO OF THEM.
I DIDN'T SEE MUCH THAT WAS
MIRACULOUS ABOUT EITHER OF THEM.
MAMA YOU'RE SO BRIGHT
AND CHEERFUL TODAY.
HOWEVER DID YOU TWO
GET ALONG MISS SHIRLEY?
I LET HER HAVE HER HEAD
AND WE GOT ON WELL ENOUGH.
I DON'T CARE WHAT
THE PRINGLES SAY...
I THINK YOU'RE
QUITE GOOD LOOKING.
THANK YOU.
OH GOOD GRIEF!
WELL, WELL.
LITTLE BO PEEP HAS
LOST HER SHEEP AND DOESN'T
KNOW WHERE TO FIND THEM.
GOOD DAY MISS KERR.
AFTER THIS I SHALL BE
SURPRISED AT NOTHING.
LEAVE THEM ALONE AND
THEY'LL COME HOME BRINGING
THEIR TAILS BEHIND THEM.
GET THOSE SHEEP AND
THAT WAGON OUT OF HERE!
PAPA!
EMMELINE YOU WERE TOLD TO
STOP WEARING THOSE RIDICULOUS
SPECTACLES OUTSIDE.
YOUR EYESIGHT WILL NEVER IMPROVE
IF YOU CONSTANTLY WEAR THEM.
YES PAPA.
BUT MISS SHIRLEY GAVE
ME THESE NEW ONES AND...
GO INSIDE.
I MEAN IMMEDIATELY.
BUT...
HURRY UP.
YOUNG MAN WHOSE FAULT IS THIS?
IS THIS YOUR WAGON?
OH, THANK YOU.
WE HAD A MARVELLOUS TIME.
MISS SHIRLEY...
MAY I HAVE A WORD WITH YOU?
YOU RUN ALONG, MISS KERR.
I'LL CATCH UP.
YES, SIR.
IT SEEMS THAT EACH TIME WE MEET
CATASTROPHE LIES IN MY WAY.
WELL THEN PERHAPS YOU OUGHT
TO GET OUT OF THE WAY.
I GET ANNOYED WHEN PEOPLE
TREAT MY INSTRUCTIONS LIGHTLY,
MISS SHIRLEY.
I GAVE EXPLICIT ORDER THAT MY
DAUGHTER WAS TO HAVE NO FURTHER
ASSOCIATION WITH
KINGSPORT LADIES COLLEGE.
WOULD YOU MIND TELLING ME WHAT
THE DEVIL YOU'RE DOING HERE?
WE'VE BEEN ON A
COUNTRY PICNIC, SIR.
HOSTED BY YOUR MOTHER.
MY MOTHER?
SHE AUTHORIZED TAKING
OUT ALL OF THOSE CARRIAGES
AND INVITING ALL THOSE GIRLS?
...NO SIR.
I DID.
AND AS SHE HAD NOTHING BETTER
TO THINK ABOUT THAN HERSELF,
I FELT IT WAS HIGH TIME
SOMEONE TRIED TO HELP HER.
THEN YOU REALLY ARE AS INSANE AS
ALL THE RUMOURS
I'VE HEARD ABOUT YOU.
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD?
YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO KNOW.
YES I WOULD!
THE PRINGLES HAVE LABELED YOU
THE MADCAP ENGLISH PROFESSOR.
SOMEONE SAID YOU HAD WRITTEN THE
MOST RIDICULOUS STORY THEY HAD
EVER READ PUBLISHED
BY...UH...SOMETHING OR OTHER
RELIABLE BAKING POWDER COMPANY?
AND THAT YOU WERE
THE SILLIEST, REDHEADED,
MOUSE OF A SCHOOLMISTRESS
THEY'D EVER KNOWN.
THANKS TO YOU, I WAS
VERY NEARLY FIRED!
THERE'S A LOGICAL EXPLANATION
BEHIND EVERYTHING,
BUT YOU PEOPLE REALLY ARE THE MOST
NARROW-MINDED, SELF-CENTRED,
QUARRELSOME GROUP I
HAVE EVER ENCOUNTERED!
I'D LIKE TO POISON
YOUR ENTIRE CLAN!
YOU CAN'T STAND TO SEE ANYONE
SUCCEED OTHER THAN YOURSELVES.
OH, I'M SURE YOU'RE ALL GLOATING
OVER WHO WILL FLY THE VICTORY
BANNER AT THE END OF THIS YEAR!
WELL, YOU HAVE NOT
GOT THE BETTER OF ME YET!
WHOA, WHOA.
COME BACK HERE, MISS.
YOU'RE UPSET BY WHAT
THE PRINGLES THINK OF YOU?
I DON'T CARE TO DISCUSS
IT, IF YOU DON'T MIND.
I'M SORRY.
YOU'RE AFRAID THE PRINGLE
RUMOURS MIGHT REINFORCE
MY CONCLUSIONS ABOUT YOU...
YOUR CONCLUSIONS?
DON'T FLATTER YOURSELF!
YOU MIGHT BE INTERESTED IN
LISTENING TO WHAT I ACTUALLY
HAD TO SAY IN YOUR DEFENCE!
YOU OUGHT TO LOOK AROUND
AND SEE IF THERE'S ANYONE
YOU WOULD LIKE TO LISTEN
TO BETTER THAN YOURSELF!
I TOOK IT UPON MYSELF TO SEE
THAT THIS WAS DELIVERED TO YOU.
I'M SURE YOU'RE FAR TOO BUSY
TO FORWARD A CHANGE OF ADDRESS
TO YOUR DAUGHTER.
IF YOU WEREN'T SO SELF-ABSORBED,
SIR, YOU'D REALIZE THERE'S
A LITTLE GIRL WHO
DESPERATELY LOVES YOU.
YOU CAN GO.
MORGAN!
OH, MISS SHIRLEY!
WAIT!
MORGAN, I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
MISS SHIRLEY!
OH, MISS SHIRLEY, THANK GOODNESS
YOU DIDN'T LET MAMA SEE ME
GETTING OUT OF THAT
FELLOW'S CARRIAGE!
PAULINE, YOU'RE
POSITIVELY TREMBLING!
OH! IT WAS HEAVENLY!
I SIMPLY HAVE TO
TELL YOU EVERYTHING!
ISAAC KENT DROVE ME HOME!
HE USED TO BE AN
OLD BEAU OF MINE.
WELL...NO.
HARDLY AN OLD BEAU.
HE NEVER HAD ANY REAL
INTENTIONS, BUT WE USED TO
GO DRIVING ROUND TOGETHER.
HE...UM...HE...PAID
ME A COMPLIMENT.
HE SAID..."
YOUR HAIR LOOKS AS MUSH LIKE
MOLASSES TAFFY AS IT EVER DID."
I HOPE THERE WASN'T ANYTHING
IMPROPER IN HIM SAYING THAT!
NOTHING WHATSOEVER!
OH.
HE ASKED ME TO GO DRIVING AGAIN.
HEAVEN KNOWS WHAT MAMA'S GOING
TO SAY, BUT...I DON'T EVEN CARE!
LOUISA AND I...WALKED
ALL AROUND THE OLD HOUSE.
REMEMBERED ALL OF THE SUMMERS
WE HAD SPENT TOGETHER AS
GIRLS...SOME OF THE LILAC BUSHES
THAT WE PLANTED YEARS AGO...
I DON'T KNOW...I'VE JUST NEVER
HAD SUCH A WONDERFUL DAY!
PAULINE, I'M SO PLEASED!
HOW CAN I EVER REPAY YOU?
I JUST WISH YOU DIDN'T HAVE
SUCH A DIFFICULT TIME HERE.
OH, I DON'T EVEN MIND
COMING HOME, SOMEHOW.
MORGAN'S HERE FOR A
FEW WEEKS ON BUSINESS.
I HOPE IT WILL BE
JUST LIKE OLD TIMES.
AFTER ALL...
MAMA NEEDS ME.
AND IT'S NICE
BEING NEEDED, ISN'T IT?
OH!
THANK YOU, MISS SHIRLEY!
YOU KEEP THE DRESS.
HEAVEN KNOWS, YOU
MIGHT GET TO WEAR IT AGAIN!
GOD BLESS YOU!
YOU'VE DONE MORE
THAN YOU'LL EVER KNOW!
KINGSPORT LADIES COLLEGE,
MISS BROOKE SPEAKING.
WHY GOOD AFTERNOON,
MRS. PRINGLE...
SORE THROAT?
TONSILLITIS! GOOD HEAVENS!
I HOPE IT ISN'T SERIOUS...IT'S
NOT CONTAGIOUS IS IT?
OH I SEE...
NO, NO...
BUT...NO WE
UNDERSTAND COMPLETELY.
ONE MUST NOT INTERFERE
WITH A DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
I AGREE WITH YOU MRS. PRINGLE.
I APPRECIATE YOUR GIVING
US SUFFICIENT NOTICE...
THANK YOU...
GOOD-BYE.
JEN PRINGLE WILL NOT BE
PERFORMING THIS EVENING.
YOU CAN'T BE SERIOUS?
NOT AFTER ALL THIS EFFORT.
WE SHALL SIMPLY HAVE TO RETURN
THE TICKETS AND PUT IT OFF.
UNTIL WHEN?
WE CAN'T AFFORD
TO RE-BOOK THE HALL.
AND WHAT ABOUT THE BAND?
I STILL HAVE TO PAY FOR THEM.
WELL MURIEL STACEY I TOLD YOU
IT WAS FOOLISH TO GET UP A PLAY
THIS TIME OF YEAR.
DON'T BLAME ME.
JEN PRINGLE IS IN NO MORE
DANGER OF TONSILLITIS THAN I AM.
THIS IS A DELIBERATE
DEVICE TO RUIN THE PLAY
AND GET RID OF ME.
THAT'S AN AWFULLY SOUR ATTITUDE!
WHAT DO YOU INTEND TO DO?
READ IT YOURSELF?
THAT WOULD RUIN
IT...MARY IS THE ENTIRE PLAY!
WE ARE NOT POSTPONING ANYTHING.
I'LL BE BACK IN AN HOUR.
CARRY ON AS WE PLANNED
UNTIL YOU HEAR FROM ME.
MISS SHIRLEY.
I WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK
TO CAPTAIN HARRIS, PLEASE.
I AM SORRY HE'S
BUSY IN THE STUDY.
AND I REGRET TO SAY
HE WON'T BE DISTURBED...
I AM SORRY ANNABEL;
BUT THIS IS A MATTER
THAT GOES BEYOND REGRET.
COME IN!
I'LL LOOK AT THE
SHIPMENT IN BOSTON.
ON MONDAY.
ALRIGHT.
I APOLOGIZE FOR
INTERRUPTING YOU SO RUDELY SIR.
I'LL BE BRIEF.
BECAUSE YOU'VE WITHDRAWN YOUR
FINANCIAL SUPPORT FROM THE
COLLEGE, WE HAVE BEEN ATTEMPTING
TO RAISE THE BALANCE OF OUR
OPERATING COSTS THROUGH THE
PRODUCTION OF A BENEFIT CONCERT
SCHEDULED FOR THIS EVENING.
NOW OUR CONCERT IS THREATENED
BECAUSE JEN PRINGLE, OUR LEADING
PERFORMER HAS CALLED IN
ILL AT THE LAST MINUTE.
EMMELINE KNOWS THE PART COLD,
WE'VE BEEN STUDYING IT TOGETHER.
THIS OPPORTUNITY WOULD
MEAN EVERYTHING TO HER.
I KNOW WHAT YOU THINK OF ME,
MY METHODS AND THE SCHOOL!
BUT, I BEG OF YOU TO LET
HER PERFORM WITH US TONIGHT.
I TAKE IT THEN YOU
JOB IS ON THE LINE?
I INTEND TO SEE
THIS THROUGH, SIR.
YOU HAD NO BUSINESS
INTERFERING HERE, MISS SHIRLEY.
EMMELINE IS FAR TOO EASILY
INFLUENCED FOR HER OWN GOOD.
BUT UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES I...
...I FEEL I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY
FOR SOME OF THE THINGS I SAID
THE OTHER DAY AND FOR THE
TROUBLE I'VE OBVIOUSLY CAUSED.
I MEANT NO HARM.
PLEASE.
THAT WAS MY OWN FAULT.
PERHAPS I REACTED HASTILY
TAKING EMMELINE OUT OF SCHOOL.
PRINGLES LIKE TO THROW THEIR
WEIGHT AROUND THIS COMMUNITY.
YOU MIGHT SAY I
TOOK EMMELINE'S EXPULSION
AS AN ATTACK ON MYSELF.
BUT I...
THOUGHT YOU SUPPORTED
THE GENERAL CONSENSUS.
PLEASE...
DON'T LUMP ME IN WITH THAT LOT.
KINGSPORT IS A
VERY INSIDIOUS TOWN.
I AM GRATEFUL TO YOU FOR
YOUR INSIGHTS, MISS SHIRLEY.
EMMELINE MAY GO.
EMMELINE MAY GO?
OH.
THANK YOU SIR, I'M
JUST DIZZY WITH GRATITUDE.
SORRY...
MISS SHIRLEY, MISS SHIRLEY.
YOU AND EMMELINE HURRY ALONG.
THE PRINGLES WILL BE
SHARPENING THEIR KNIVES.
THANK YOU.
FORGIVE ALL EVIL TOWARD ME OF
ALL MEN DEED OR DEVICE TO HURT ME
YEA I WOULD NOT BEAR ONE
HEART UNRECONCILED WITH MINE
WHEN MINE IS COLD I WILL NOT
TAKE DEATH'S HAND WITH ANY SOIL
OF HATE OR WRATH OR WRONG ABOUT
ME, BUT BEING FRIENDS WITH THIS
PAST WORLD, PASS FROM IT IN
THE GENERAL PEACE OF LOVE...
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU ALL SO MUCH FOR
YOUR...WELL...OVERWHELMING
SUPPORT FOR THIS
EVENING'S BENEFIT.
I WOULD NOW LIKE TO INTRODUCE
TO YOU, KLC'S BRILLIANT,
YOUNG ENGLISH PROFESSOR.
AN INDIVIDUAL WHO HAS
OVERSEEN EVERY LAST INCH OF THIS
PRODUCTION AND WHOSE INSPIRED
DIRECTION HAS BROUGHT FORTH
SUCH MAGNIFICENT PERFORMANCES
FROM YOUR DAUGHTERS.
MISS ANNE SHIRLEY!
MISS SHIRLEY, ON BEHALF OF
THE KING'S COUNTY BOARD OF
EDUCATION, IT GIVES
ME VERY GREAT PLEASURE
TO PRESENT YOU WITH THIS CHEQUE.
THE PROCEEDS OF THIS EVENING'S
EXCITING EVENT MADE OUT TO THE
KINGSPORT LADIES COLLEGE IN
THE AMOUNT OF TWO THOUSAND,
FIVE HUNDRED DOLLARS!
THANK YOU LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
IT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE FOR ME TO
SPEAK WITHOUT HAVING BY MY SIDE
THE THREE OTHER ENERGETIC
SUPPORTERS OF TONIGHT'S EVENT.
MISS KERR, MISS MACKAY,
AND ESPECIALLY OUR BELOVED
PRINCIPAL, MISS KATHERINE
BROOKE; WHO HAVE ALL WORKED SO
TIRELESSLY ON THIS PRODUCTION.
IT WAS WITH GREAT TREPIDATION
THAT I BEGAN MY YEAR HERE
AT KINGSPORT LADIES COLLEGE.
AND I OWE AN ENORMOUS DEBT OF
GRATITUDE TO MY FELLOW TEACHERS
AND TO THE PARENTS OF MY
STUDENTS WHO ALL TRIED TO MAKE
ME FEEL SO AT HOME DURING MY
FIRST FEW WEEKS IN KINGSPORT.
I HAVE GROWN TO LOVE AND
RESPECT ALL OF OUR GIRLS AT KLC
AND HAVE FOUND MANY
KINDRED SPIRITS AMONG THEM.
IF WE HAVE OPENED YOUR HEARTS
THIS EVENING AND ENTERTAINED
YOU EVEN A LITTLE,
WE HAVE SUCCEEDED.
THANK YOU ALL FOR
YOUR VERY FINE SUPPORT.
I CAN'T THANK YOU ENOUGH FOR
WHAT YOU'VE DONE FOR MY MYRA.
SHE'S GOTTEN ALONG BETTER
THIS TERM THAN SHE HAS
IN A LONG TIME.
SHE'S A...JOY TO TEACH!
THANK YOU!
I JUST HOPE THEY ALL REALIZE
WHAT A JEWEL YOU ARE, MY DEAR.
I KNOW SOME OF THE OTHER
PRINGLES HAVE BEEN ABOMINABLE,
BUT I DON'T CARE WHAT THEY SAY.
YOU CAN BOARD WITH ME NEXT TERM!
THANK YOU FOR THE INVITATION!
I HAD A TEACHER JUST
LIKE YOU WHEN I WAS A GIRL.
YOU BROUGHT BACK
SO MANY MEMORIES!
CONGRATULATIONS, MY DEAR!
THANK YOU FOR YOUR KIND SUPPORT.
PAPA...PAPA...WHAT
DID YOU THINK?
YOU WERE AN ANGEL THAT
STOLE AWAY EVERYONE'S HEART,
INCLUDING MINE.
COME BACK TO EARTH
NOW FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
IT ALL FEELS LIKE A DREAM.
THANKS, I'M GLAD YOU ENJOYED IT.
EMMELINE.
OH, YOU WERE WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU!
LOOKS LIKE YOU SINGLE-HANDEDLY
ROUTED THE ENTIRE PRINGLE CLAN.
WELL, LET'S JUST SAY THE WINDS
OF PERSECUTION HAVE BLOWN OVER.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THIS HAS MEANT A
GREAT DEAL TO ME.
I'LL NEVER FORGET
IT AS LONG AS LIVE.
NOR WILL I.
GOODNIGHT EMMELINE.
MISS SHIRLEY!
I'D LIKE YOU TO GO ON TUTORING
MY DAUGHTER SO SHE'LL BE
CAUGHT UP WHEN SHE
RETURNS TO THE COLLEGE.
I'M PREPARED TO MAKE
IT WORTH YOUR WHILE.
ONLY IF YOU PUT MY WAGES BACK
INTO SUPPORTING THE COLLEGE.
YOU'RE ASKING ME TO RENEGOTIATE.
YES.
YOU HAVE A DEAL!
THANK YOU!
GOOD NIGHT EMMELINE.
GOOD NIGHT.
MISS BROOKE GENEROUSLY
LEFT THE LIGHT ON FOR US!
SHE MUST BE IN A GOOD MOOD!
SETTLE DOWN.
I'LL BE ALONG SHORTLY
TO TUCK YOU GIRLS IN.
ISN'T THAT RING AROUND
THE MOON ENCHANTING?
I'VE SEEN A GOOD MANY
MOONS IN MY TIME.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS ONE.
SIT DOWN!
LET'S LET IT JUST
SOAK INTO OUR SOULS.
WASN'T IT A MARVELLOUS EVENING?
DON'T MAKE A FOOL OUT
OF YOURSELF, PLEASE.
IT WAS THOUGHT IN ANCIENT TIMES
THAT WHEN A MAN AND A WOMAN SAT
UNDER SUCH A MOON, THEY
WOULD BE BONDED TOGETHER
IN LOVE FOR ETERNITY.
LOVE...IF I DIED TOMORROW, NOT
ONE LIVING SOUL WOULD MISS ME.
WHAT IS IT YOU
WANT, ANNE SHIRLEY?
TO BE YOUR FRIEND.
I DON'T HAVE FRIENDS.
I DON'T HAVE YOUR NOTABLE GIFT
FOR DOING THE QUEEN ACT - ALWAYS
SAYING THE RIGHT
THING TO EVERYONE.
YOU SAY YOU LIKE
PEOPLE TO BE FRANK?
WELL I'M GOING TO BE FRANK.
IT'S YOUR OWN FAULT
THAT NO ONE LIKES YOU!
KATHERINE BROOKE, YOU ARE
ALL PRICKLES AND STINGS!
I KNOW I'M UNSOCIAL
AND PEOPLE HATE ME.
DO YOU THINK IT DOESN'T
HURT THAT I'M ALWAYS NEGLECTED
AND OVERLOOKED AT
SOCIAL FUNCTIONS?
I'M SORRY.
I'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE TO
SWALLOW ALL THE SNUBS AND POKES
I'VE RECEIVED DURING MY LIFE.
I REMEMBER EVERY SINGLE ONE.
FOR FIFTEEN YEARS I HAD TO
ENDURE RELATIVES WHO CARED AS
LITTLE FOR ME AS
MY DEAD PARENTS!
I LIVED IN THIRD-RATE BOARDING
HOUSES THAT FROZE IN WINTER
AND STANK IN SUMMER!
I'VE WORN THEIR
CAST-OFF CLOTHES!
FORTUNATELY, I HAD MY GRADES.
I MADE IT THROUGH COLLEGE
AND I PAID BACK EVERY CENT!
OH YES, I'M INDEPENDENT NOW.
THE TRUTH IS, I HATE TEACHING!
BUT THERE'S
NOTHING ELSE I CAN DO!
LOOK AT YOU.
LITTLE MESSENGER OF OPTIMISM.
BUT HOW LONG WILL IT LAST?
FIVE?
MAYBE TEN YEARS
BEFORE YOU WITHER
INSIDE OF
THIS...ENDLESS MONOTONY.
PREPARE TO JOIN THE RANKS OF
COLD, UNINTERESTING SPINSTERS
WHO HAVE CHOSEN A PROFESSIONAL
CAREER, ANNE SHIRLEY!
"...AND IN PARTICULAR, THE
PERFORMANCE OF EMMELINE HARRIS
WHO WAS SO CONVINCING IN
THE ROLE OF THE YOUNG QUEEN.
THE AUDIENCE WAS SO
UNEXPECTEDLY MOVED.
IT IS OUR OPINION THAT THIS
PROFICIENT GROUP OF YOUNG
ACTRESSES MUST ESTABLISH A
PERMANENT DRAMATIC SOCIETY.
THE KINGSPORT EXAMINER EAGERLY
AWAITS THEIR NEXT PRODUCTION."
AND ON THAT NOTE OF
PRAISE, I HOPE YOU ALL PERFORM
AS TRIUMPHANTLY ON YOUR
TERM EXAM NEXT FRIDAY.
CLASS DISMISSED.
EMMELINE!
I'D LIKE TO APOLOGIZE...FOR
THE...INCONVENIENCE
THAT I CAUSED YOU, MISS SHIRLEY.
WE'RE ALL GLAD TO
SEE THAT YOUR HEALTH
HAS IMPROVED...SO QUICKLY.
YES.
I THINK THAT THE DOCTOR
WAS OVERLY CONCERNED.
I HOPE I MAY STAY IN THE
DRAMATIC SOCIETY - IF YOU'RE
GOING TO CONTINUE.
OH. WE COULDN'T DO WITHOUT YOU.
OH, THANK YOU, MISS SHIRLEY!
OH - MY MOTHER WANTS
TO KNOW IF YOU'D LIKE TO HELP
WITH THE ANNUAL HOSPITAL BAZAAR.
IF YOU HAVE THE TIME.
TELL YOUR MOTHER
I'D BE FLATTERED!
GOOD AFTERNOON GIRLS.
OH ANNE.
HELLO.
THE BOARD WAS
TOTALLY ENTHRALLED.
BETTER THAN THAT...
THEY WERE ABSOLUTELY
FLOORED WHEN THEY RECEIVED
CAPTAIN HARRIS' CHEQUE.
THEY WANT TO RENEW YOUR
CONTRACT FOR FIVE YEARS!
FIVE YEARS!
I'M NOT SURE I
COULD LAST THAT LONG.
WELL, I THINK THAT YOU OUGHT
TO WRITE A BOOK ABOUT IT.
OH MISS BROOKE
ISN'T IT WONDERFUL!
AUTHORS ARE SUCH KITTLE KATTLE.
I WOULDN'T TRUST YOUR
DESCRIPTION OF ANY OF US.
HERE, THESE CAME FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
OH!
THANK YOU AGAIN.
I WOULD LIKE TO
RETURN THE FAVOUR.
I'D BE PLEASED TO
HAVE YOU ESCORT MY FAMILY
FOR A SHORT VISIT TO BOSTON
WHEN I RETURN IN A MONTH.
SINCERELY, MORGAN HARRIS.
OH, THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL!
PAULINE HARRIS YOU DON'T KNOW
IF YOU'RE COMING OR GOING GIRL.
MOVE THAT HATBOX.
NOT UP THERE GIRL
YOU'LL BRAIN ME.
IT'S NOT SAFE UP THERE EITHER.
PUT IT BACK GIRL, PUT IT BACK!
LOWER THE BLIND, IT NEEDS TO
BE JUST ABOUT ONE INCH LOWER.
OH PAULINE...PAULINE.
NOW YOU'VE DONE IT!
ALL THAT LIGHT MAKES
MY HEADACHE WORSE.
I'M SORRY MAMA.
WELL, YOU'VE GOT YOUR
COLOUR BACK MRS. HARRIS;
YOU MUST BE FEELING BETTER.
I AM COMPLETELY WORN
OUT WITH ALL THE WORRY
AND MOTION SICKNESS.
MY STOMACH IS
DROPPING OUT OF ME.
WHY I EVER LISTENED TO
YOU AND CAME ON THIS TRIP
IN THE FIRST PLACE...
NOW, NOW...WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE
SOME LUNCH PAULINE.
WE ARE NOT HUNGRY.
CAN THEY MAKE A DECENT CUP
OF TEA ON THIS CONTRAPTION?
I'D RATHER DRINK MUD THAN
THE TEA THAT SOME PEOPLE MAKE.
YES MRS. HARRIS.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN PROCURE.
...AND SEE THAT THEY
WASH THE CUP OUT PROPERLY.
I DON'T MEAN TO BE A TROUBLE TO
ANYONE...BUT THE WAY I'M FEELING
I DON'T THINK I'LL
BE HERE MUCH LONGER.
THEN PERHAPS YOU'LL
APPRECIATE ME.
POOR AUNT PAULINE.
OH WELL, GRANDMAMA WILL SLEEP
FOR DAYS ONCE WE GET THERE.
I CAN HARDLY WAIT TO
SEE PAPA'S NEW HOUSE.
I'VE ONLY EVER HEARD
OF HOW WONDERFUL IT IS.
I'VE A FEELING WE'RE
ALL HERE ON APPROVAL.
PAPA THINKS VERY HIGHLY
OF YOU, MISS SHIRLEY.
HE SAID SO.
HELLO, HOW IS MOTHER?
SHE ALLOWED US TO
ORDER HER A CUP OF TEA.
HOWEVER, SHE IS
THROWING OUT COMPLAINTS
AT THE SPEED OF THIS TRAIN.
IF WE LIKE YOUR
NEW HOUSE IN BOSTON PAPA,
CAN MISS SHIRLEY
AND I STAY WITH YOU?
HMM, I DON'T KNOW IF
BOSTON'S LARGE ENOUGH
FOR TWO SOPHISTICATED LADIES.
GOING FROM AVONLEA TO KINGSPORT
WAS AN ADVENTURE CAPTAIN.
I ASSURE YOU THIS WILL
BE AN EPOCH IN MY LIFE.
WELL, I'M SURE YOU AND BOSTON
WILL MAKE QUITE AN IMPRESSION
ON EACH OTHER.
IF I CAN REMEMBER NOT TO
LOOK AS BACKWARD AS I FEEL.
ALL THIS MOVING ABOUT...
MY NEURITIS IS AGONY AND
NOBODY CARES WHAT I SUFFER.
MOTHER...
SO THIS IS WHAT YOU'VE
BEEN WASTING MY MONEY
ON MORGAN HARRIS.
I DIDN'T INVITE YOU ALL THE WAY
TO BOSTON TO CARRY ON LIKE THIS!
IT ISN'T FAIR, MORGAN.
IT SIMPLY ISN'T FAIR!
THE CHILD HAD GOT TO COME
BACK AND LIVE WITH YOU!
I CAN'T AFFORD THE
EXPENSES AND I SIMPLY
CAN'T STAND THE TROUBLE!
PAULINE HAS GOT QUITE ENOUGH
TO DO - OH, I DON'T MIND MAMA -
PLEASE DON'T CONTRADICT ME!
DON'T BE SO DEMANDING!
SHE'S BACK IN SCHOOL,
BESIDES I THOUGHT
YOU ENJOYED HAVING HER WITH YOU!
I AM 79 YEARS OF AGE, MY
BOY, AND I CAN'T BE BOTHERED
WITH THE CHILD.
YOU'VE GOT THIS ENORMOUS HOUSE!
IT ALL COMES OUT OF YOUR
FATHER'S ESTATE, DOESN'T IT?
HUH?
I HAVE EVERY RIGHT
TO BE 'DEMANDING'!
WHY DON'T YOU GET MARRIED AGAIN?
I HAVEN'T THE
TEMPERAMENT FOR IT.
I SUPPOSE NO ONE WOULD TAKE YOU!
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS, MOTHER!
OF COURSE, I REALIZE MY OPINIONS
DON'T MATTER ANY LONGER.
I MIGHT JUST AS WELL BE DEAD.
THEN YOU CAN HAVE
THE REST OF THE MONEY!
PLEASE DON'T SAY THAT,
MAMA - I WILL SAY IT!
YOU'RE TWO UNGRATEFUL CHILDREN!
HOW MANY TIMES HAVE I SAT
UP AT NIGHT, NURSING YOU?
WHEN YOU WERE LITTLE?
SOMETIMES I THOUGHT YOU'D
NEVER LIVE TO SEE THE DAWN!
A MOTHER'S SACRIFICES
ARE SOON FORGOTTEN.
MAMA.
PLEASE COME TO BED.
IT'S JUST THE
STRAIN OF BEING -
SAINTS ABOVE, PAULINE!
WILL YOU KEEP OUT OF THIS?
NOW LISTEN TO ME, MORGAN.
I AM NOT GOING TO BED UNTIL
YOU GIVE ME A DECISIVE ANSWER.
FACE UP TO YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES
AND BEHAVE LIKE A MAN!
ALL RIGHT!
I SHALL LOOK INTO MAKING THE
ARRANGEMENTS AS SOON AS I CAN.
WELL.
THAT'S BETTER.
GOODNIGHT?
GOODNIGHT, MORGAN.
YOU CAN'T RELY ON THAT BOY TO
STAY IN THE SAME LINE FOR TWO
MINUTES TOGETHER.
HE'LL TOSS THAT CHILD BACK IN
MY LAP AS SURE AS SURE CAN BE.
AND WHAT DO YOU THINK OF MY
SON'S LACK OF RESPONSIBILITY?
I QUITE AGREE!
GOODNIGHT, MISS SHIRLEY!
PLEASE...DON'T GET UP.
I JUST WANTED TO SAY WHAT A
LOVELY EVENING THIS HAS BEEN.
AND THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME
SUCH A WONDERFUL OPPORTUNITY.
I APOLOGIZE FOR
MOTHER'S BEHAVIOUR.
IN HER CONDITION,
SARCASM IS HER ONE RELIEF.
IT'S HER PRINGLE NATURE...
I SUPPOSE.
I'M SURPRISED YOU'VE PUT UP WITH
ALL THIS KINGSPORT NONSENSE
AS WELL AS YOU HAVE.
WELL, IT HAS
BEEN A CHALLENGE...
AS WELL AS A
VERY GOOD EXPERIENCE.
OH, I DESPERATELY MISS
MY GREEN GABLES THOUGH.
WATCHING THE HOME
LIGHTS FLICKER ACROSS THE POND
AT NIGHT...MARILLA WAITING
FOR ME ON THE VERANDAH.
PROBABLY SOUNDS
VERY FOOLISH TO YOU.
CAN'T ESCAPE YOUR WHOLESOME
ISLAND UPBRINGING...
IT MUST FEEL VERY EMPTY LIVING
IN THIS VAST HOUSE ALL ALONE.
WELL, IT'S AN INVESTMENT REALLY.
I'M AWAY SO FREQUENTLY.
WHAT IS IT THAT KEEPS
YOU AWAY FROM KINGSPORT?
KEEPING OCCUPIED WITH
THE ALL-CONSUMING PROBLEMS
OF MY BUSINESS.
RUNNING AWAY...?
NO. PERHAPS HOLDING OUT
FOR A REASON TO RETURN.
WELL, I HOPE YOU'VE FOUND ONE.
I'M VERY GRATEFUL TO YOU
FOR ALL YOUR HOSPITALITY.
WELL, I'M VERY GRATEFUL
TO YOU FOR THE PLEASURE
OF SUCH HIGH SPIRITS.
GOODNIGHT.
GOODNIGHT MORGAN HARRIS.
ANNE SHIRLEY, I HOPE
WE SHALL SEE YOU OFTEN
WHEN I RETURN TO KINGSPORT.
LET'S TRY A NEW ONE, SHALL WE?
YES!
DO YOU THINK THIS MAKES
ME LOOK OLDER, PAPA?
OH, YES, EMMELINE.
WE CAN'T MAKE UP OUR
MINDS WHICH OF THESE HATS
LOOK MORE SOPHISTICATED!
NEITHER CAN I.
WE'LL TAKE ALL OF THEM.
PAPA!
WE CAN MANAGE THEM.
HERE SHE IS.
THE GREAT LADY OF
THE WEST INDIES.
SHE'S MAGNIFICENT!
WHAT DOES "MISTRAL" MEAN, PAPA?
IT MEANS A "ROUGH, COLD WIND".
OH NO, CAPTAIN.
IT SHOULD BE CHRISTENED AFTER
A DELICIOUS, PERFUMED WIND.
LIKE A ZEPHYR.
THEN I SHALL NAME THE NEXT
ONE THE ZEPHYR IN YOUR HONOUR!
...AND THE EXCURSION TO BOSTON
ALL SEEMS LIKE A DREAM SOMEHOW.
EMMELINE, WHO HAS HAD SUCH A
FORSAKEN LIFE UP TO NOW
HAS BLOSSOMED AND I FEEL
CAPTAIN HARRIS NOW RECOGNIZES
THE TREASURE HE
DIDN'T KNOW HE POSSESSED.
I AM A LITTLE WEARY OF
LIVING OUT OF A TRUNK THOUGH
AND I LONG TO FEEL THE
SUMMER LOVELINESS OF HOME.
I MISS YOU BOTH SO VERY MUCH.
WITH ALL MY HEART.
ANNE.
SHE'S PLAIN WORN OUT
IF YOU ASK ME MARILLA.
I'M NOT SURPRISED, THE WAY
GIRLS ROAM THE EARTH NOW
IS SOMETHING TERRIBLE.
IT REMINDS ME OF SATAN IN THE
BOOK OF JOB GOING TO AND FRO
AND WALKING UP AND DOWN.
I DON'T THINK THE
LORD EVER INTENDED IT...
WHAT IS TO BE WILL BE RACHEL.
AND WHAT ISN'T TO
BE SOMETIMES HAPPENS.
RICHES ARE ALL
VERY WELL MARILLA.
BUT IF ANNE PREFERS THE
HANDSOME UNKNOWN TO AVONLEA.
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING
MORE TO BE SAID.
IT'S IN THE HANDS OF PROVIDENCE.
I ENJOYED YOUR
COMPANY IN BOSTON.
I HOPE THE TERM IS CONTINUING
WELL IN KINGSPORT AND EMMELINE
IS CAUGHT UP NOW IN HER STUDIES.
THANK YOU AGAIN.
SINCERELY, MORGAN HARRIS.
ANNE SHIRLEY.
WHAT IN HECK ARE YOU DOING HERE?
GIL?
YOU'RE THE VERY LAST PERSON
I'D EVER EXPECTED TO MEET OUT
HERE ON A DAY LIKE THIS!
C'MON.
THE ROYAL ACADEMY OF PHYSICIANS
IS CONVENING HERE THIS WEEKEND
AND I'M HERE AS A DELEGATE.
YOU MUST BE PROUD OF YOURSELF.
NOT AS PROUD AS I WAS OF
YOU WHEN I READ THAT CLIPPING
MISS STACEY SENT ME ABOUT
THE SUCCESS OF YOUR PLAY.
THAT'S SWEET OF YOU GIL.
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
WELL I WAS ACTUALLY HOPING
WE'D RUN INTO EACH OTHER.
I WASN'T SURE WHETHER YOU'D BE
HAPPY TO SEE ME OR NOT, SO I..
HAPPY?
I CAN'T BEGIN TO
EXPRESS MY HAPPINESS!
LET ME LOOK AT YOU.
OH YES.
DO I LOOK LIKE A
YOUNG MEDICAL STUDENT NOW?
NOT A BIT.
YOU CAN'T FOOL ME.
YOU ARE STILL THE
SAME INCORRIGIBLE GIL.
TELL ME ALL THE AVONLEA NEWS.
HAVE YOU BEEN BACK?
UH, NO, I'VE BEEN
SPENDING MOST OF MY TIME
WITH THE STUARTS IN HALIFAX.
DR. STUART'S A VERY
PROMINENT SURGEON.
IT'S HE WHO ARRANGED FOR
ME TO ATTEND AS HIS DELEGATE.
YOU SEE...
CHRISTINE AND I ARE ENGAGED.
IT'S SET FOR NEXT SUMMER.
I'M SO HAPPY FOR YOU GIL.
I GUESS THAT'S WHY I WANTED TO
SEE YOU SO MUCH; TO APOLOGIZE
FOR BEING SUCH A
FOOL LAST SUMMER.
YOU KNOW, I THINK I
UNDERSTAND NOW WHAT YOU MEANT.
I MEANT WHAT I SAID TOO
AND I WON'T EVER FORGET YOU.
YOU TURNED OUT AS I
ALWAYS IMAGINED YOU WOULD.
DOESN'T IT SEEM LIKE
YESTERDAY WE WERE OFF TO QUEEN'S
AND VYING FOR
THOSE SCHOLARSHIPS.
I SUPPOSE YOU'VE
KEPT UP YOUR WRITING.
NOT REALLY...
I'VE BEEN BUSY AND WELL
PUBLISHERS AREN'T INTERESTED
IN THOSE KINDS OF STORIES.
WELL I WOULDN'T
GIVE UP ALTOGETHER.
YOU KNOW I ALWAYS THOUGHT
YOU SHOULD WRITE A BOOK
ABOUT AVONLEA.
CHANGE THE NAME, OF COURSE,
OR RACHEL LYNDE WOULD THINK
SHE WAS THE HEROINE.
AVONLEA IS THE DEAREST PLACE
IN THE WORLD, I DON'T THINK
IT'S AN INTERESTING
ENOUGH SETTING FOR A STORY.
WELL, I INTEND TO TAKE CHRISTINE
BACK TO THE ISLAND WITH ME
AND SET UP MY PRACTICE THERE.
DR. STUART HAS A LOT OF PULL
IN HALIFAX AND WOULD LIKE US
TO LIVE THERE, BUT
I DON'T WANT ANY HANDOUTS.
BESIDES, ANY OTHER PLACE JUST
WOULDN'T SEEM LIKE HOME TO ME.
NO, OF COURSE.
THE BOARD OF GOVERNORS
AT THE COLLEGE JUST OFFERED
ME A FIVE-YEAR CONTRACT...
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
YOU'VE CERTAINLY WON
YOUR WAY INTO THE HEARTS
OF THIS AFFLUENT OLD TOWN.
YOU WON'T BE LONELY.
I'LL SURVIVE.
WELL I OUGHT TO GO.
TRAIN LEAVES AT 5:30.
AW, NO. REALLY?
OH...UH I WAS GOING
TO UH MAIL THIS BUT....
A NOTE JUST ISN'T THE SAME.
THANKS GIL.
GOOD-BYE ANNE.
GOOD-BYE GIL.
DON'T FORGET ME.
GIL!
THANK YOU, GOOD-BYE.
GOOD-BYE ANNE.
MISS SHIRLEY WOULD YOU HELP
US ARRANGE ALL THESE GARLANDS
AND BUNTING?
THIS IS A HOPELESS MESS!
WHAT'S THE MATTER MRS. PRINGLE?
NOT ONE OF THESE NITWITS
HAS AS MUCH ARTISTIC ABILITY
YOU HAVE IN YOUR BABY FINGER.
LADIES I'M PUTTING
MISS SHIRLEY IN CHARGE HERE.
LET ME SEE.
I SUGGEST YOU GATHER
IT UP IN A ROSETTE LIKE THIS
AND THEN WE'LL HANG THEM
WITH THE FESTOONS AFTERWARDS.
WE WERE ALL SO IMPRESSED
WITH YOUR PRODUCTION
AT THE COLLEGE MISS SHIRLEY.
THANK YOU.
AND TO THINK HOW YOU TRANSFORMED
MORGAN HARRIS' LITTLE GIRL.
HE'S HARDLY HAD ANYTHING
TO DO WITH THE POOR CHILD
SINCE SHE WAS BORN.
SUCH A TRAGEDY WHEN
HIS ADELAIDE DIED...
SHE WAS A RARE BEAUTY.
OLD MRS. HARRIS AND MOTHER
PRINGLE ARE FIRST COUSINS.
AND I KNOW HOW THE HARRISES
HAVE CUT THEMSELVES OFF
FROM EVERYBODY.
IT WAS MORGAN'S FAULT THOUGH,
SHE RAN AWAY AND LEFT HIM.
TERRIBLE REPUTATION
WITH THE LADIES.
THEY SAY ADELAIDE REALLY
DIED OF A BROKEN HEART.
I'M SURE THAT HE'S FELT
SO GUILTY ALL THESE YEARS
THAT HE CAN'T STAND
THE SIGHT OF THE CHILD.
MORE THAN LIKELY IT'S
THE OLD LADY HE CAN'T STAND.
WELL I KNOW FOR A FACT THAT HE
HAS BEEN SEEING ELVIRA EVANS...
STANDARD OIL
FORTUNE FROM BOSTON.
SHE HAS BEEN STAYING FOR THE
LAST TWO WEEKS AT MAPLEHURST
OR SO MY SISTER-IN-LAW TELLS ME.
YOU'VE GOTTEN TO KNOW COUSIN
MORGAN HAVEN'T YOU MISS SHIRLEY?
YES.
WE'VE MET ON SEVERAL OUTINGS.
HE'S VERY CHARMING.
WE'RE GOING TO GIVE MISS EVANS
A TOUR OF THE OLD TOWN THIS
AFTERNOON, EMMELINE.
"DEAR MISS SHIRLEY, PLEASE
ACCEPT OUR CONGRATULATIONS
ON YOUR BOOK ENTITLED
'AVONLEA VIGNETTES'.
ENCLOSED IS OUR CHEQUE FOR TWO
HUNDRED AND FIFTY DOLLARS
AS ADVANCED AGAINST
OUR ROYALTIES -"
ANNE!
ANNE?
OH, HELLO.
ANNE, I WAS HOPING
I'D RUN IN TO YOU.
WE'VE MISSED HAVING
YOU BACK AT MAPLEHURST.
I CAN IMAGINE IT MUST BE VERY
DIFFICULT FOR YOU TO GET AWAY
FROM YOUR IMPORTANT GUEST.
YES, IT IS.
BUT PLEASE -
DON'T APOLOGIZE. I UNDERSTAND.
GOOD DAY, SIR.
MAY I OFFER YOU A RIDE
BACK TO THE COLLEGE?
NO, THANK YOU.
WHAT'S NAGGING
YOU, MISS SHIRLEY?
YOU'RE BEHAVING RATHER LIKE
A SPINSTERLY OLD SCHOOL MARM,
DON'T YOU THINK?
PERHAPS THAT'S BECAUSE I AM ONE!
I SAY THAT WITH ADMIRATION!
THAT WAS A COMPLIMENT.
I AM A GREAT PROPONENT
OF INDEPENDENT THINKING.
MOREOVER, I HAVE ALWAYS HELD
THAT EARLY MARRIAGES ARE A SURE
INDICATION OF SECOND RATE GOODS
THAT HAD TO BE SOLD IN A HURRY.
WOULDN'T YOU AGREE?
WELL YOU CAN BE SURE I AM OF THE
FIRST RATE KIND, MORGAN HARRIS,
AND I CERTAINLY HAVE FAR
GREATER AMBITIONS THAN MARRIAGE.
ALL THAT YOU ARE
INSINUATING IS NAGGING ME.
I'M ABOUT TO HAVE A SHORT
WORK OF FICTION PUBLISHED!
I AM AFRAID IT HAS ME
COMPLETELY PREOCCUPIED!
WELL, LET ME OFFER
MY CONGRATULATIONS!
GOOD DAY!
ANNE...ANNE!
I AM SORRY.
I OUGHT NOT TO HAVE SUCH
A BACK HANDED INVITATION.
I'VE BEEN MEANING TO ASK
MOTHER TO INVITE YOU BACK
TO MAPLEHURST.
HOW GRACIOUS OF YOU!
BUT MY SCHEDULE IS SO JAM
PACKED, I AM SURE I WON'T BE
ABLE TO SQUEEZE IT IN.
I TAKE IT YOU'LL ATTEND
THE HOSPITAL BENEFIT
TOMORROW EVENING?
YES, I'M...
WORKING AS A VOLUNTEER.
I SHALL LOOK FORWARD
TO SEEING YOU THERE.
WOULD YOU DO ME THE
HONOUR, MISS SHIRLEY,
OF RESERVING ME
WALTZ ON YOUR CARD.
OF COURSE.
I'D BE PLEASED
TO, MORGAN HARRIS.
THANK YOU.
IF I HAVE A WALTZ SPACE FREE!
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU LOOK LIKE A
GIBSON MAGAZINE COVER!
PERHAPS SOME ROMANTIC
ARTIST WILL FALL FOR YOU
AND ASK TO PAINT YOUR PICTURE...
OH, MISS SHIRLEY!
I'M GONNA WEAR MY HAIR JUST
LIKE THAT WHEN I TURN EIGHTEEN!
YOU DARLINGS!
IMITATION IS THE SINCEREST
FORM OF FLATTERY.
WOULD YOU RUN ALONG AND
SEE IF MY CAB IS HERE?
THANK YOU!
MY, MY...GOING TO LONDON
TO VISIT THE QUEEN, ARE WE?
ARE YOU NOT CAPABLE OF
SAYING ANYTHING PLEASANT?
NO.
I HAVEN'T YOUR TALENT
FOR PRETENDING THINGS.
YOU TAKE MY BREATH AWAY
WITH YOUR COMPLIMENTS.
YOU ALWAYS HAVE SOME
SECRET DELIGHT, DON'T YOU?
DON'T DECEIVE YOURSELF!
YOU'LL NEVER BE ONE OF THEM!
DESPITE YOU FLAUNTING YOUR
STRING OF PEARLS AND MAKING
A SPECTACLE OF YOURSELF.
MORGAN HARRIS IS A MAN
OF STATUS AND ACHIEVEMENT.
AND YOU, MY DEAR, ARE
NOTHING BETTER THAN A TEACHER.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN, BUT I HONESTLY
FEEL SORRY FOR YOU, KATHERINE.
YOU SHUT OUT EVERY SPARK
OF HAPPINESS AROUND YOU.
I WILL NOT BE POISONED
BY YOUR BITTERNESS!
YOU ARE GOOD LUCK ANNE SHIRLEY.
THIS IS THE LARGEST NUMBER
OF TICKETS WE'VE EVER SOLD
FOR THE HOSPITAL.
WELL, I ENJOY HELPING OUT ANY
WHICH WAY I CAN MRS. PRINGLE.
DON'T GET STUCK BEHIND
THAT TABLE ALL NIGHT.
BE SURE TO GET A DANCE.
I WILL.
YOU TOOK THE
TEACHER'S COURSE AT QUEEN'S.
SHIRLEY, ISN'T IT?
ANNE SHIRLEY.
YES.
LEWIS ALLEN.
I REMEMBER YOU WON
THE AVERY SCHOLARSHIP
AND GILBERT BLYTHE
WON THE GOLD MEDAL.
YES THAT'S RIGHT.
PLEASED TO KNOW YOU.
WHAT DO YOU DO NOW, LEWIS?
I'M THE PRINCIPAL OF
RICHMOND PUBLIC SCHOOL.
NOT THE MOST ADVENTUROUS PLACE
IN THE WORLD, BUT UH I'VE DONE
ALRIGHT FOR MYSELF, COMPARED
TO A LOT OF OTHERS FROM QUEEN'S.
DO YOU DANCE AS
WELL AS YOU BOAST?
BETTER.
MORGAN HARRIS CERTAINLY
UPSTAGED THE PRINGLES
WITH THAT EVANS WOMAN.
THEY SAY SHE'S A PERFECT CAT.
WORTH MILLIONS THOUGH.
I'VE MET HER AND BELIEVE
ME IT WILL TAKE ALL HIS GOLD
TO GILD A PILL LIKE HER.
IT'S A MATCH OF ADJOINING
BANK ACCOUNTS, TO BE SURE.
ANNE! ANNE!
GOOD EVENING SIR;
OR RATHER GOODNIGHT.
GOODNIGHT?
YOU PROMISED ME A WALTZ.
I'M SORRY.
MY CARD WAS FULL ALL EVENING.
YOU NEEDN'T FEEL
OBLIGATED TO PATRONIZE
A LOCAL SCHOOL TEACHER.
I'M SURE YOU'VE PAID
HANDSOMELY FOR YOUR TICKETS.
WAIT A MOMENT, LET ME EXPLAIN.
PLEASE DON'T SPOIL THE
EVENING FOR YOUR GUEST
BY CAUSING A SCENE.
ANNE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I'M QUITE EXHAUSTED.
PLEASE DON'T COMPLICATE
MATTERS BY MAKING EXCUSES.
ELVIRA EVANS IS A
BUSINESS ASSOCIATE.
FOR THE PAST YEAR I HAVE BEEN
LIQUIDATING THE LAST OF HER
FATHER'S SHIPPING ESTATE.
BRINGING HER TO MAPLEHURST
WAS A GESTURE OF HOSPITALITY.
THE CONCLUSION OF A
LENGTHY TRANSACTION.
I KNOW WHEN I'M BEING
CONVENIENTLY EXCLUDED.
IT ISN'T THAT AT ALL.
BE REASONABLE.
WHY SHOULD I.
I HAVE NO ULTERIOR MOTIVES.
YOU'RE ACTING AS
FICKLE-MINDED AS A BREEZE.
WE ALL GO ON ABOUT YOU.
EVEN MOTHER.
SHE ABSOLUTELY ADORES YOU.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES
HOW COULD I HAVE INVITED YOU
THIS EVENING?
CERTAINLY WASN'T
FISHING FOR AN INVITATION.
PERHAPS IT'S MY WHOLESOME
ISLAND UPBRINGING, BUT I HAVE
NO INTENTION OF
BECOMING "FANCY'S FOOL"!
I WOULD LIKE YOU TO
COME BACK TO MAPLEHURST.
INDEED I DON'T KNOW WHY.
AS EMMELINE'S GOVERNESS PERHAPS?
I'LL SAVE YOU THE
TROUBLE OF ASKING.
I WON'T LOSE YOU
AGAIN, SHIRLEY.
LET GO OF ME.
PLEASE, I WOULD...OH!
MORGAN HARRIS, OH I'M AWFULLY
SORRY, BUT YOU GRABBED ME.
I WANT TO ASK YOU TO MARRY ME.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I'M IN LOVE WITH YOU.
YOU REALLY MEAN THAT DON'T YOU.
MY LIFE ON IT.
I ONLY KNOW I COULD
NEVER BEAR TO LOSE YOU.
WOULD YOU DO ME THE HONOUR OF
GIVING ME YOUR HAND IN MARRIAGE?
ANNE, WHAT IS IT?
I DO CARE A GREAT DEAL
FOR YOU AND EMMELINE.
BUT I CAN'T.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN THAT FOR FIVE GLORIOUS
SECONDS I REALLY THOUGHT
PERHAPS I COULD MARRY YOU.
I USED TO DREAM OF
A MOMENT LIKE THIS.
NOW, I CAN'T DESCRIBE
IT, I NEED TO GO HOME.
YOU COULD GO BACK
FOR SUMMER HOLIDAYS.
RENT ONE OF THOSE BIG
OLD PLACES ON THE GULF.
NOT THE SAME THING...
IS IT?
NO.
LOOK AT YOU.
YOU'RE OUT HERE
WITHOUT EVEN YOUR COAT ON!
YOU'LL CATCH YOUR DEATH.
WE SHOULD GO BACK IN.
I STILL HAVE A WALTZ FREE.
ALRIGHT?
LET'S GIVE THOSE OLD LADIES
SOMETHING TO GOSSIP ABOUT.
COME IN...
WHY MR. MCGUINNESS, WHAT IS IT?
YOU MUST COME QUICKLY
TO MAPLEHURST, MISS.
EVERYONE'S WORRIED.
MRS. HARRIS HAS
KEPT SILENT ALL WEEK.
SILENT?
SOMETHING MUST BE
DREADFULLY WRONG.
SHE TOOK A BAD SPELL
JUST AFTER PAPA LEFT.
NOW SHE WON'T EAT OR DRINK
AND POOR AUNT PAULINE IS BESIDE
HERSELF TO KNOW
WHAT WE SHOULD DO.
MISS SHIRLEY THANK
GOODNESS YOU'VE COME.
I'M AFRAID THAT SHE'S
SLIPPING AWAY...
AND IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
ISAAC KENT WANTS
ME TO...TO...MARRY
HIM....PRACTICALLY.
HE'S ASKED ME TO JOIN
THE PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH
CHOIR LEAGUE.
MAMA HATES ISAAC AS MUCH AS SHE
DID FIFTEEN YEARS AGO WHEN SHE
SET THE BULL TERRIER ON HIM
FOR COMING AROUND TO SEE ME.
I DON'T THINK SHE'LL FORGIVE ME.
I'M SO AFRAID
SHE'S GOING TO DIE...
YOU MUST CHOOSE
BETWEEN THEM, PAULINE.
OH, I DON'T THINK I
CAN LIVE WITHOUT HIM!
DON'T BE FRIGHTENED
NOW, YOU MUST ACCEPT!
OH, MISS SHIRLEY!
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN ABLE TO
SMOOTH THINGS OVER WITH MAMA.
PLEASE TRY TO GET
HER TO FORGIVE ME?
OH IT'S YOU IS IT?
MRS. HARRIS PLEASE HEAR
ME THROUGH PATIENTLY...
I'M ALWAYS
PATIENT...VERY PATIENT.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
PAULINE IS GREATLY TROUBLED.
SHE IS OF THE OPINION THAT
SHE SHOULD ACCEPT ISAAC KENT'S
HAND IN MARRIAGE.
I THOUGHT THERE WAS
SOME FOOLISHNESS BETWEEN HER
AND THAT RIDICULOUS FELLOW!
IN YOUR HEART YOU MUST KNOW
IT'S THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
THE TRUTH IS, PAULINE NEEDS
YOUR FORGIVENESS IF SHE'S
EVER GONNA BE HAPPY.
I ADVISED HER TO BE MARRIED.
AND I BEG OF YOU TO LET HER GO.
IF YOU'VE MANAGED TO GET PAULINE
TO ACCEPT THAT ISAAC KENT
YOU'VE ACCOMPLISHED MORE THAN
I THOUGHT WAS HUMANLY POSSIBLE.
AT LEAST I SHAN'T HAVE TO CLIMB
DOWN AND TELL HIM TO TAKE HER.
"I WITHHOLD NOT MY
HEART FROM ANY JOY..."
THAT IS BIBLE AUTHORITY FOR YOU.
MY DEAR, MAN
IS BORN INTO TROUBLE
AS THE SPARKS FLY UPWARDS...
JOB 5 VERSE 6, MISS SHIRLEY.
PAULINE...COME....HERE....GIRL!
NO ONE CAN DENY MARGARET PRINGLE
HARRIS' PLACE AS A CORNERSTONE
OF OUR COMMUNITY.
IT IS WITH GREAT REMORSE
THAT WE TURN HER SPIRIT
OVER TO HER MASTER.
THOUGH OUR HEARTS BE
TROUBLED WITH THIS GRAVE LOSS,
WE MUST REMIND OURSELVES OF THE
FLEETINGNESS OF OUR OWN LIVES
AND THAT SOME DAY WE SHALL
REJOICE WITH MARGARET FOREVER
IN THE HEREAFTER.
AMEN.
GOOD-BYE.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE'RE GOING BACK TO
BOSTON, MISS SHIRLEY.
PAULINE HAS ACCEPTED ISAAC KENT.
I'VE DECIDED TO SELL MAPLEHURST.
HOW I SHALL MISS YOU EM.
BUT WE WILL SEE
EACH OTHER AGAIN SOON.
AND I PROMISE YOU I WON'T EVER
FORGET YOU, JUST YOU MIND THAT.
I WILL.
GOOD-BYE MISS SHIRLEY.
THERE'S NO ONE IN THE
WHOLE WORLD LIKE YOU.
PLEASE ACCEPT MY
CONDOLENCES MORGAN.
MOTHER MENTIONED
YOU BEFORE SHE WENT.
SHE WAS VERY KEEN ON YOU.
SHE WAS NEVER ONE TO
THROW AWAY A COMPLIMENT.
THAT MEANS A GREAT DEAL TO ME.
WILL YOU NOT RECONSIDER?
I'VE COME VERY CLOSE
TO RECONSIDERING...
BUT IT ISN'T ANY USE MORGAN.
I'LL MISS YOU, ANNE.
I HOPE YOU RENT THAT BIG
OLD HOUSE ON THE GULF SOMEDAY,
'CAUSE I'LL MISS YOU TOO.
I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE TO THANK
YOU MISS BROOKE IT'S BEEN SUCH
A REWARDING YEAR.
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS, PLEASE.
WHERE WILL YOU BE SPENDING
YOUR SUMMER HOLIDAYS?
HERE IN THIS FIRE-TRAP.
WHERE DID YOU SUPPOSE?
WHY STAY IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT?
WHY...WHY?
DON'T TROUBLE YOURSELF.
YOU'VE PAID YOUR LIP SERVICE.
NOW GOOD-BYE.
I SHALL SEE YOU NEXT TERM.
I WON'T BE COMING
BACK NEXT TERM.
I'VE GIVEN MY RESIGNATION
TO THE BOARD AND MISS STACEY.
I CAME HERE TO ASK YOU IF YOU'D
LIKE TO SPEND YOUR HOLIDAYS
WITH ME AT GREEN GABLES.
UNLESS YOU HAVE
SOMEWHERE ELSE YOU'RE GOING.
AN OUTBURST OF CHARITY...
I'M HARDLY A
CANDIDATE FOR THAT YET.
KATHERINE BROOKE WHETHER YOU
KNOW IT OR NOT WHAT YOU WANT
IS A DARN GOOD SPANKING.
IT MUST HAVE
RELIEVED YOU TO SAY THAT.
IT HAS.
AND I'VE WANTED TO SAY IT
TO YOU FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
BUT I HAVE ASKED YOU
TO COME BECAUSE THE VERY IDEA
OF YOU SPENDING THE SUMMER
COOPED UP IN HERE IS INDECENT.
YOU ASKED ME BECAUSE
YOU FEEL SORRY FOR ME.
I AM SORRY FOR YOU.
YOU SHUT OUT LIFE AND NOW
LIFE IS SHUTTING YOU OUT.
NOW ARE YOU COMING OR NOT?
WHAT WOULD YOU
SAY IF I ACCEPTED?
I'D SAY THAT'S THE FIRST
FAINT GLIMMER OF COMMON SENSE
I'VE EVER DETECTED IN YOU.
ALRIGHT I ACCEPT.
NOW YOU CAN GO THROUGH THE
MOTIONS OF TELLING ME HOW
DELIGHTED YOU ARE AND HOW
I'LL HAVE A WONDERFUL TIME.
I AM DELIGHTED.
BUT AS TO A WONDERFUL TIME
THAT WILL DEPEND ENTIRELY
ON YOU KATHERINE.
THE MURDER TRIALS IN THIS
BOSTON PAPER MY NIECE SENT ME
ARE REAL INTERESTING MARILLA.
FULL OF HEATHEN, THAT PLACE.
I HOPE ANNE WILL
NEVER GO THERE AGAIN.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THAT NEW
MINISTER GOING ON ABOUT HOW HE
DOESN'T BELIEVE THAT ALL THE
HEATHEN WILL BE ETERNALLY LOST!
THE IDEA!
IF THEY WON'T BE, ALL THE
MONEY WE'VE BEEN SENDING TO THE
FOREIGN MISSIONS WILL BE
COMPLETELY WASTED, THAT'S WHAT!
I WOULDN'T FRET
IF I WERE YOU RACHEL.
GOODNESS KNOWS THE WORLD IS FULL
OF BEGGARS AND IT'S A PRETTY
PASS IF WE CAN'T HELP A FELLOW
BEING IN NEED, CHRISTIAN OR NOT.
MARILLA CUTHBERT!
DON'T YOU BE BUYING ANY
JUNK FROM THOSE PEDDLERS JUST
TO SATISFY YOUR CONSCIENCE.
OH IT'S AN ILL WIND
THAT BLOWS NO GOOD.
COME BACK HERE YOU'LL
KILL YOURSELF RUNNING.
OH, MARILLA!
ANNE SHIRLEY!
I'M HOME MARILLA.
I'M HOME TO STAY.
OH YOU BLESSED CHILD!
HOW I'VE MISSED YOU.
WE WERE LOOKING
FOR YOU TOMORROW.
HOW DID YOU GET
FROM BRIGHT RIVER?
I WALKED, DEAREST OF MARILLAS.
WE LEFT OUR
LUGGAGE AT THE STATION.
I GOT HOMESICK ALL AT ONCE
AND I WANTED TO SHOW KATHERINE
ALL MY OLD HAUNTS.
WELCOME TO GREEN GABLES.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING
ME MISS CUTHBERT.
AREN'T THESE BLOSSOMS FRAGRANT?
SMELL THEM MARILLA...
DRINK THEM IN.
NOW ENOUGH OF THAT NONSENSE.
IT'S YOU I WANT TO HEAR ABOUT,
NOT DRINKING IN BLOSSOMS.
YOU MUST BE REAL
TIRED, KATHERINE.
COME AND HAVE A CUP
OF TEA ON THE VERANDAH.
OH, LET'S GO SLOWLY MARILLA.
I'VE DREAMT OF
THIS MOMENT ALL YEAR.
I WANT TO SOAK IT ALL IN.
NOT IF RACHEL HAS ANYTHING TO
DO WITH IT, SHE'LL WANT TO SPILL
OUT ALL THE NEWS OF AVONLEA.
OH ANNE SHIRLEY.
I'VE GOT SO MUCH TO TELL YOU!
THERE'S SO MUCH
GOING ON IN AVONLEA.
OH RACHEL, I HAVE
SO MUCH TO TELL YOU!
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN!
RACHEL, THIS IS
KATHERINE BROOKE.
RACHEL LYNDE.
HOW DO YOU DO?
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
COME ON IN NOW YOU
MUST BE STARVING
GREEN GABLES NEVER CHANGES.
THAT'S THE BEAUTIFUL THING ABOUT
COMING HOME, DON'T YOU THINK?
KATHERINE?
WHAT'S WRONG?
CAN I HELP YOU?
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND!
EVERYTHING'S ALWAYS
BEEN SO EASY FOR YOU.
I'M CAUGHT IN A TRAP.
I - I DON'T' THINK I'M EVER
GOING TO BE ABLE TO GET OUT!
YOU DON'T HATE ME
ANY LONGER, DO YOU?
OH ANNE.
HATE HAS GOT TO BE
LIKE A DISEASE WITH ME!
I CAN NEVER LEAD A
NORMAL LIFE, NOW.
YES YOU CAN!
YOU'LL BE QUITE
INDEPENDENT AND FREE HERE!
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE GIRL,
I REMEMBER AN OLD FADED PRINT
ON MY UNCLE'S WALL
SHOWING A STRING OF CAMELS
AROUND A DESERT
WITH A PALM SPRING.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO
TRAVEL AND SEE THAT PLACE.
TO SEE THE TAJ MAHAL,
THE PILLARS AT CARNET!
I WANT TO KNOW,
NOT JUST BELIEVE,
THAT THE WORLD IS ROUND.
I COULD NEVER DO IT
ON A TEACHER'S SALARY.
I SHALL HAVE TO GO ON FOREVER,
PRATING ABOUT DISCIPLINE
AND THE INEXHAUSTIBLE
RESOURCES OF THE DOMINION!
I ALWAYS WANTED TO BE
YOUR FRIEND, KATHERINE
SPELLED WITH A "K".
UNDERNEATH ALL YOUR PRICKLES,
YOU REALLY ARE A KINDRED SPIRIT!
DOES LIFE NEVER FRIGHTEN
YOU WITH ITS BLEAKNESS,
ANNE SHIRLEY?
THIS IS THE FIRST PLACE THAT
I'VE EVER BEEN TO THAT FEELS
LIKE A REAL...HOME.
ISN'T HE PERFECT?
HE IS THE MOST PERFECT
BABY I'VE EVER SEEN, DIANA.
EVERY BABY IS THE
SWEETEST AND THE BEST.
BEFORE HE CAME I WANTED A
GIRL SO I COULD CALL HER ANNE.
BUT I WOULDN'T EXCHANGE
BABY FRED FOR A MILLION GIRLS.
IF YOU HAD AN ANNE
YOU'D FEEL THE SAME ABOUT HER.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO
HOLD THE BABY KATHERINE?
NO, NO...I'VE NEVER
HELD A BABY IN MY LIFE.
NEVER HELD A BABY!
DON'T BE SILLY.
I'M AFRAID OF IT
GOING TO PIECES IN MY ARMS.
THERE YOU ARE, HE'S
TAKEN WITH YOU KATHERINE.
IT FEELS SO GOOD TO
SEE YOU DEAR FOLK AGAIN.
I WANT TO HEAR
ALL THE AVONLEA NEWS.
I'VE GROWN A WHOLE INCH
SINCE YOU LEFT ANNE.
AND NOW THAT SQUIRT ANTHONY
PYE CAN'T PICK ON ME ANYMORE.
CAN'T YOU THINK OF
ANY MORE INTERESTING NEWS
THAN THAT MINNIE MAY!
DID YOU KNOW THAT
GILBERT BLYTHE WAS DYING?
MINNIE MAY HOLD YOUR TONGUE!
WHAT DO YOU MEAN DIANA?
WE DIDN'T MEAN TO TELL
YOU SO SUDDENLY, ANNE.
HE TOOK SCARLET
FEVER IN MID-TERM.
HE PICKED IT UP AT
THE HOSPITAL IN HALIFAX.
TERRIBLE WORN OUT
WITH SCHOOL I EXPECT.
THEY GOT A TRAINED NURSE
AND EVERYTHING'S BEEN DONE.
I PICKED THIS UP
AT THE POST OFFICE.
IT'S ADDRESSED TO YOU.
MY...MY BOOK!
WELL DON'T SIT THERE
SHAKING LIKE A LEAF!
OPEN IT.
OH MARILLA.
THIS CAN'T BE REAL.
THEY ACCEPTED MY MANUSCRIPT LAST
FEBRUARY WITH A $250 ADVANCE.
YOU'RE A GREAT ONE FOR SECRETS.
IT'S NOT A CLASSIC OR A
ROMANCE OR ANYTHING IMPORTANT.
JUST A HUMOROUS BOOK OF
STORIES I DID ABOUT AVONLEA
IN MY SPARE TIME LAST FALL.
BUT IT'S MINE, IT'S ALL MINE.
"TO MARILLA AND MATTHEW CUTHBERT
FOR THEIR UNFAILING LOVE AND
SUPPORT AND FOR GILBERT WHO
INSPIRED ME WITH THE IDEA
IN THE FIRST PLACE."
YOU DO BEAT ALL ANNE.
EVERYONE'LL THINK
I PUT YOU UP TO IT.
THAT'S AWFUL GOOD OF YOU;
ESPECIALLY CONSIDERING GILBERT.
HOW SICK IS HE REALLY?
IT'S BEEN A BAD
CASE FROM THE START.
NO ONE'S HEARD
ANYTHING THE PAST WEEK.
HE HAS THE BLYTHE CONSTITUTION
IN HIS FAVOUR
THOUGH...IF GOD WILLS IT.
MARILLA THERE'S A BOOK OF
REVELATIONS IN EVERYONE'S LIFE.
I'VE BEEN SO WRONG..
IF GIL WERE TO...
...NOT KNOWING
HOW I REALLY CARE.
OH, THERE THERE NOW.
WHAT WOULD I DO WITHOUT HIM?
WE CAN'T CHANGE
WHAT GOD DETERMINES.
JERRY BOOTE...JERRY BOOTE
WORKS FOR MR. BLYTHE.
IT MUST BE A SIGN.
THE WORST WOULD
BE MORE ENDURABLE
THAN NOT KNOWING AT ALL.
JERRY! JERRY!
JERRY, WAIT!
JERRY DO YOU KNOW HOW
GILBERT BLYTHE IS DOING?
I THINK, I THINK HE'S BAD.
THE BLYTHES ARE ALL
HOPING HE'S GONNA GET BETTER.
I DON'T KNOW.
THE DOCTOR FIGURES MAYBE
HE'S GONNA HAVE
A CLOSE SHAVE YET, THOUGH.
WILL YOU ASK MR. BLYTHE
TO GIVE HIM THIS FOR ME?
COME WITH ME IF YOU LIKE
AND GIVE IT TO HIM YOURSELF.
HELLO GIL.
IT'S ME.
ANNE.
I'VE COME TO ASK YOU TO
GO FOR ONE OF OUR OLD-TIME
RAMBLES IN THE WOODS.
WISH I COULD GO.
I BROUGHT YOU MY BOOK.
I'VE BEEN PUBLISHED GIL.
I WROTE ABOUT AVONLEA
JUST AS YOU SAID I SHOULD.
WITHOUT ANY "HIGH
FAULTING MUMBO JUMBO".
I'VE DEDICATED THE
INSCRIPTION TO MARILLA
AND TO MATTHEW, AND... TO YOU.
I WAS PLANNING ON SAVING
IT AS A WEDDING GIFT, AND THEN
I JUST DECIDED I COULDN'T WAIT.
ANNE, THERE'S NOT GOING
TO BE ANY WEDDING, ANYMORE.
YOU'RE GONNA WELL AGAIN GIL.
I KNOW YOU WILL.
I CALLED IT OFF.
IT WOULDN'T BE
FAIR TO CHRISTINE.
OH GIL...
THERE WOULD NEVER BE
ANYONE FOR ME BUT YOU.
OH, ANNE, THE SUMMER'S
FLOWN BY SO QUICKLY.
A SCHOOL TEACHER REALLY
IS A SLAVE OF TIME.
I DON'T KNOW HOW I'M
EVER GOING TO GO BACK.
DON'T BE SILLY.
THERE'S ALWAYS
ANOTHER BEND IN THE ROAD.
BEND IN THE ROAD.
THERE'S NO BEND IN MY ROAD.
I CAN SEE IT STRETCHING OUT
IN FRONT OF ME TO THE SKYLINE.
KATHERINE, JUST LOOK AT YOU.
YOU'RE ROSY AND HEALTHY.
AND YOU HAIR LOOKS
SO ATTRACTIVE LIKE THAT
INSTEAD OF ALL PULLED BACK.
BESIDES, I HAPPEN TO KNOW
OF TWO ELIGIBLE YOUNG MEN
WHO'VE ASKED ABOUT YOU.
REALLY?
THEY'RE GONNA BE AT
THE BONFIRE TONIGHT.
OH, I WOULDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY TO THEM.
WILL YOU HELP ME, ANNE?
THEY'LL JUST LAUGH AT ME
AND THINK I'M AN OLD GOOSEBERRY.
YOU GIVE YOURSELF
FAR TOO LITTLE CREDIT.
I WISH I HAD YOUR CONFIDENCE.
I CAN BELIEVE ALMOST ANYTHING
OF THIS GREEN GABLES OF YOURS.
WELL, MINE'S FULL.
I'LL BE ALONG.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
MARILLA HAS THREE FULL BUSHELS.
HELLO ANNE.
HELLO GIL.
YOU'RE LOOKING VERY ROBUST.
WELL, I...UH...I
GUESS I JUST MADE UP MY MIND
I WASN'T GOING
TO LET IT LICK ME.
CARE FOR A STROLL DOWN THE LANE.
I DON'T THINK THERE'S GOING
TO BE MANY MORE FINE AFTERNOONS
LIKE THIS LEFT IN THE SUMMER.
I WISH I COULD, BUT...
KATHERINE AND I, WE'RE OFF
TO ALICE PENHALLOW'S BONFIRE
IN AN HOUR.
IT'S THE FIRST PARTY I'M TAKING
HER TO AND SHE'S VERY NERVOUS.
HOW ABOUT I WALK
YOU ACROSS THE POND.
I WAS REALLY AFRAID FOR
YOU GIL, UNTIL WE HEARD YOU
WERE OVER THE WORST.
WELL I WAS LUCKY I SUPPOSE.
I'M NOT QUITE MY OLD SELF YET.
BY THE TIME TERM
STARTS I'LL BE IN FINE FORM.
I'M GLAD YOU CAME
BACK WHEN YOU DID ANNE.
IT MEANT A LOT TO ME.
I FINALLY READ YOUR BOOK.
IT'S A FINE PIECE OF WORK.
I KNEW YOU COULD DO IT.
THE PUBLISHERS ARE ALREADY
PLANNING A SECOND EDITION.
IT WAS A LONG LESSON TO
LEARN, BUT YOU WERE RIGHT.
I'M NOT GOING BACK TO KINGSPORT.
I'M GONNA STAY HERE
AT GREEN GABLES AND WRITE.
PRIVATE GIRLS' SCHOOL WAS
TOO ROUGH ON YOU, WAS IT?
NO.
IT'S JUST THAT I WENT LOOKING
FOR MY IDEALS OUTSIDE OF MYSELF.
I'VE DISCOVERED IT'S NOT
WHAT THE WORLD HOLDS FOR YOU,
IT'S WHAT YOU BRING TO IT.
THE DREAMS DEAREST TO
MY HEART ARE RIGHT HERE.
WELL I HOPE YOU
KEEP ON DREAMING.
IT'LL BE THREE YEARS BEFORE
I FINISH MEDICAL SCHOOL.
EVEN THEN THERE WON'T
BE ANY DIAMOND SUNBURSTS
OR MARBLE HALLS.
I DON'T WANT
SUNBURSTS OR MARBLE HALLS.
I JUST WANT YOU.